<bill session="116" type="h" number="3055" updated="2019-11-01T19:16:30Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-31">PASS_BACK:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-10-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for the Departments of Commerce and Justice, Science, and Related Agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2020, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Commerce, Justice, Science, Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, Interior, Environment, Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, Transportation, and Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Commerce, Justice, Science, Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, Interior, Environment, Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, Transportation, and Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020'</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Commerce, Justice, Science, Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, Interior, Environment, Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, Transportation, and Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Department of Commerce Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Department of Commerce Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Department of Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Department of Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Department of Transportation Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Department of Transportation Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Fair Compensation for Low-Wage Contractor Employees Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Fair Compensation for Low-Wage Contractor Employees Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Science Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Science Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Department of Commerce Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Department of Commerce Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Science Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Science Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Department of Commerce Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Science Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="display">Commerce, Justice, Science, Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, Interior, Environment, Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, Transportation, and Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000248"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-03">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 116-101, by Mr. Serrano.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-06-03" state="REPORTED" calendar="Union" number="76">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 76.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T01:25:26-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 445 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3055 with 1 hour of general debate. Motion to recommit with or without instructions allowed. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3055 under a structured rule. Rule also provides for proceedings during the period from June 28, 2019, through July 9, 2019. Rule also provides that it shall be in order on the legislative day of June 27, 2019, that the House suspend the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T14:06:42-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 445 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T15:37:35-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 445.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4797-4896" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T15:37:40-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3055 with 1 hour of general debate. Motion to recommit with or without instructions allowed. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3055 under a structured rule. Rule also provides for proceedings during the period from June 28, 2019, through July 9, 2019. Rule also provides that it shall be in order on the legislative day of June 27, 2019, that the House suspend the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T15:37:48-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 445 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T15:37:49-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Earl Blumenauer to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T15:38:57-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 3055.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T16:42:40-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Burgess amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T16:48:05-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes fo debate on the Scanlon amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T16:52:10-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rutherford amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T16:56:32-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Rutherford amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Rutherford demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T17:02:50-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Scalise amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T17:07:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Serrano en bloc amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T17:09:32-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Serrano en bloc amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T17:17:04-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the King (IA) amendment No. 9.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T17:29:04-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the King (IA) amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. King (IA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T17:29:55-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Posey amendment No. 11.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T17:38:15-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Scott (VA) amendment No. 12.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T17:45:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Walberg amendment No. 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T17:52:03-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Blumenauer amendment No. 16.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T17:55:39-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Blumenauer amendment No. 17.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T18:03:57-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Blumenauer amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Aderholt demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T18:05:23-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Sewell amendment No. 22.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T18:08:16-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bost amendment No. 30.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T18:16:15-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Clarke (NY) amendment No. 31.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T18:21:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Banks amendment No. 36.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T18:27:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Banks amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Banks demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T18:28:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Huffman amendment No. 44.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T18:32:21-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jeffries amendment No. 49.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T18:38:54-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cunningham amendment No. 53.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T18:42:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cunningham amendment No. 54.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T18:45:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cunningham amendment No. 58.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T18:48:28-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Serrano moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T18:49:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T18:49:13-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 3055 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T10:19:22-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4929-4978, H4978-4997" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T10:19:40-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T10:26:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Crow amendment No. 65.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T10:34:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Dean amendment No. 66.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T10:38:16-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Escobar amendment No. 68.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T10:44:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Golden amendment No. 70.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T10:55:29-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Golden amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Golden demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T10:56:24-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kendra S. Horn amendment No. 71.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T11:00:55-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Golden amendment No. 72.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T11:03:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Malinowski amendment No. 73.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T11:08:01-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Neguse amendment No. 75.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T11:11:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Neguse amendment No. 76.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T11:14:37-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ocasio-Cortez amendment No. 78.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T11:19:05-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Omar amendment No. 79.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T11:25:27-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Porter amendment No. 81.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T11:29:30-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Porter amendment No. 82.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T11:35:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pressley amendment No. 83.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T11:38:50-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pressley amendment No. 84.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T11:42:10-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Stevens amendment No. 85.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T11:46:13-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Stevens amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Stevens demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T11:47:19-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Underwood amendment No. 89.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T11:53:55-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Underwood amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Underwood demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T12:01:21-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes on the Bishop of Georgia en bloc amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T12:10:46-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Banks amendment No. 99.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T12:15:25-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Banks amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Banks demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T12:16:16-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Biggs amendment No. 101.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T12:21:34-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pence amendment No. 105.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T12:27:47-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Pence amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Pence demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T12:28:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Spanberger amendment No. 114.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T12:33:38-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Spanberger amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Spanberger demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T12:34:09-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Underwood amendment No. 115.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T12:59:58-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes on the McCollum en bloc amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T13:12:25-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Wasserman Schultz amendment No. 128.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T13:21:13-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Wasserman Schultz amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Gosar demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T13:21:40-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Young amendment No. 129.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T13:29:21-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pallone amendment No. 132.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T13:39:54-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Pallone amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Pallone demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T13:40:54-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Buchanan amendment No. 133.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T13:51:57-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Buchanan amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. McCollum demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T13:52:34-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the McCollum en bloc amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T14:01:15-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the McCollum amendment en bloc No. 5, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. McCollum demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T14:03:03-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Duncan amendment No. 135.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T14:11:56-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Duncan amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Duncan demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T14:12:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Blumenauer amendment No. 136.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T14:24:57-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Blumenauer amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Gosar demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T14:26:30-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gosar amendment No. 139.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T14:33:36-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gosar amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Gosar demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T14:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gosar amendment No. 140.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T14:41:17-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Duncan amendment No. 143.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T14:53:19-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Duncan amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Duncan demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T14:54:32-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mullin amendment No. 147.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T14:59:58-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Mullin amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. McCollum demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T15:01:09-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mullin amendment No. 148.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T15:07:31-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Mullin amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Mullin demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T15:08:57-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Smith (MO) amendment No. 151.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T15:12:47-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Newhouse amendment No. 156.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T15:20:09-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Graves (LA) amendment No. 158.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T15:30:39-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Graves (LA) amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Gosar demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T15:32:30-04:00">
      <text>Subsequently, the Committee resumed its sitting.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T15:33:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hice (GA) amendment No. 161.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T15:36:23-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hice amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hice demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T15:37:04-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Banks amendment No. 163.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T15:45:35-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Banks amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Banks demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T15:46:05-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Biggs amendment No. 165.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T15:53:46-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Biggs amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Biggs demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T15:54:35-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cunningham amendment No. 167.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T16:03:36-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cunningham amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Cunningham demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T16:04:50-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cunningham amendment No. 168.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T16:10:16-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cunningham amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Cunningham demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T16:11:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Carbajal amendment No. 176.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T16:20:30-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Carbajal amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Carbajal demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T16:21:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hill (CA) amendment No. 187.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T16:25:44-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hill (CA) amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Hill (CA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T16:28:56-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Schrier amendment No. 190.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T16:31:22-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Schrier amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Schrier demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T16:31:47-04:00">
      <text>VACATING DEMAND FOR A RECORDED VOTE - Ms. McCollum asked unanimous consent that the request for a recorded vote on the amendments en bloc No. 5 offered by Ms. McCollum be withdrawn to the end that the question be put de novo. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T16:35:58-04:00">
      <text>Ms. McCollum moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T16:36:08-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T16:36:41-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 3055 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T16:49:58-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4978-4997" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T16:50:12-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T19:13:12-04:00">
      <text>Ms. McCollum moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T19:13:23-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20T19:14:08-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 3055 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-21T09:06:06-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5011-5022" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-21T09:18:08-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-21T09:19:48-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Raskin amendment No. 195.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-21T09:24:56-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Wasserman Schultz en bloc amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-21T09:46:59-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Blumenauer amendment No. 198.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-21T09:51:37-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Walberg amendment No. 199.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-21T09:55:13-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bost amendment No. 206.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-21T09:57:58-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Bost amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Wasserman Schultz demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-21T09:59:22-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cunningham amendment No. 219.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-21T10:03:12-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Golden amendment No. 220.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-21T10:09:01-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Golden amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Golden demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-21T10:09:59-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McAdams amendment No. 221.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-21T10:14:53-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the McAdams amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McAdams demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-21T10:16:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cunningham amendment No. 226.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-21T10:20:07-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kim amendment No. 228.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-21T11:08:16-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hoyer moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-21T11:08:27-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-21T11:09:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 3055 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T15:22:53-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5047-5068" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T15:23:06-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T15:24:47-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Woodall amendment No. 229.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T15:38:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Price (NC) amendment en bloc No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T15:43:52-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Price (NC) amendment en bloc No. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T15:50:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the DeFazio amendment No. 233.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T15:59:27-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the DeFazio amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Hern (OK) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T16:00:47-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Duncan amendment No. 234.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T16:11:07-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Duncan amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Price (NC) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T16:12:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Duncan amendment No. 235.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T16:22:54-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Duncan amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Duncan demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T16:30:56-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Heck amendment No. 241.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T16:37:23-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grothman amendment No. 244.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T16:43:32-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Grothman amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Grothman demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T16:44:34-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bost amendment No. 248.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T16:50:30-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Banks amendment No. 251.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T16:57:54-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Banks amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Banks demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T16:59:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Vargas amendment No. 258.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T17:14:55-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Krishnamoorthi amendment No. 267.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T17:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jayapal amendment No. 268.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T17:22:45-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jayapal amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Jayapal demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T17:23:27-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Wexton amendment No. 273.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T17:32:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Garcia (IL) amendment No. 282.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T17:36:43-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Malinowski amendment No. 284.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T17:42:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pressley amendment No. 288.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T17:48:24-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 445, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pressley amendment No. 289.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T17:54:18-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Price (NC) moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T17:54:28-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T17:55:09-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 3055 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T18:33:34-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5069-5071" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T18:33:42-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T19:21:46-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Price (NC) moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T19:21:55-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T19:22:04-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 3055 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T14:09:10-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5100-5104" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T14:09:19-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T14:20:18-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 3055.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T14:21:39-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T14:21:54-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T14:23:17-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hurd (TX) moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5102-5104" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T14:23:34-04:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hurd (TX) motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to increase the Executive Office for Immigration Review by $75 million and decrease Periodic Censuses and Programs by a similar amount.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T14:31:08-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T14:38:54-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 201 - 220 (Roll no. 407).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="408" datetime="2019-06-25T14:49:45-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 227 - 194 (Roll no. 408).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T14:49:50-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T14:49:51-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 3055.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-08">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-09">
      <text>Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-07-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="141">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 141.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5880"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed to the measure presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5881"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure withdrawn in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote-aux how="roll" type="cloture" roll="330" datetime="2019-10-22" where="s" result="pass">
      <text>Cloture on the motion to proceed to the measure invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 92 - 2. Record Vote Number: 330.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5946"/>
    </vote-aux>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22">
      <text>Motion to proceed to measure considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5947"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by motion.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5951" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-23">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6080" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-28">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6179, S6183-6187" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-28">
      <text>Cloture motion on the measure presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6187"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-29">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6206-6220" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-30">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6271-6281, S6281-6294" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-31">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6311-6322" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-31">
      <text>Cloture motion on the measure withdrawn by unanimous consent in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6322"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="341" datetime="2019-10-31" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate, under the order of 10/30/19, having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, with an amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 84 - 9. Record Vote Number: 341.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2584"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3164"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3163"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3052"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2745"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="162"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3277"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="678"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="116" relation="procedurally-related" number="445"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s999"/>
    <amendment number="s998"/>
    <amendment number="s997"/>
    <amendment number="s996"/>
    <amendment number="s995"/>
    <amendment number="s994"/>
    <amendment number="s993"/>
    <amendment number="s992"/>
    <amendment number="s991"/>
    <amendment number="s990"/>
    <amendment number="s989"/>
    <amendment number="s988"/>
    <amendment number="s987"/>
    <amendment number="s986"/>
    <amendment number="s985"/>
    <amendment number="s984"/>
    <amendment number="s983"/>
    <amendment number="s982"/>
    <amendment number="s981"/>
    <amendment number="s980"/>
    <amendment number="s979"/>
    <amendment number="s978"/>
    <amendment number="s977"/>
    <amendment number="s976"/>
    <amendment number="s975"/>
    <amendment number="s974"/>
    <amendment number="s973"/>
    <amendment number="s972"/>
    <amendment number="s971"/>
    <amendment number="s970"/>
    <amendment number="s969"/>
    <amendment number="s968"/>
    <amendment number="s967"/>
    <amendment number="s966"/>
    <amendment number="s965"/>
    <amendment number="s964"/>
    <amendment number="s963"/>
    <amendment number="s962"/>
    <amendment number="s961"/>
    <amendment number="s960"/>
    <amendment number="s959"/>
    <amendment number="s958"/>
    <amendment number="s957"/>
    <amendment number="s956"/>
    <amendment number="s955"/>
    <amendment number="s954"/>
    <amendment number="s953"/>
    <amendment number="s952"/>
    <amendment number="s951"/>
    <amendment number="s950"/>
    <amendment number="s949"/>
    <amendment number="s948"/>
    <amendment number="h482"/>
    <amendment number="h481"/>
    <amendment number="h480"/>
    <amendment number="h479"/>
    <amendment number="h478"/>
    <amendment number="h477"/>
    <amendment number="h476"/>
    <amendment number="h475"/>
    <amendment number="h474"/>
    <amendment number="h473"/>
    <amendment number="h472"/>
    <amendment number="h471"/>
    <amendment number="h470"/>
    <amendment number="h469"/>
    <amendment number="h468"/>
    <amendment number="h467"/>
    <amendment number="h466"/>
    <amendment number="h465"/>
    <amendment number="h464"/>
    <amendment number="h463"/>
    <amendment number="h462"/>
    <amendment number="h461"/>
    <amendment number="h460"/>
    <amendment number="h459"/>
    <amendment number="h458"/>
    <amendment number="h457"/>
    <amendment number="h456"/>
    <amendment number="h455"/>
    <amendment number="h454"/>
    <amendment number="h453"/>
    <amendment number="h452"/>
    <amendment number="h451"/>
    <amendment number="h450"/>
    <amendment number="h449"/>
    <amendment number="h448"/>
    <amendment number="h447"/>
    <amendment number="h446"/>
    <amendment number="h445"/>
    <amendment number="h444"/>
    <amendment number="h443"/>
    <amendment number="h442"/>
    <amendment number="h441"/>
    <amendment number="h440"/>
    <amendment number="h439"/>
    <amendment number="h438"/>
    <amendment number="h437"/>
    <amendment number="h436"/>
    <amendment number="h435"/>
    <amendment number="h434"/>
    <amendment number="h433"/>
    <amendment number="h432"/>
    <amendment number="h431"/>
    <amendment number="h430"/>
    <amendment number="h429"/>
    <amendment number="h428"/>
    <amendment number="h427"/>
    <amendment number="h426"/>
    <amendment number="h425"/>
    <amendment number="h424"/>
    <amendment number="h423"/>
    <amendment number="h422"/>
    <amendment number="h421"/>
    <amendment number="h420"/>
    <amendment number="h419"/>
    <amendment number="h418"/>
    <amendment number="h417"/>
    <amendment number="h416"/>
    <amendment number="h415"/>
    <amendment number="h414"/>
    <amendment number="h413"/>
    <amendment number="h412"/>
    <amendment number="h411"/>
    <amendment number="h410"/>
    <amendment number="h409"/>
    <amendment number="h408"/>
    <amendment number="h407"/>
    <amendment number="h406"/>
    <amendment number="h405"/>
    <amendment number="h404"/>
    <amendment number="h403"/>
    <amendment number="h402"/>
    <amendment number="h401"/>
    <amendment number="h400"/>
    <amendment number="h399"/>
    <amendment number="h398"/>
    <amendment number="h397"/>
    <amendment number="h396"/>
    <amendment number="h395"/>
    <amendment number="h394"/>
    <amendment number="h393"/>
    <amendment number="h392"/>
    <amendment number="h391"/>
    <amendment number="h390"/>
    <amendment number="h389"/>
    <amendment number="h388"/>
    <amendment number="h387"/>
    <amendment number="s1243"/>
    <amendment number="s1242"/>
    <amendment number="s1241"/>
    <amendment number="s1239"/>
    <amendment number="s1238"/>
    <amendment number="s1237"/>
    <amendment number="s1236"/>
    <amendment number="s1235"/>
    <amendment number="s1234"/>
    <amendment number="s1233"/>
    <amendment number="s1232"/>
    <amendment number="s1231"/>
    <amendment number="s1230"/>
    <amendment number="s1229"/>
    <amendment number="s1228"/>
    <amendment number="s1227"/>
    <amendment number="s1226"/>
    <amendment number="s1225"/>
    <amendment number="s1224"/>
    <amendment number="s1223"/>
    <amendment number="s1222"/>
    <amendment number="s1221"/>
    <amendment number="s1220"/>
    <amendment number="s1219"/>
    <amendment number="s1218"/>
    <amendment number="s1217"/>
    <amendment number="s1216"/>
    <amendment number="s1215"/>
    <amendment number="s1214"/>
    <amendment number="s1213"/>
    <amendment number="s1212"/>
    <amendment number="s1211"/>
    <amendment number="s1210"/>
    <amendment number="s1209"/>
    <amendment number="s1208"/>
    <amendment number="s1207"/>
    <amendment number="s1206"/>
    <amendment number="s1205"/>
    <amendment number="s1204"/>
    <amendment number="s1203"/>
    <amendment number="s1202"/>
    <amendment number="s1201"/>
    <amendment number="s1200"/>
    <amendment number="s1199"/>
    <amendment number="s1198"/>
    <amendment number="s1197"/>
    <amendment number="s1195"/>
    <amendment number="s1194"/>
    <amendment number="s1193"/>
    <amendment number="s1192"/>
    <amendment number="s1191"/>
    <amendment number="s1190"/>
    <amendment number="s1189"/>
    <amendment number="s1188"/>
    <amendment number="s1187"/>
    <amendment number="s1186"/>
    <amendment number="s1185"/>
    <amendment number="s1184"/>
    <amendment number="s1183"/>
    <amendment number="s1182"/>
    <amendment number="s1181"/>
    <amendment number="s1180"/>
    <amendment number="s1179"/>
    <amendment number="s1178"/>
    <amendment number="s1177"/>
    <amendment number="s1176"/>
    <amendment number="s1175"/>
    <amendment number="s1174"/>
    <amendment number="s1173"/>
    <amendment number="s1172"/>
    <amendment number="s1171"/>
    <amendment number="s1170"/>
    <amendment number="s1169"/>
    <amendment number="s1168"/>
    <amendment number="s1167"/>
    <amendment number="s1166"/>
    <amendment number="s1165"/>
    <amendment number="s1164"/>
    <amendment number="s1163"/>
    <amendment number="s1162"/>
    <amendment number="s1161"/>
    <amendment number="s1160"/>
    <amendment number="s1159"/>
    <amendment number="s1158"/>
    <amendment number="s1157"/>
    <amendment number="s1156"/>
    <amendment number="s1155"/>
    <amendment number="s1154"/>
    <amendment number="s1153"/>
    <amendment number="s1152"/>
    <amendment number="s1151"/>
    <amendment number="s1150"/>
    <amendment number="s1149"/>
    <amendment number="s1148"/>
    <amendment number="s1147"/>
    <amendment number="s1146"/>
    <amendment number="s1145"/>
    <amendment number="s1144"/>
    <amendment number="s1143"/>
    <amendment number="s1142"/>
    <amendment number="s1141"/>
    <amendment number="s1140"/>
    <amendment number="s1139"/>
    <amendment number="s1138"/>
    <amendment number="s1137"/>
    <amendment number="s1136"/>
    <amendment number="s1135"/>
    <amendment number="s1134"/>
    <amendment number="s1133"/>
    <amendment number="s1132"/>
    <amendment number="s1131"/>
    <amendment number="s1130"/>
    <amendment number="s1129"/>
    <amendment number="s1128"/>
    <amendment number="s1127"/>
    <amendment number="s1126"/>
    <amendment number="s1125"/>
    <amendment number="s1124"/>
    <amendment number="s1123"/>
    <amendment number="s1122"/>
    <amendment number="s1121"/>
    <amendment number="s1120"/>
    <amendment number="s1119"/>
    <amendment number="s1118"/>
    <amendment number="s1117"/>
    <amendment number="s1116"/>
    <amendment number="s1115"/>
    <amendment number="s1114"/>
    <amendment number="s1113"/>
    <amendment number="s1112"/>
    <amendment number="s1111"/>
    <amendment number="s1110"/>
    <amendment number="s1109"/>
    <amendment number="s1108"/>
    <amendment number="s1107"/>
    <amendment number="s1106"/>
    <amendment number="s1105"/>
    <amendment number="s1104"/>
    <amendment number="s1103"/>
    <amendment number="s1102"/>
    <amendment number="s1101"/>
    <amendment number="s1100"/>
    <amendment number="s1099"/>
    <amendment number="s1098"/>
    <amendment number="s1097"/>
    <amendment number="s1096"/>
    <amendment number="s1095"/>
    <amendment number="s1094"/>
    <amendment number="s1093"/>
    <amendment number="s1092"/>
    <amendment number="s1091"/>
    <amendment number="s1090"/>
    <amendment number="s1089"/>
    <amendment number="s1088"/>
    <amendment number="s1087"/>
    <amendment number="s1086"/>
    <amendment number="s1085"/>
    <amendment number="s1084"/>
    <amendment number="s1083"/>
    <amendment number="s1082"/>
    <amendment number="s1081"/>
    <amendment number="s1080"/>
    <amendment number="s1079"/>
    <amendment number="s1078"/>
    <amendment number="s1077"/>
    <amendment number="s1076"/>
    <amendment number="s1075"/>
    <amendment number="s1074"/>
    <amendment number="s1073"/>
    <amendment number="s1072"/>
    <amendment number="s1071"/>
    <amendment number="s1070"/>
    <amendment number="s1069"/>
    <amendment number="s1068"/>
    <amendment number="s1067"/>
    <amendment number="s1066"/>
    <amendment number="s1065"/>
    <amendment number="s1064"/>
    <amendment number="s1063"/>
    <amendment number="s1062"/>
    <amendment number="s1061"/>
    <amendment number="s1060"/>
    <amendment number="s1059"/>
    <amendment number="s1058"/>
    <amendment number="s1057"/>
    <amendment number="s1056"/>
    <amendment number="s1055"/>
    <amendment number="s1054"/>
    <amendment number="s1053"/>
    <amendment number="s1052"/>
    <amendment number="s1051"/>
    <amendment number="s1050"/>
    <amendment number="s1049"/>
    <amendment number="s1048"/>
    <amendment number="s1047"/>
    <amendment number="s1046"/>
    <amendment number="s1045"/>
    <amendment number="s1044"/>
    <amendment number="s1043"/>
    <amendment number="s1042"/>
    <amendment number="s1041"/>
    <amendment number="s1040"/>
    <amendment number="s1039"/>
    <amendment number="s1038"/>
    <amendment number="s1037"/>
    <amendment number="s1036"/>
    <amendment number="s1035"/>
    <amendment number="s1034"/>
    <amendment number="s1033"/>
    <amendment number="s1032"/>
    <amendment number="s1031"/>
    <amendment number="s1030"/>
    <amendment number="s1029"/>
    <amendment number="s1028"/>
    <amendment number="s1027"/>
    <amendment number="s1026"/>
    <amendment number="s1025"/>
    <amendment number="s1024"/>
    <amendment number="s1023"/>
    <amendment number="s1022"/>
    <amendment number="s1021"/>
    <amendment number="s1020"/>
    <amendment number="s1019"/>
    <amendment number="s1018"/>
    <amendment number="s1017"/>
    <amendment number="s1016"/>
    <amendment number="s1015"/>
    <amendment number="s1014"/>
    <amendment number="s1013"/>
    <amendment number="s1012"/>
    <amendment number="s1011"/>
    <amendment number="s1010"/>
    <amendment number="s1009"/>
    <amendment number="s1008"/>
    <amendment number="s1007"/>
    <amendment number="s1006"/>
    <amendment number="s1005"/>
    <amendment number="s1004"/>
    <amendment number="s1003"/>
    <amendment number="s1002"/>
    <amendment number="s1001"/>
    <amendment number="s1000"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2019-06-25T14:41:40Z" status="Passed House">Commerce, Justice, Science, Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, Interior, Environment, Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, Transportation, and Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2020

This bill provides FY2020 appropriations for several federal departments and agencies. It includes 5 of the 12 regular FY2020 appropriations bills:

 the Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020; the Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020; the Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020; the Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020; and the Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020. The departments and agencies funded in the bill include

 the Department of Commerce; the Department of Justice; science-related agencies, including the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA); the Department of Agriculture; the Food and Drug Administration; the Commodity Futures Trading Commission; the Department of the Interior; the Environmental Protection Agency; the Forest Service; the military construction activities of the Department of Defense; the Department of Veterans Affairs; the Department of Transportation; the Department of Housing and Urban Development; and several additional related and independent agencies. The bill provides appropriations to compensate certain low-wage employees of government contractors who were affected by the partial government shutdown that began on December 22, 2018. The bill also specifies restrictions and requirements for using funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-101</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
