<amendment session="116" chamber="h" number="575" updated="2019-08-12T16:15:42Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3494" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2019-07-17T18:35:19-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000379"/>
  <offered datetime="2019-07-16"/>
  <description>Amendment establishes the Foreign Threat Response Center, comprised of analysts from all elements of the intelligence community, to provide comprehensive assessment of foreign efforts to influence United States' political processes and elections by the Governments of Russia, Iran, North Korea, China, and any other foreign country the Director determines appropriate.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 11 printed in Part B of House Report 116-154 to establish the Foreign Threat Response Center, comprised of analysts from all elements of the intelligence community, to provide comprehensive assessment of foreign efforts to influence United States' political processes and elections by the Governments of Russia, Iran, North Korea, China, and any other foreign country the Director determines appropriate.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2019-07-17T18:35:19-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="491">
      <text>On agreeing to the Kennedy amendment (A011) Agreed to by recorded vote: 237 - 196 (Roll no. 491).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5979" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-07-16T20:23:30-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A011) offered by Mr. Kennedy.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5896-5898" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5896-5897" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-16"/>
    <action datetime="2019-07-17T18:35:19-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-17T18:35:19-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Kennedy amendment (A011) Agreed to by recorded vote: 237 - 196 (Roll no. 491).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-16T20:23:30-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A011) offered by Mr. Kennedy.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5896-5898" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5896-5897" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-17T18:35:19-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-16">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
