<bill session="116" type="h" number="986" updated="2019-08-29T22:45:11Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-09T18:36:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-05-09T18:36:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that certain guidance related to waivers for State innovation under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act shall have no force or effect.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Protecting Americans with Preexisting Conditions Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Protecting Americans with Preexisting Conditions Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Protecting Americans with Preexisting Conditions Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Protecting Americans with Preexisting Conditions Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Americans with Preexisting Conditions Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Americans with Preexisting Conditions Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Protecting Americans with Preexisting Conditions Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000382"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001292" joined="2019-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2019-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001066" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2019-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001069" joined="2019-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000624" joined="2019-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2019-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000592" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000379" joined="2019-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001163" joined="2019-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2019-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001207" joined="2019-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000034" joined="2019-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000599" joined="2019-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2019-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001180" joined="2019-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000133" joined="2019-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2019-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-27">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by the Yeas and Nays: 19 - 13 .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-04-03" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-04-30">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 116-44, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-30">
      <text>Committee on Ways and Means discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-04-30" calendar="Union" number="22">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 22.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-05-07T19:25:41-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 357 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 986 and H.R. 2157. Specified amendments are in order. Provides for consideration of H.R. 986 and H.R. 2157 both under structured rules. One hour of general debate provided for each measure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T14:05:37-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 357.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3519-3550" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T14:05:42-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 986 and H.R. 2157. Specified amendments are in order. Provides for consideration of H.R. 986 and H.R. 2157 both under structured rules. One hour of general debate provided for each measure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T14:06:30-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 357 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T14:06:30-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Jesus G. "Chuy" Garcia to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T14:08:14-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 986.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T15:28:15-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 357, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Langevin amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T15:36:50-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 357, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brown (MD) amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T15:46:51-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Brown (MD) amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Brown (MD) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T15:47:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 357, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pressley amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T15:56:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 357, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Harder amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T16:03:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 357, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Walden amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T16:12:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 357, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Holding amendment No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T16:21:24-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Holding amendment No. 7, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Pallone demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T16:22:04-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 357, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Porter amendment No. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T16:37:56-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 357, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pappas amendment No. 9.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T16:47:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 357, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rouda amendment No. 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T16:57:30-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 357, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Malinowski amendment No. 11.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T17:07:35-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Malinowski amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Malinowski demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T17:07:50-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 357, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Wild amendment No. 12.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T17:18:48-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Wild amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Wild demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T18:03:17-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 986.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T18:04:09-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T18:05:33-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Walden moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3548" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T18:05:50-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Walden motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to prohibit the Secretary of HHS to waive protections for individuals with preexisting conditions, including guaranteed availablity and renewability of health insurance, the prohibition on using health status to vary premiums, and the prohibition on preexisting conditions exclusions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T18:18:45-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T18:27:03-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 182 - 231 (Roll no. 195).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="196" datetime="2019-05-09T18:36:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 230 - 183, 1 Present (Roll no. 196).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T18:36:02-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-05-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="90">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 90.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="116" relation="procedurally-related" number="357"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1884"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="identical" number="466"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h208"/>
    <amendment number="h207"/>
    <amendment number="h206"/>
    <amendment number="h205"/>
    <amendment number="h204"/>
    <amendment number="h203"/>
    <amendment number="h202"/>
    <amendment number="h201"/>
    <amendment number="h200"/>
    <amendment number="h199"/>
    <amendment number="h198"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2019-04-30T13:56:22Z" status="Reported to House, Part I">Protecting Americans with Preexisting Conditions Act of 2019

This bill nullifies the Department of the Treasury and the Department of Health and Human Services guidance titled "State Relief and Empowerment Waivers," published on October 24, 2018. The guidance pertains to Section 1332 waivers (also known as State Innovation Waivers or State Relief and Empowerment Waivers), which allow states to forego certain requirements of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act in order to implement experimental plans for health care coverage, as long as the resulting coverage meets certain statutory criteria.

The guidance, which supersedes earlier guidance from 2015, alters agency interpretation of how states may satisfy the statutory criteria for waiver approval. For example, the guidance (1) redefines acceptable coverage under such waivers to include short-term, limited-duration insurance and association health plans; (2) allows the comprehensiveness and affordability of coverage under such waivers to be assessed based on projected availability, rather than enrollment; and (3) allows the level of coverage to be assessed based on the effects over the entire course of the waiver, rather than per year.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-44</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
