<bill session="116" type="h" number="2968" updated="2019-09-24T14:30:23Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for the Department of Defense for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2020, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="display">Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000108"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-23">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 116-84, by Mr. Visclosky.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-05-23" state="REPORTED" calendar="Union" number="59">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 59.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2474"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2740"/>
    <bill type="sj" session="116" relation="unknown" number="7"/>
    <bill type="hj" session="116" relation="unknown" number="37"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-05-23T11:46:31Z" status="Reported to House">Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2020

This bill provides FY2020 appropriations to the Department of Defense (DOD) for military activities. The bill excludes military construction, military family housing, civil works projects of the Army Corps of Engineers, and nuclear warheads, which are all considered in other appropriations bills.

Within the DOD budget, the bill provides appropriations for

 Military Personnel; Operation and Maintenance; Procurement; Research, Development, Test and Evaluation; and Revolving and Management Funds. The bill provides appropriations for Other Department of Defense Programs, including

 the Defense Health Program, Chemical Agents and Munitions Destruction, Drug Interdiction and Counter-Drug Activities, and the Office of the Inspector General. The bill provides appropriations for (1) Related Agencies, including the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System Fund and the Intelligence Community Management Account; and (2) Overseas Contingency Operations/ Global War on Terrorism.

The bill also includes provisions that

 repeal the 2001 Authorization for Use of Military Force after 240 days; prohibit funds from being used to construct a wall, fence, border barriers, or border security infrastructure along the southern land border of the United States; prohibit funds from being used to deliver F-35 air vehicles or other F-35 weapon system equipment to Turkey; and direct the President to remove the Armed Forces from hostilities in or affecting Yemen unless a declaration of war or specific authorization has been enacted, with certain exceptions.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-84</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
