<bill session="116" type="hj" number="68" updated="2019-10-24T19:00:29Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Proposing a balanced budget amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</title>
    <title type="display">Proposing a balanced budget amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000590"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-06-20T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Constitutional Amendment 

This joint resolution proposes a constitutional amendment prohibiting total expenditures from exceeding total receipts for a fiscal year. The prohibition excludes expenditures for repayment of debt principal and receipts derived from borrowing.

For a national emergency, two-thirds of each chamber of Congress may authorize expenditures that exceed receipts for limited times. Debts incurred from the expenditures must be paid as soon as practicable.

The amendment requires a two-thirds roll call vote of each chamber of Congress to increase the public debt limit. It also requires the President to submit a balanced budget to Congress annually.

If the President does not submit a balanced budget for a fiscal year, any executive actions may be unilaterally overturned by a simple majority vote of each of chamber of Congress until the President submits a balanced budget.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
