<bill session="116" type="h" number="1508" updated="2019-07-30T13:22:41Z">
  <state datetime="2019-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for Move America bonds and Move America credits.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Move America Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Move America Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Move America Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000574"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2019-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001185" joined="2019-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000615" joined="2019-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000813" joined="2019-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E244"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="146"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-03-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Move America Act of 2019

This bill allows tax-exempt Move America bonds and Move America tax credits to be used for certain infrastructure projects.

A Move America bond is treated as a tax-exempt private facility bond with certain exceptions. At least 95% of the net proceeds from the issuance of the bond must be used for infrastructure projects, including

 airports; docks and wharves; mass commuting facilities; facilities for the furnishing of water; sewage facilities; railroads; certain surface transportation projects eligible for federal assistance, projects for an international bridge or tunnel, or facilities for transferring freight from truck to rail or rail to truck; flood diversions; inland waterways; or rural broadband service infrastructure. The bill specifies exceptions and modifications to existing rules for bonds regarding land acquisition, government ownership, rehabilitation expenditures, and the alternative minimum tax.

The bonds are subject to a volume cap equal to 50% of a state's current private activity bond volume cap. States may exchange all or a portion of the volume cap for Move America tax credits to be allocated to taxpayers. The credits include (1) an equity credit for a portion of the basis of each qualified facility; and (2) an infrastructure fund credit for investments in qualified infrastructure funds, including a state infrastructure bank, a water pollution control revolving fund, or a drinking water treatment revolving loan fund.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
