<bill session="116" type="s" number="1587" updated="2019-06-29T03:32:15Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to impose a tax on certain trading transactions to invest in our families and communities, improve our infrastructure and our environment, strengthen our financial security, expand opportunity and reduce market volatility.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Inclusive Prosperity Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Inclusive Prosperity Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Inclusive Prosperity Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2019-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="identical" number="2923"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-05-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Inclusive Prosperity Act of 2019

 This bill imposes an excise tax on the transfer of ownership in certain securities (covered transaction), including any share of stock in a corporation; any partnership or beneficial interest in a partnership or trust; any note, bond, debenture, or other evidence of indebtedness (excluding tax-exempt municipal bonds); and derivative financial instruments.

The bill includes exceptions for initial issues, certain traded short-term indebtedness, and securities lending arrangements.

The bill also (1) imposes a penalty on taxpayers who fail to include a covered transaction on their tax return or information statement, and (2) allows an individual taxpayer whose modified adjusted gross income does not exceed $50,000 ($75,000 for married taxpayers filing joint returns) a tax credit for the amount of tax paid on covered transactions.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
