<bill session="116" type="h" number="1640" updated="2019-11-02T07:16:09Z">
  <state datetime="2019-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide for the admission of certain sons and daughters of citizens of the United States, which citizens served on active duty in the Armed Forces of the United States abroad, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Uniting Families Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Uniting Families Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Uniting Families Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000188"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2019-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000132" joined="2019-11-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Citizenship" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-03-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Uniting Families Act of 2019 

This bill establishes a non-immigrant visa category for an alien who (1) is 18 or older and is the genetic son or daughter of a U.S. citizen who served in the Armed Forces on active duty abroad; or (2) is the spouse or child of such alien and is accompanying, or following to join, such alien.

To obtain a visa, the alien's citizen parent must petition and receive approval from the Department of Homeland Security. The petition shall include (1) DNA evidence establishing the parent-child relationship, (2) a written statement that the parent will provide financial support until the alien receives lawful permanent resident status, and (3) proof of the parent's U.S. citizenship and active duty with the Armed Forces abroad.

The period of authorized admission for aliens with the visa is five years, and 5,000 principal visa aliens may be admitted per fiscal year. Holders of such a visa may adjust to lawful permanent resident status after meeting various requirements, such as being admissible as an immigrant.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
