<bill session="116" type="h" number="2367" updated="2019-07-31T07:33:35Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to require a lifetime income disclosure.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lifetime Income Disclosure Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lifetime Income Disclosure Act</title>
    <title type="display">Lifetime Income Disclosure Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000607"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2019-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001124" joined="2019-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000391" joined="2019-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001187" joined="2019-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001201" joined="2019-04-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1574"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="972"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1994"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1084"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1007"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-04-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Lifetime Income Disclosure Act 

This bill requires pension benefit statements to include a lifetime income disclosure at least once during any 12-month period.

The disclosure must set forth the lifetime income stream equivalent of the total benefits accrued with respect to the participant or beneficiary. The "lifetime income stream equivalent of the total benefits accrued" is the amount of monthly payments the participant or beneficiary would receive if the total accrued benefits were used to provide lifetime income streams based on certain assumptions, including that the participant or beneficiary has a spouse of equal age and a single life annuity.

The Department of Labor must issue a model lifetime income disclosure, assumptions that plan administrators may use in converting total accrued benefits into lifetime income stream equivalents, and related rules.

No plan fiduciary, sponsor, or other person may be liable under the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) solely due to the provision of lifetime income stream equivalents derived in accordance with the assumptions and related rules issued by Labor, including explanations contained in the model lifetime income disclosure.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
