<bill session="116" type="s" number="476" updated="2019-07-31T07:34:32Z">
  <state datetime="2019-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Creating Transparency to Have Drug Rebates Unlocked (C-THRU) Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Creating Transparency to Have Drug Rebates Unlocked (C&#8211;THRU) Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XI and XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide greater transparency of discounts provided by drug manufacturers.</title>
    <title type="display">Creating Transparency to Have Drug Rebates Unlocked (C-THRU) Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2019-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000174" joined="2019-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2019-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2019-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-02-13T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Creating Transparency to Have Drug Rebates Unlocked (C-THRU) Act of 2019

This bill establishes a series of requirements relating to drug rebates and discounts under Medicare and Medicare Advantage (MA).

 Specifically, for each pharmacy benefits manager (PBM) that contracts with a prescription drug&#160;plan (PDP) under Medicare or&#160;MA,&#160;or with a qualified health benefits plan offered through a health insurance exchange,&#160;HHS must publish on its website (1) the amount and type of rebates and discounts negotiated by the PBM and the extent to which these rebates and discounts are passed on to the plan sponsor, and (2) the difference between the amount paid by the plan sponsor to the PBM and the amount paid by the PBM to pharmacies.

As a condition of participation as a contractor&#160;under Medicare or MA, a PBM must pass&#160;on to&#160;a&#160;PDP sponsor a minimum percentage, as established by HHS, of the amount of rebates and discounts negotiated by the PBM that are attributable to patient utilization under the plan.

The bill also&#160;modifies requirements&#160;regarding Medicare enrollees' access to negotiated drug prices.&#160;Current law requires&#160;a PDP sponsor&#160;to provide enrollees in Medicare&#160;or MA&#160;with access to negotiated&#160;drug prices that&#160;account for rebates and discounts. The bill requires&#160;that, with respect to a covered drug,&#160;a&#160;negotiated price (or,&#160;if necessary, an approximate negotiated price)&#160;be provided at the point of sale.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
