<bill session="116" type="s" number="223" updated="2019-02-27T14:27:06Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Patriot Employer Tax Credit Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Patriot Employer Tax Credit Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a tax credit to Patriot employers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Patriot Employer Tax Credit Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2019-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S589-590" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="802"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-24T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Patriot Employer Tax Credit Act

This bill allows a Patriot employer a business-related tax credit equal to 10% of up to $15,000 of wages paid to any employee in a taxable year.

The bill sets forth criteria for designation as a Patriot employer, including requirements that the employer

 maintain its headquarters in the United States and not expatriate to avoid payment of U.S. income taxes, comply with the employer mandate to provide minimum essential health care coverage to its employees under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, provide employees with paid sick leave or paid family and medical leave, compensate at least 90% of its employees at an hourly rate that is at least 218% of the federal poverty level for an individual for the calendar year divided by 1,750 and provide at least 90% of its employees with a basic level of retirement benefits, provide for differential wage payments to its employees who are members of the Uniformed Services, have a written policy in place for the recruitment of employees who have served in the Uniformed Services or who are disabled, and increase the number of its employees performing substantially all of their services inside the United States to offset the number of employees who work outside the United States.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
