<bill session="116" type="h" number="3088" updated="2019-10-01T21:15:24Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Securities and Exchange Commission to adjust certain resubmission thresholds for shareholder proposals.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Shareholder Protection Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Shareholder Protection Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Shareholder Protection Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000614"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-27T11:29:15-04:00">
      <text>ASSUMING FIRST SPONSORSHIP - Mr. Steil asked unanimous consent that he may hereafter be considered as the first sponsor of H.R. 3088, a bill originally introduced by Representative Duffy, for the purpose of adding cosponsors and requesting reprintings pursuant to clause 7 of rule XIII. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-06-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Shareholder Protection Act of 2019

This bill directs the Securities and Exchange Commission to increase specified resubmission thresholds for shareholder proposals. (Current regulations allow the resubmission of a shareholder proposal that has been previously included in an issuer's proxy materials if, when the proposal was last included, it received a specified percentage of the vote; this percentage, which&#160;varies&#160;depending upon the number of times a proposal has been previously submitted, represents the minimum threshold at which resubmission is permissible.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
