<amendment session="116" chamber="h" number="160" updated="2019-08-21T15:51:04Z">
  <amends type="h" number="1644" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2019-04-10T10:57:03-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000630"/>
  <offered datetime="2019-04-09"/>
  <description>Amendment requires GAO to produce a report, within 1 year, reviewing the benefits to consumers of broadband internet access providers offering broadband internet access service on a standalone basis and what steps Congress can take to increase the availability of standalone broadband internet access service to consumers, particularly those living in rural areas.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 4 printed in Part A of House Report 116-37 to require GAO to produce a report, within 1 year, reviewing the benefits to consumers of broadband internet access providers offering broadband internet access service on a standalone basis and what steps Congress can take to increase the availability of standalone broadband internet access service to consumers, particularly those living in rural areas.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2019-04-10T10:57:03-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="163">
      <text>On agreeing to the Delgado amendment (A004) Agreed to by recorded vote: 363 - 60 (Roll no. 163).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-04-09T16:57:58-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A004) offered by Mr. Delgado.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3182-3183" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3182" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-09"/>
    <action datetime="2019-04-09T16:57:58-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A004) offered by Mr. Delgado.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3182-3183" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3182" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-10T10:57:03-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Delgado amendment (A004) Agreed to by recorded vote: 363 - 60 (Roll no. 163).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-10T10:57:03-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-10T10:57:03-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-09">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
