<amendment session="116" chamber="h" number="199" updated="2019-06-29T07:12:38Z">
  <amends type="h" number="986" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2019-05-09T17:45:57-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001304"/>
  <offered datetime="2019-05-09"/>
  <description>Page 3, line 17, insert after the period the following new sentence: "Nothing in the previous sentence shall be construed to affect the approval of waivers under section 1332 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (42 U.S.C. 18052) that establish reinsurance programs that are consistent with the requirements under subsection (b)(1) of such section (42 U.S.C. 18052(b)(1)), lower health insurance premiums, and protect health insurance coverage for people with preexisting conditions.".</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 2 printed in Part A of House Report 116-51 to ensure that nothing in the bill will be construed to affect the approval of waivers under section 1332 of the ACA that establish reinsurance programs that lower health insurance premiums, and protect health insurance coverage for people with preexisting conditions.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2019-05-09T17:45:57-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="191">
      <text>On agreeing to the Brown (MD) amendment (A002) Agreed to by recorded vote: 351 - 70 (Roll no. 191).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T15:36:17-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Brown (MD).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3532-3533, H3545" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3532" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09"/>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T17:45:57-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Brown (MD) amendment (A002) Agreed to by recorded vote: 351 - 70 (Roll no. 191).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T17:45:57-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T17:45:57-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09T15:36:17-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Brown (MD).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
