<bill session="116" type="s" number="1132" updated="2019-06-05T04:42:29Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title II of the Social Security Act and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make improvements in the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program, and to provide for Social Security benefit protection.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting and Preserving Social Security Act</title>
    <title type="display">Protecting and Preserving Social Security Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2019-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2019-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2019-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2389" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2654"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2302"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-04-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting and Preserving Social Security Act 

This bill revises the methodology for calculating Old Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance (OASDI) benefits and phases out the cap on compensation subject to Social Security taxation.

The bill directs the Bureau of Labor Statistics to prepare and publish a Consumer Price Index for Elderly Consumers (CPI-E) to track cost-of-living changes for individuals age 62 or older. The Social Security Administration shall use the CPI-E to calculate the cost-of-living adjustment for OASDI benefits, where it currently uses the Consumer Price Index for Urban Wage Earners and Clerical Workers.

The bill phases out and after 2025 eliminates&#160;the cap on compensation ($132,900 in 2019) subject to Social Security taxation. This change applies to both wage earners and the self-employed.

The bill also changes the calculation for the primary insurance amount (the amount received by a beneficiary who elects to receive OASDI benefits at full retirement age) by including the additional earnings that are now taxed as a result of the cap elimination.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
