<bill session="116" type="s" number="1067" updated="2019-09-27T10:00:37Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for research to better understand the causes and consequences of sexual harassment affecting individuals in the scientific, technical, engineering, and mathematics workforce and to examine policies to reduce the prevalence and negative impact of such harassment, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combating Sexual Harassment in Science Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combating Sexual Harassment in Science Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Combating Sexual Harassment in Science Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2019-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2019-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2019-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2019-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2019-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2019-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2019-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2019-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2019-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2019-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2019-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2019-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-04-08T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Combating Sexual Harassment in Science Act of 2019

This bill addresses sexual harassment in the science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) fields by supporting sexual harassment research and efforts to prevent and respond to sexual harassment.

This bill directs the National Science Foundation (NSF) to award grants to institutions of higher education or nonprofit organizations (or their consortia) to

 expand research into sexual harassment in the STEM workforce, including students and trainees; and examine interventions for reducing the incidence and negative consequences of such harassment. The NSF must convene a working group composed of representatives of federal statistical agencies to develop questions on sexual harassment in STEM departments in order to gather national data on the prevalence, nature, and implications of such harassment in institutions of higher education.

The NSF shall enter into agreements with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine to (1) update a responsible conduct guide issued by the National Academies, and (2) study the influence of sexual harassment in institutions of higher education on the career advancement of individuals in the STEM workforce.

The National Science and Technology Council shall establish an interagency working group to coordinate the federal science agencies' efforts to reduce the prevalence of sexual harassment involving grant personnel.

The Office of Science and Technology Policy must develop a uniform set of policy guidelines for such agencies to prevent and respond to reports of sexual harassment.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
