<bill session="116" type="s" number="541" updated="2019-09-25T05:22:07Z">
  <state datetime="2019-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Labor to establish a pilot program for providing portable benefits to eligible workers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Portable Benefits for Independent Workers Pilot Program Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Portable Benefits for Independent Workers Pilot Program Act</title>
    <title type="display">Portable Benefits for Independent Workers Pilot Program Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000805"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2019-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2019-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2019-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2019-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2019-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001197" joined="2019-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2019-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="identical" number="4016"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-02-25T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Portable Benefits for Independent Workers Pilot Program Act 

This bill requires the Department of Labor to award grants for FY2020, on a competitive basis, to states, local governments, or nonprofit organizations to support broad innovation and experimentation with respect to portable benefits.

Portable benefits are work-related benefits that are provided to workers who are not traditional full-time employees in a manner that allows the worker to maintain the benefits upon changing jobs.

The grants must be used for (1) the evaluation, or improvement to the design or implementation, of existing models or approaches for providing portable benefits; or (2) the design, implementation, and evaluation of new models or approaches for providing such benefits. The grants may not be used for a model or approach that provides only retirement-related benefits.

The Government Accountability Office must evaluate and report to Congress on the outcome of the grants awarded pursuant to this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
