<bill session="116" type="h" number="130" updated="2019-07-30T13:05:46Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit States from carrying out more than one Congressional redistricting after a decennial census and apportionment, to require States to conduct such redistricting through independent commissions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">John Tanner Fairness and Independence in Redistricting Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">John Tanner Fairness and Independence in Redistricting Act</title>
    <title type="display">John Tanner Fairness and Independence in Redistricting Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000754"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001202" joined="2019-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="44"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="124"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts and representation"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="State and local courts"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">John Tanner Fairness and Independence in Redistricting Act

This bill establishes requirements regarding congressional redistricting, including that redistricting plans must be developed by an independent redistricting commission.

A state that has been redistricted after an apportionment of Representatives may not be redistricted again until after the next apportionment, unless the state is ordered by a court to conduct a subsequent redistricting in order to comply with the Constitution or enforce the Voting Rights Act of 1965.

Each state must establish an independent redistricting commission to develop redistricting plans that meet specified criteria. If such a plan is not enacted into law, a state's highest court may select a plan developed by the state's commission. If the state court does not select a plan, a U.S. district court must develop a plan.

The Election Assistance Commission must make payments to states to carry out redistricting.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
