<amendment session="116" chamber="h" number="636" updated="2019-10-25T21:45:32Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2513" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2019-10-22T18:17:44-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000087"/>
  <offered datetime="2019-10-22"/>
  <description>Page 17, after line 19, insert the following:    "(D) DISCLOSURE OF NON-PII DATA.-Notwithstanding subparagraph (B), FinCEN may issue guidance and otherwise make materials available to financial institutions and the public using beneficial ownership information reported pursuant to this section if such information is aggregated in a manner that removes all personally identifiable information. For purposes of this subparagraph, 'personally identifiable information' includes information that would allow for the identification of a particular corporation or limited liability company.".</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 4 printed in Part B of House Report 116-247 to ensure FinCEN may use the information obtained by this bill to notify industry and the public about criminal trends, while maintaining safeguards on personal privacy.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2019-10-22T18:17:44-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="574">
      <text>On agreeing to the Maloney, Carolyn B. amendment (A004) Agreed to by recorded vote: 235 - 188 (Roll no. 574).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T15:22:44-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A004) offered by Mrs. Maloney, Carolyn B..</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8337-8338, H8366-8367" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8337" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22"/>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T15:22:44-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A004) offered by Mrs. Maloney, Carolyn B..</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8337-8338, H8366-8367" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8337" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T18:17:44-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Maloney, Carolyn B. amendment (A004) Agreed to by recorded vote: 235 - 188 (Roll no. 574).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T18:17:44-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T18:17:44-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
