<bill session="116" type="h" number="4317" updated="2019-09-23T15:30:21Z">
  <state datetime="2019-09-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-09-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-09-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend and expand the new energy efficient home credit, to extend the energy efficient commercial buildings deduction, to eliminate the basis reduction for low-income housing properties receiving certain energy benefits, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Building Efficiently Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Building Efficiently Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Building Efficiently Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000559"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2019-09-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-09-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-09-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Building Efficiently Act of 2019

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to expand the new energy efficient home tax credit to allow, in lieu of the existing credit, a credit for 3.3% of the cost of constructing a new energy efficient home that is a qualified energy efficient residential rental property.

An energy efficient residential rental property must be certified as being constructed, reconstructed, or retrofitted under a plan designed to reduce energy and power consumption of the building by at least 40% compared to (1) the baseline annual energy and power consumption of the building in the case of a retrofit made to an existing building, or (2) a reference building which meets the minimum requirements of the International Energy Conservation Code 2018 in any other case.

The bill also (1) extends through 2020 the energy efficient commercial buildings deduction; and (2) eliminates the basis reduction requirements for certain low-income housing properties receiving the energy efficient home credit, the energy efficient commercial building deduction, or the credit for investments in energy property.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
