<bill session="116" type="s" number="1332" updated="2019-09-04T15:42:12Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-03">PROV_KILL:CLOTUREFAILED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to set forth the congressional budget for the United States Government for fiscal year 2020 and setting forth the appropriate budgetary levels for fiscal years 2021 through 2029.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to set forth the congressional budget for the United States Government for fiscal year 2020 and setting forth the appropriate budgetary levels for fiscal years 2021 through 2029.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-05-07" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="78">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 78.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-05-23">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3086"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-23">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed to the measure presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3086"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-03">
      <text>Motion to proceed to measure considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3145"/>
    </action>
    <vote-aux how="roll" type="cloture" roll="130" datetime="2019-06-03" where="s" result="fail" state="PROV_KILL:CLOTUREFAILED">
      <text>Cloture on the motion to proceed to the measure not invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 22 - 69. Record Vote Number: 130.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3153"/>
    </vote-aux>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="sc" session="116" relation="unknown" number="12"/>
    <bill type="sc" session="116" relation="unknown" number="11"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Economic theory"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="U.S. Postal Service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-05-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill establishes the congressional budget for the federal government for FY2020 and sets forth budgetary levels for FY2021-FY2029.

The bill recommends levels and amounts for FY2020-FY2029 for

 federal revenues, new budget authority, budget outlays, deficits, public debt, debt held by the public, and the major functional categories of spending. It also recommends levels and amounts for FY2020-FY2029 in the Senate for Social Security and Postal Service discretionary administrative expenses.

The bill includes reconciliation instructions that direct several Senate committees to report and submit to the Senate Budget Committee legislation to reduce the deficit by specified amounts over FY2020-FY2029. The committees include

 the Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry Committee; the Senate Armed Services Committee; the Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs Committee; the Senate Energy and Natural Resources Committee; the Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee; the Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee; and the Senate Veterans Affairs Committee. The Senate Finance Committee must report and submit legislation to reduce the deficit and revenues by specified amounts over FY2020-FY2029.

(Under the Congressional Budget Act of 1974, reconciliation bills are considered by Congress using expedited legislative procedures that prevent a filibuster and restrict amendments in the Senate.)

The bill establishes reserve funds that provide flexibility in applying budget enforcement rules to legislation relating to (1) efficiencies, consolidations, and other savings; or (2) health savings accounts.

It also sets forth budget enforcement procedures for legislation considered in the Senate.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
