<bill session="116" type="h" number="876" updated="2019-07-30T13:14:49Z">
  <state datetime="2019-02-06T12:25:44-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-02-06T12:25:44-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to carry out a plan for the purchase and installation of an earthquake early warning system for the Cascadia Subduction Zone, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Pacific Northwest Earthquake Preparedness Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Pacific Northwest Earthquake Preparedness Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pacific Northwest Earthquake Preparedness Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pacific Northwest Earthquake Preparedness Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Pacific Northwest Earthquake Preparedness Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2019-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000616" joined="2019-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-06T12:18:33-05:00">
      <text>Mr. DeFazio moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-06T12:18:50-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1368-1370" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-06T12:18:53-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 876.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2019-02-06T12:25:44-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1368-1369" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-02-06T12:25:49-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-02-06T14:46:10Z" status="Passed House">Pacific Northwest Earthquake Preparedness Act of 2019

This bill requires the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to develop a plan for the purchase and installation of an earthquake early warning system for the Cascadia Subduction Zone. The term "Cascadia Subduction Zone" means the landward-dipping fault that is approximately 684 miles long, separates the Juan De Fuca and North America plates, and stretches along a portion of the western coast of the United States beginning off Cape Mendocino, California, along the states of Oregon and Washington, to Northern Vancouver Island, British Columbia, Canada.

The President shall establish an Earthquake and Tsunami Task Force to develop a comprehensive strategy and recommendations on how the nation should prepare and plan for, mitigate against, respond to, recover from, and more successfully adapt to an earthquake, tsunami, or combined earthquake and tsunami event in the Cascadia Subduction Zone. FEMA shall report to Congress on the comprehensive strategy and task force recommendations.

The task force shall enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences for developing recommendations for a federal research strategy to advance scientific understanding of a Cascadia Subduction Zone earthquake and resulting tsunami preparedness.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
