<bill session="116" type="h" number="3475" updated="2019-10-01T21:15:21Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to provide for necessary payments from the Spectrum Relocation Fund for costs of spectrum research and development and planning activities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SPECTRUM NOW Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SPECTRUM NOW Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supplementing the Pipeline for Efficient Control of The Resources for Users Making New Opportunities for Wireless Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supplementing the Pipeline for Efficient Control of The Resources for Users Making New Opportunities for Wireless Act</title>
    <title type="display">SPECTRUM NOW Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001163"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000558" joined="2019-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="4171"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="identical" number="1968"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Radio spectrum allocation"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-06-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Supplementing the Pipeline for Efficient Control of The Resources for Users Making New Opportunities for Wireless Act or the SPECTRUM NOW Act

This bill directs&#160;federal entities operating on mid-band spectrum to study the feasibility of (1) increasing spectrum efficiency, and (2) relocating federally held spectrum or sharing it with commercial users to facilitate the deployment of 5G. These federal entities must then submit plans for repurposing their spectrum, or a portion thereof, for commercial wireless use.

Further, the National Telecommunications and Information Administration must consult with the Federal Communications Commission and the relevant federal entity to determine whether spectrum may be made available on an unlicensed basis if the entity determines it is not feasible to make spectrum available on a licensed basis in accordance with the bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
