<bill session="116" type="h" number="463" updated="2019-10-31T07:15:47Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide for forgiveness of certain overpayments of retired pay paid to deceased retired members of the Armed Forces.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Retiree Survivor Comfort Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Retiree Survivor Comfort Act</title>
    <title type="display">Military Retiree Survivor Comfort Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000255"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2019-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000576" joined="2019-10-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-20T11:08:16-04:00">
      <text>ASSUMING FIRST SPONSORSHIP - Mr. Garamendi asked unanimous consent that he may hereafter be considered as the first sponsor of H.R. 463, a bill originally introduced by Representative Jones, for the purpose of adding cosponsors and requesting reprintings pursuant to clause 7 of rule XIII. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Military Retiree Survivor Comfort Act 

This bill requires the United States to forgive any overpayment of military retired or retainer pay for any period after the death of the recipient through the last day of the month in which such death occurs, if such payment is electronically deposited to a joint account bearing the name of the decedent and the decedent's designated beneficiary.

The bill provides a special effective date for the first annuity payment to a survivor under the Survivor Benefit Plan when an overpayment is so forgiven.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
