<bill session="116" type="h" number="2181" updated="2019-11-02T07:16:30Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-30T17:18:55-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-10-30T17:18:55-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the withdrawal and protection of certain Federal land in the State of New Mexico.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Chaco Cultural Heritage Area Protection Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Chaco Cultural Heritage Area Protection Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Chaco Cultural Heritage Area Protection Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Chaco Cultural Heritage Area Protection Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Chaco Cultural Heritage Area Protection Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Chaco Cultural Heritage Area Protection Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Chaco Cultural Heritage Area Protection Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000570"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2019-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000629" joined="2019-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000574" joined="2019-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2019-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001080" joined="2019-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2019-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2019-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2019-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2019-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000484" joined="2019-04-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-05">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-17">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-07-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 19 - 14.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-07-17">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-04">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 116-224.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-10-04" calendar="Union" number="177">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 177.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-10-28T19:41:13-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 656 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 823, H.R. 1373 and H.R. 2181. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate for H.R. 823, H.R. 1373 and H.R. 2181. The resolution provides for proceedings during the period from November 1, 2019 through November 11, 2019.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-29T14:18:11-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 656 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-30T14:38:45-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 656.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8622-8640" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8631-8632" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-30T14:38:50-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 823, H.R. 1373 and H.R. 2181. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate for H.R. 823, H.R. 1373 and H.R. 2181. The resolution provides for proceedings during the period from November 1, 2019 through November 11, 2019.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-30T14:38:55-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 656 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-30T14:38:56-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Henry Cuellar to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-30T14:40:19-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2181.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-30T15:33:21-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 656, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lujan Amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-30T15:42:55-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 656, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gosar Amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-30T15:49:40-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gosar amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Gosar demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-30T15:50:43-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 656, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gosar Amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-30T15:56:49-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gosar amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Gosar demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-30T15:57:59-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 656, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Arrington Amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-30T16:07:35-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Arrington amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Arrington demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-30T16:53:09-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2181.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-30T16:53:54-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-30T16:55:10-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Arrington moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8638" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-30T16:55:32-04:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Arrington motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to prohibit the bill from going into effect if the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Governor of New Mexico, determines that the state of New Mexico would incur a loss of revenue in relation to the permanent withdrawal under the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-30T17:04:10-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-30T17:12:02-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 199 - 222 (Roll no. 596).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="597" datetime="2019-10-30T17:18:55-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 245 - 174 (Roll no. 597).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-10-30T17:18:57-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-31">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="116" relation="procedurally-related" number="656"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="identical" number="1079"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h658"/>
    <amendment number="h657"/>
    <amendment number="h656"/>
    <amendment number="h655"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2019-10-04T12:38:11Z" status="Reported to House">Chaco Cultural Heritage Area Protection Act of 2019

This bill withdraws any federal lands and interests that are within the boundaries of the Chaco Cultural Heritage Withdrawal Area and any land or interest located in such area which is acquired by the United States after enactment of this bill from

 entry, appropriation, and disposal under the public land laws; location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws. The Department of the Interior may convey the federal lands to, or exchange such lands with, an Indian tribe in accordance with an approved resource management plan.

Certain oil and gas leases for federal lands on which drilling options have not started before the end of the primary term of the applicable lease and that are not producing oil or gas in paying quantities

 must terminate by operation of law pursuant to the Mineral Leasing Act and federal regulations, and may not be extended by Interior. Any portion of federal land subject to such a lease that has been terminated, relinquished, or acquired by the United States shall also be withdrawn as described above.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-224</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
