<bill session="116" type="h" number="1180" updated="2019-10-30T15:00:33Z">
  <state datetime="2019-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a period of continuing appropriations in the event of a lapse in appropriations under the normal appropriations process, and to prohibit consideration of other matters in the House of Representatives if appropriations are not enacted.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">End Shutdowns Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">End Shutdowns Act</title>
    <title type="display">End Shutdowns Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001292"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2019-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="identical" number="281"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-02-13T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">End Shutdowns Act

This bill provides continuing appropriations to prevent a government shutdown if any appropriations measure for a fiscal year has not been enacted before the fiscal year begins and continuing appropriations are not in effect.

 The bill provides appropriations at the rate of operations that was provided for the prior fiscal year to continue programs, projects, and activities for which funds were provided in the preceding fiscal year.

The bill also prohibits the House of Representatives from considering matters other than appropriations or emergency legislation on or after October 1 of each fiscal year if continuing appropriations provided by this bill are in effect.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
