<bill session="116" type="s" number="2299" updated="2019-11-01T04:59:32Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-31">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to enhance the safety and reliability of pipeline transportation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PIPES Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PIPES Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Leonel Rondon Pipeline Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Leonel Rondon Pipeline Safety Act</title>
    <title type="display">PIPES Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000463"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2019-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-07-31" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1097"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2139"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-07-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">PIPES Act of 2019

This bill addresses pipeline safety and infrastructure. It authorizes appropriations through FY2023 for specified pipeline safety programs under the Pipeline Safety Improvement Act of 2002 and related enactments.

Among other things, the bill

 requires fees for compliance reviews of liquefied natural gas (LNG) facilities; authorizes the establishment of limited safety-enhancing testing programs to evaluate innovative technologies and operational practices testing the safe operation of natural gas or hazardous liquid pipeline facilities; sets forth requirements for idled natural or other gas transmission and hazardous liquid pipelines; updates the standards for LNG facilities; establishes the National Center of Excellence for Liquefied Natural Gas Safety and Training to include a repository of information on best practices relating to LNG operations; requires each distribution integrity plan developed by an operator of a gas distribution pipeline to include the risks from the presence of cast iron pipes and mains and risks that may result from the operation of a low-pressure distribution system; directs operators to establish protocols for communicating with fire, police, and other relevant public officials after a disaster that includes fires, explosions, or one or more fatalities; and requires procedural manuals for operations, maintenance, and emergencies to include certain written procedures.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
