<bill session="116" type="h" number="379" updated="2019-07-30T13:09:06Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To limit the authority of a State to require remote sellers to collect taxes and fees owed by purchasers then located in such State incident to their purchases of goods and services from such sellers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Businesses from Burdensome Compliance Cost Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Businesses from Burdensome Compliance Cost Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Protecting Businesses from Burdensome Compliance Cost Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000584" joined="2019-01-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Antitrust, Commercial, and Administrative Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Antitrust, Commercial, and Administrative Law" code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-09T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Businesses from Burdensome Compliance Cost Act of 2019

This bill limits the authority of a state to require a remote seller to collect (1) a tax or fee owed by a purchaser located in the state incident to a purchase of a good or service from the seller, and (2) information incident to the purchase. A remote seller is a seller with no physical presence in the state in which the purchaser is located at the time of the purchase.

A state may not impose the requirements for collecting taxes or fees and related information on a remote seller unless the purchase occurs after this bill takes effect and the tax or fee is imposed under a statute in effect in the state where the purchaser is located at the time of the purchase. A subdivision of a state may not impose the requirements on a remote seller.

The tax or fee must apply to purchases throughout the state of the good or service. The rate must be uniform and may not exceed the combined rate of the state and local taxes and fees payable by purchasers in the state of the good or service from sellers physically present in the state.

The state statute may not require the seller to (1) remit the taxes or fees to more than one location, or (2) provide information about the purchaser other than the zip code of the purchase and the aggregate amount of fees or taxes collected in a particular zip code.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
