<bill session="116" type="s" number="1110" updated="2019-06-01T09:19:36Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for restoration, economic development, recreation, and conservation on Federal lands in Northern California, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Northwest California Wilderness, Recreation, and Working Forests Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Northwest California Wilderness, Recreation, and Working Forests Act</title>
    <title type="display">Northwest California Wilderness, Recreation, and Working Forests Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2019-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2250"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against animals and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Insects"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-04-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Northwest California Wilderness, Recreation, and Working Forests Act

This bill sets forth provisions concerning the restoration, economic development, and conservation of, and recreational access to, certain public lands in Northern California.

The bill establishes

 the South Fork Trinity-Mad River Restoration Area, the Northwest California Public Lands Remediation Partnership, the Trinity Lake and Del Norte County visitor centers, the Horse Mountain Special Management Area, the Elk Camp Ridge National Recreation Trail, and the Sanhedrin Conservation Management Area. The bill designates

 specified federal lands as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, the North Fork Wilderness as the North Fork Eel River Wilderness, specified federal lands as potential wilderness areas, and specified segments of certain rivers and creeks and of a specified river estuary as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System. Also, the bill

 authorizes the use of certain forest residues for research and development of biobased products that&#160;result in net carbon sequestration; authorizes initiatives to restore degraded redwood forest ecosystems in the Redwood National Forest and state parks; requires studies concerning certain visitor accommodations and recreational trails in the Six Rivers, Shasta-Trinity, and Mendocino National Forests, as applicable; authorizes partnerships for trail and campground maintenance, public education, visitor contacts, and visitor center staffing on federal lands in Mendocino, Humboldt, Trinity, and Del Norte Counties; and adjusts the boundaries of the Elkhorn Ridge Wilderness.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
