<bill session="116" type="hr" number="445" updated="2019-10-04T11:30:20Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-19T14:06:41-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-06-19T14:06:41-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3055) making appropriations for the Departments of Commerce and Justice, Science, and Related Agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2020, and for other purposes; relating to consideration of the bill (H.R. 2740) making appropriations for the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2020, and for other purposes; and providing for proceedings during the period from June 28, 2019, through July 8, 2019.</title>
    <title type="display">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3055) making appropriations for the Departments of Commerce and Justice, Science, and Related Agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2020, and for other purposes; relating to consideration of the bill (H.R. 2740) making appropriations for the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2020, and for other purposes; and providing for proceedings during the period from June 28, 2019, through July 8, 2019.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000312"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 116-119, by Mr. McGovern.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T01:10:26-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3055 under a structured rule. Rule also provides for proceedings during the period from June 28, 2019, through July 9, 2019. Rule also provides that it shall be in order on the legislative day of June 27, 2019, that the House suspend the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-06-19" state="REPORTED" calendar="House" number="30">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 30.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T12:11:30-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4779-4787" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T12:18:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 445.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T12:20:42-04:00">
      <text>UNANIMOUS CONSENT REQUEST - Mr. McGovern asked unanimous consent that the amendment at the desk be considered as though printed as amendment No. 123 in Part B of House Report 116-119, if offered by Mrs. Lee (NV) or her designee, be debatable for 10 minutes equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent. The Clerk reported the amendment. Mr. Woodall objected to the unanimous consent request. Subsequently, the objection was withdrawn. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T12:20:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed with debate on H. Res. 445.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T13:21:07-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDING - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 445, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Woodall demanded the yeas and nays on ordering the previous question and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T13:30:50-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4787-4789" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T13:56:49-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 232 - 193 (Roll no. 356).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4787-4788" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="357" datetime="2019-06-19T14:06:41-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 231 - 195 (Roll no. 357).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4779-4780" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19T14:06:42-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2740"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="procedurally-related" number="3055"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-06-19T20:57:56Z" status="Passed House">This resolution sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 3055 (Commerce, Justice, Science, Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, Interior, Environment, Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, Transportation, and Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2020) and H.R. 2740 (Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020).

Certain proceedings may take place on any legislative day from June 28, 2019, through July 8, 2019.

It shall be in order (1) to consider concurrent resolutions providing for adjournment during July 2019, and (2) at any time on the legislative day of June 27, 2019, for the Speaker of the House to suspend the rules.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-119</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
