<bill session="116" type="hr" number="497" updated="2019-10-04T20:45:20Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-17T18:23:44-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-07-17T18:23:44-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Recommending that the House of Representatives find William P. Barr, Attorney General of the United States, and Wilbur L. Ross, Jr., Secretary of Commerce, in contempt of Congress for refusal to comply with subpoenas duly issued by the Committee on Oversight and Reform.</title>
    <title type="display">Recommending that the House of Representatives find William P. Barr, Attorney General of the United States, and Wilbur L. Ross, Jr., Secretary of Commerce, in contempt of Congress for refusal to comply with subpoenas duly issued by the Committee on Oversight and Reform.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000984"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-17T14:09:58-04:00">
      <text>By direction of the Committee on Oversight and Reform, Mr. Cummings called up H. Res. 497 and asked for its immediate consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-17T14:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 491.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5941-5949" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-17T14:10:01-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3494 and H. Res. 489 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 3494 under a structured rule; provides for consideration of a resolution relating to House Report 116-125, if called up by direction of the Committee on Overisight and Reform; provides for consideration of a joint resolution reported by the Committee on Foreign Affairs regarding the Arms Export Control Act; provides for consideration of H. Res. 489.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-17T14:10:10-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 497.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-17T15:26:50-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-17T15:27:09-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 497, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the resolution and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Comer demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the resolution until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-17T18:17:25-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5977-5978" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="489" datetime="2019-07-17T18:23:44-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 230 - 198 (Roll no. 489).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5942" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-07-17T18:23:46-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-23T19:57:45-04:00">
      <text>CHAIR ANNOUNCEMENT - The Chair informed the House that, pursuant to H.Res. 497, the Speaker has certified to the United States Attorney for the District of Columbia the refusal of William P. Barr and Wilbur L. Ross, Jr., to produce documents to the Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="House Committee on Oversight and Reform"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-07-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This resolution finds Attorney General William P. Barr and Secretary of Commerce Wilbur L. Ross, Jr. in contempt of Congress for failing to comply with certain subpoenas authorized and issued by the House Committee on Oversight and Reform relating to the 2020 census. The resolution states that Mr. Barr and Mr. Ross failed to produce documents in compliance with subpoenas issued on April 2, 2019. The resolution also states that Mr. Barr ordered a Department of Justice employee, John Gore, not to comply with an April 11, 2019, subpoena requiring Mr. Gore to appear for deposition testimony before the committee.

The House of Representatives must certify to the U.S. Attorney for the District of Columbia a committee report detailing the failure to comply with the subpoenas.

The resolution requires the House and committee to take additional action to enforce the subpoenas.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
