<bill session="116" type="h" number="3323" updated="2019-10-23T07:20:58Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to repeal certain rules related to the determination of unrelated business taxable income, to provide that reimbursements for costs of using passenger automobiles for charitable organizations are excluded from gross income, to make the employer credit for paid family and medical leave available to tax-exempt eligible employers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nonprofit Relief Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nonprofit Relief Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Nonprofit Relief Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000537" joined="2019-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001201" joined="2019-10-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-06-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Nonprofit Relief Act of 2019

This bill amends Internal Revenue Code provisions relating to tax-exempt or organizations to

 repeal the requirement that the unrelated business taxable income of tax-exempt organizations be computed separately for each trade or business activity, exclude from the gross income of charitable volunteers reimbursement of expenses for the use of a passenger vehicle for the benefit of a charitable organization, and allow the tax credit for employer-paid family and medical leave for nonprofit employers. The bill also increases the corporate income tax rate from 21% to 21.06% (as an offset to the cost of this bill).</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
