<amendment session="116" chamber="h" number="596" updated="2019-08-16T10:13:10Z">
  <amends type="h" number="582" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2019-07-18T11:34:03-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000171"/>
  <offered datetime="2019-07-18"/>
  <description>Amendment requires the Government Accountability Office, to submit a report to Congress on the economic and employment impacts of the four minimum wage increases in the bill to be prepared after the second wage increase and before the third wage increase. Also, the amendment requires Congress to assess the report's findings and to take any appropriate legislative action, including action to delay or otherwise modify the next scheduled wage increases.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in Part B of House Report 116-155 to require the Government Accountability Office, in consultation with specified experts, to submit a report to Congress on the economic and employment impacts (nationally, regionally, and locally) of the four minimum wage increases in the bill (standard, tipped minimum, youth, and 14(C)) with the report to be prepared after the second wage increase and before the third wage increase. Also, the amendment requires Congress to assess the reports findings and to take any appropriate legislative action, including action to delay or otherwise modify the next scheduled wage increases.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2019-07-18T11:34:03-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="494">
      <text>On agreeing to the O'Halleran amendment (A002) Agreed to by recorded vote: 248 - 181 (Roll no. 494).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-07-18T11:01:16-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A002) and on the bill pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-18T10:49:15-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. O'Halleran.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7123-7126" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7123-7124" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-18"/>
    <action datetime="2019-07-18T10:49:15-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. O'Halleran.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-18T11:34:03-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to by House: On agreeing to the O'Halleran amendment (A002) Agreed to by recorded vote: 248 - 181 (Roll no. 494).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-18">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-18T11:34:03-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the O'Halleran amendment (A002) Agreed to by recorded vote: 248 - 181 (Roll no. 494).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-18T11:34:03-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
