<bill session="116" type="s" number="538" updated="2019-03-28T04:42:25Z">
  <state datetime="2019-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Investing in American Workers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Investing in American Workers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a credit for employer-provided worker training.</title>
    <title type="display">Investing in American Workers Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000805"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2019-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2019-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-02-25T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Investing in American Workers Act 

This bill allows a business-related tax credit for employers who increase worker training expenditures.

The credit is equal to 20% of the excess of (1) the qualified training expenditures for the year, over (2) the average of the adjusted qualified training expenditures for the three previous years. If the employer had no qualified training expenditures in any one of the three previous years, the credit is equal to 10% of the adjusted qualified training expenditures for the year.

The credit applies to expenditures for the training of non-highly compensated employees (annual compensation does not exceed $82,000). The training must result in the attainment of a recognized postsecondary credential and be provided through

 an apprenticeship program; a program of training services that is included on a list of eligible training providers that states are required to maintain under the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act; a program that is conducted by an area career and technical education school, a community college, or a labor organization; or a program that is sponsored and administered by an employer, industry trade association, industry or sector partnership, or labor organization. Certain small businesses and tax-exempt organizations may apply the credit against payroll taxes, subject to specified limits and requirements. Eligible small businesses may also apply the credit against the alternative minimum tax.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
