<bill session="116" type="s" number="1156" updated="2019-09-12T11:12:37Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to require the Secretary of each military department to develop resilience plans for installations of the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">READINESS Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">READINESS Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Requiring Every American Defense Installation to Nullify Environmental Stresses for Security Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Requiring Every American Defense Installation to Nullify Environmental Stresses for Security Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Requiring Every American Defense Installation to Nullify Environmental Stresses for Security Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2019-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2019-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2019-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2019-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1790"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-04-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Requiring Every American Defense Installation to Nullify Environmental Stresses for Security Act of 2019 or the READINESS Act of 2019

This bill requires the Department of Defense to ensure the readiness of the Armed Forces through a program of military installation resilience plans. These plans, which may include state-owned National Guard facilities, shall contain the following elements, as appropriate:

 an assessment of current risks and threats, such as changes in environmental conditions, and future risks and threats&#8212;based upon authoritative projections of changing environmental conditions&#8212;to the resilience of a major installation considered in a master plan during a 50-year lifespan; a description of vulnerable assets or infrastructure located on the installation as well as critical community infrastructure and resources outside of the installation; and a description of measures to mitigate threats to the resilience of an installation and its mission, associated costs of the measures, and agreements that will aid the resilience of the installation and vulnerable community infrastructure and resources.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
