<bill session="116" type="hj" number="28" updated="2019-10-24T18:39:08Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-25">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making further continuing appropriations for fiscal year 2019, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short">Further Additional Continuing Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Further Additional Continuing Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Further Additional Continuing Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Further Additional Continuing Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Further Additional Continuing Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Further Additional Continuing Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Further Additional Continuing Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Further Additional Continuing Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000480"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-16T18:05:18-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 52 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 28. The resolution provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 28 under a closed rule with one motion to recommit. Also, the resolution provides that it shall be in order at any time through the legislative day of January 25, 2019, for the Speaker to entertain motions to suspend the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-17T10:32:50-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 52 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-17T10:44:20-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 52.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H689-692" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-17T10:44:25-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 28. The resolution provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 28 under a closed rule with one motion to recommit. Also, the resolution provides that it shall be in order at any time through the legislative day of January 25, 2019, for the Speaker to entertain motions to suspend the rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-17T10:44:52-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.J. Res. 28.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-17T11:17:13-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-17T11:17:23-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Granger moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H692" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-17T11:17:34-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Granger motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment striking the date February 28, 2019 and inserting January 15, 2019.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-17T11:21:43-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-17T11:22:25-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Granger motion to recommit with instructions, the Chair put the question on the motion to recommit and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Granger demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-17T12:42:44-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H698-699" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-17T12:51:25-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 195 - 222 (Roll no. 43).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2019-01-17T12:51:26-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H689" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-01-17T12:51:29-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-17T13:52:20-05:00">
      <text>VITIATION OF EARLIER PROCEEDINGS - Mr. Hoyer asked unanimous consent to vacate proceedings by which House Joint Resolution 28 was passed, and the motion to reconsider laid upon the table, to the end that the Chair put the question on passage of House Joint Resolution 28 de novo, and further that if a recorded vote or the yeas and nays are ordered on the question of passage of House Joint Resolution 28, further proceedings may be postponed through the legislative day of January 23, 2019, as though under clause 8 of rule 20. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-17T13:53:20-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - Pursuant to the order of the House of January 17, 2019, the Chair put the question on passage of H.J.Res. 28 and by voice vote announced that the ayes prevailed. Mr. Scalise demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of passage through the legislative day of January 23, 2019.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-23T13:20:38-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1022-1023" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="46" datetime="2019-01-23T13:45:43-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 229 - 184 (Roll no. 46).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-01-23T13:45:44-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-25">
      <text>The joint resolution was considered read the second time.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-25">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S683-684" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="2019-01-25" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-01-25">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-25T18:57:50-05:00">
      <text>Mrs. Lowey asked unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table, with the Senate amendment thereto, and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1215-1216" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="without objection" type="pingpong" datetime="2019-01-25T18:58:36-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1215-1216" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-01-25T18:58:40-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2019-01-25">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2019-01-25" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="116-5" type="public" datetime="2019-01-25">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 116-5.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hj" session="116" relation="unknown" number="45"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="116" relation="procedurally-related" number="52"/>
    <bill type="hj" session="116" relation="unknown" number="27"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s54"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2019-01-26T04:59:58Z" status="Public Law">Further Additional Continuing Appropriations Act, 2019 

(Sec. 101) This joint resolution provides continuing FY2019 appropriations to several federal agencies through the earlier of February 15, 2019, or the enactment of the applicable appropriations legislation.

It is known as a continuing resolution (CR) and ends the partial government shutdown that began after the existing CR expired on December 21, 2018, because seven of the remaining FY2019 appropriations bills have not been enacted.

 (Five of the FY2019 appropriations bills were enacted last year, including

 the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2019; the Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2019; the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2019; the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2019; and the Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2019.) The CR also

 makes appropriations available, pursuant to a requirement under current law, to compensate employees furloughed as a result of any lapse in appropriations that began on or about December 22, 2018; ratifies and approves certain obligations incurred in anticipation of the appropriations made and the authority granted by this joint resolution; reimburses or compensates certain states, federal grantees, and furloughed state employees for the lapse in appropriations; and delays the release of required sequestration reports and orders by the Congressional Budget Office and the Office of Management and Budget. Additionally, the CR extends through February 15, 2019, several programs and authorities, including

 the authority for the Department of Health and Human Services Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority to withhold from public disclosure certain technical data or scientific information that reveals vulnerabilities of existing medical or public health defenses against biological, chemical, nuclear, or radiological threats; an exemption from antitrust laws for meetings and consultations to discuss the development of certain vaccines and drugs related to public health threats such as bioterrorism, pandemics, or epidemics; the Violence Against Women Act; the authority for the Environmental Protection Agency to collect and spend certain fees related to pesticides; and several authorities related to immigration. (Sec. 102) This section specifies that the time period covered by the Continuing Appropriations Act, 2019 includes the lapse in appropriations that began on or about December 22, 2018.

(Sec. 103) This section specifies that the requirement under current law to compensate employees furloughed as a result of a lapse in appropriations is subject to the enactment of appropriations legislation ending the lapse.

(Sec. 104) This section requires any debits on the scorecard maintained under the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010 (PAYGO Act) for 2019 to be transferred to the 2020 scorecard.

(The PAYGO Act prohibits direct spending and revenue legislation from increasing the budget deficit. PAYGO scorecards are used to enforce the requirements and determine whether a sequestration order implementing spending cuts is necessary.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
