<bill session="116" type="s" number="1828" updated="2019-08-03T07:56:17Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to clarify Federal law with respect to reporting certain positive consumer credit information to consumer reporting agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Credit Access and Inclusion Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Credit Access and Inclusion Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Credit Access and Inclusion Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2019-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000300" joined="2019-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2019-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2019-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2019-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2019-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-06-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Credit Access and Inclusion Act of 2019

This bill allows for the reporting of certain positive consumer-credit information to consumer reporting agencies. Specifically, a person or the Department of Housing and Urban Development may report information related to&#160;a consumer's performance&#160;in making payments either under a lease agreement for a dwelling or pursuant to a contract for a utility or telecommunications service. However, information about a consumer's usage of any utility or telecommunications service may be reported only to the extent that the information relates to payment by the consumer for such service or other terms of the provision of that service. Furthermore, an energy-utility firm may not report a consumer's outstanding balance as late if the firm and the consumer have entered into a payment plan and the consumer is meeting the obligations of that plan.

Specified provisions that&#160;establish&#160;civil liability&#160;with respect to&#160;furnishers of information to consumer reporting agencies shall not apply to any violation of the bill.

The Government Accountability Office must report on the consumer impact of such reporting.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
