<bill session="116" type="h" number="4117" updated="2019-09-18T16:45:16Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reduce the disadvantages of individual retirement plans with respect to employer-sponsored retirement plans by helping taxpayers comply with laws affecting individual retirement plans, by providing for reduced penalties under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for certain self-corrections with respect to such laws, and by expanding the Employee Plans Compliance Resolution System to cover certain errors under individual retirement plans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IRA Preservation Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IRA Preservation Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">IRA Preservation Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000188"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000376" joined="2019-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1431"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-07-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">IRA Preservation Act of 2019

This bill modifies requirements for individual retirement accounts (IRAs). It requires the Department of the Treasury to make available to the public an overview of the laws and regulations related to IRAs and examples of common IRA errors and how to avoid them.

The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to (1) reduce penalties for taxpayers who voluntarily correct certain IRA errors, including excess contributions and failures to take required minimum distributions; (2) eliminate the 10% additional tax on early distributions that are attributable to withdrawal of interest or other income earned on excess contributions to an IRA; (3) repeal the tax disqualification penalty (loss of tax-exempt status) for accounts where employees engage in certain prohibited transactions; and (4) revise the statute of limitations for collecting certain taxes in connection with an IRA.

Treasury must expand the Employee Plans Compliance Resolution System to allow trustees, custodians, and issuers of IRAs to address inadvertent failures for which an IRA owner was not at fault.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
