<bill session="116" type="s" number="1401" updated="2019-10-31T10:03:07Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish eligibility requirements for education support professionals under the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ESP Family Leave Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ESP Family Leave Act</title>
    <title type="display">ESP Family Leave Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000622"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2019-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2019-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2019-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-05-09T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">ESP Family Leave Act

This bill provides that employees who are education support professionals will be considered as meeting the hours of service requirements to become eligible for family or medical leave under the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993, if they have worked a number of hours equal to not less than 60% of the total monthly hours expected for their job descriptions and duties, as assigned for the previous school year.

The bill defines an "education support professional" as an employee within a public school or public institution of higher education which may include: (1) paraeducators who provide instructional and noninstructional support; (2) secretarial, clerical, and administrative support staff; (3) custodians and maintenance service workers who provide building and grounds maintenance and repair; (4) skilled trade workers who provide services in schools, e.g., electricians, carpenters, and machinery operators; (5) workers who provide food service; (6) workers who provide school transportation and delivery services; (7) computer audiovisual, and language technical support staff; (8) security staff; (9) nursing, health, and therapy support staff; and (10) other staff that may serve public education students.

The Department of Labor may provide a method for calculating leave under the Act for education support professionals.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
