<bill session="116" type="s" number="1143" updated="2019-09-20T11:30:22Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to improve testing and inspections for lead on military installations, in Department of Defense housing and schools, and in military dependent children, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Get the Lead Out of Military Housing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Get the Lead Out of Military Housing Act</title>
    <title type="display">Get the Lead Out of Military Housing Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000622"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2019-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1790"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2257"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2500"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2255"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2254"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2252"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Blood and blood diseases"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee performance"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-04-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Get the Lead Out of Military Housing Act

This bill addresses the exposure of personnel and dependents to lead in military facilities. It requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to establish a policy under which a certified lead-based paint inspector or risk assessor may access a military installation in order to conduct lead testing. Penalties are imposed for failure to provide testing results to relevant government agencies or obstruction of the testing.

 DOD shall test for, and mitigate, the presence of lead-based paint and lead in drinking water in schools that are (1) owned or operated by the Department of Defense Education Activity, or (2) providing educational programs pursuant to agreements to provide education to military dependents.

DOD may not discourage inspection of housing for presence of lead-based paint or sources of lead.

 The bill expands requirements for lead-level testing or screening as part of well-baby care under the TRICARE program. It prescribes testing for the level of lead in the blood at the ages of both 12 and 24 months for children at elevated risk of lead exposure. The Government Accountability Office shall study the effectiveness of such screening, testing, and treatment for lead exposure and poisoning. DOD shall maintain records concerning the year housing for military personnel was built, and members must provide notice of when their residence was built as a condition of receiving a housing allowance.

 The military departments shall certify whether housing complies with requirements of the Toxic Substances Control Act regarding lead-based paint hazards at federal facilities. Political appointees in military departments that have failed to meet the certification requirements may not receive bonus pay.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
