<bill session="116" type="s" number="137" updated="2019-05-24T05:27:44Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to increase the credit for employers establishing workplace child care facilities, to increase the child care credit to encourage greater use of quality child care services, to provide incentives for students to earn child care-related degrees and to work in child care facilities, and to increase the exclusion for employer-provided dependent care assistance.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Right Start Child Care and Education Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Right Start Child Care and Education Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Right Start Child Care and Education Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2019-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2019-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2019-01-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-16T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Right Start Child Care and Education Act of 2019

This bill expands the tax credits and exclusions that are available for child care expenses. The bill includes provisions that

 increase the tax credit for employer-provided child care facilities; increase the household and dependent care tax credit and make the credit refundable; allow a new $2,000 annual tax credit for three years for child care providers who hold a bachelor's degree in early childhood education, child care, or a related degree and who provide at least 1,200 hours of child care services in a taxable year; and increase the tax exclusion for employer-provided dependent care assistance.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
