<bill session="116" type="h" number="4793" updated="2019-11-01T15:15:30Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-10-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish a stewardship fee on the production and importation of opioid pain relievers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Budgeting for Opioid Addiction Treatment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Budgeting for Opioid Addiction Treatment Act</title>
    <title type="display">Budgeting for Opioid Addiction Treatment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000188"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000557" joined="2019-10-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="identical" number="425"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-10-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Budgeting for Opioid Addiction Treatment Act 

This bill imposes a one cent per milligram fee on the sale of active opioids by the manufacturer, producer, or importer. The fee excludes prescription drugs used exclusively for the treatment of opioid addiction as part of a medically assisted treatment effort.

The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must establish a program to provide rebates or discounts to cancer and hospice patients to ensure that they do not pay the fee.

 Any increase in federal revenues from the fee after rebates and discounts are subtracted must be distributed to states under the Substance Abuse Prevention and Treatment Block Grant program. The states must use the funds exclusively for substance abuse (including opioid abuse) efforts in the states, including (1) specified treatment programs, and (2) the recruitment and training of substance use disorder professionals to work in rural and medically underserved communities.

HHS must report to Congress on the impact of this bill on the retail cost of opioids and patient access to opioid medication, the effectiveness of the discount or rebate for cancer and hospice patients, how the funds are being used to improve substance abuse treatment efforts, and suggestions for improving access to opioids for cancer and hospice patients and substance abuse treatment efforts.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
