<bill session="116" type="s" number="1498" updated="2019-08-16T10:41:50Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Defense to enhance the readiness of the Department of Defense to challenges relating to climate change and to improve the energy and resource efficiency of the Department, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Defense Climate Resiliency and Readiness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Defense Climate Resiliency and Readiness Act</title>
    <title type="display">Department of Defense Climate Resiliency and Readiness Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2019-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2019-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="identical" number="2759"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Lighting, heating, cooling"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Materials"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military command and structure"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-05-15T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Department of Defense Climate Resiliency and Readiness Act

 This bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to provide a strategy to achieve aggregate net zero energy by non-operational sources by no later than December 31, 2029. The term "net zero energy" means a reduction in overall energy use, maximized energy efficiency, implementation of energy recovery and cogeneration capabilities, and an offset of the remaining demand for energy with production of energy from onsite renewable energy sources.

Annual DOD budget submissions must include an item for climate-related adaptation and mitigation, as well as an estimate of adverse impacts to readiness and costs.

 Regarding DOD procurement (1) contracts must contain an estimate of total projected energy consumption and a statement concerning renewable energy and energy efficiency investments; (2) contractors must evaluate climate change risks, including by describing relevant corporate governance processes; and (3) a contractor will be assessed a fee if it consumes more energy than it produces.

DOD must develop a vulnerability and risk assessment tool to measure risks to systems, installations, and operational capabilities.

 Strategic decisions regarding an installation must consider risks associated with climate change, and DOD shall incorporate these into the National Defense Strategy, the National Military Strategy, and operational plans.

DOD shall conduct a research and development program concerning hybrid microgrid systems and electric grid energy storage.

With respect to base realignment and closure activities, DOD shall consider current and potential vulnerabilities to military installations and operations resulting from climate change and their resilience.

 The bill establishes the position of Assistant Secretary of Defense of Energy and Climate Resiliency.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
