<bill session="116" type="h" number="69" updated="2019-07-30T13:05:15Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to allow States, in accordance with State law, to let Federal funds for the education of disadvantaged children follow low-income children to the public school, charter school, accredited private school, or supplemental educational service program they attend, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ending Common Core and Expanding School Choice Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ending Common Core and Expanding School Choice Act</title>
    <title type="display">Ending Common Core and Expanding School Choice Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001302"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2019-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Ending Common Core and Expanding School Choice Act

This bill&#160;&#160;modifies requirements&#160;related to federal&#160;education funding for disadvantaged children. Specifically, the bill&#160; (1)&#160;eliminates the standards, assessments, and academic accountability requirements for state and local educational agencies that receive federal funds for the education of disadvantaged children, (2) requires such funds to be allocated based on the number of children residing in each state who are living in poverty, and (3) allows educational agencies to distribute per-pupil amounts from such funds to parents for qualified elementary and secondary education expenses.

The bill prohibits federal officers or employees from mandating academic standards, assessments, curricula, or accountability systems.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
