<bill session="116" type="h" number="173" updated="2019-07-31T07:32:42Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Natural Gas Act to bolster fairness and transparency in consideration of interstate natural gas pipelines, to provide for greater public input opportunities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pipeline Fairness and Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pipeline Fairness and Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="display">Pipeline Fairness and Transparency Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000568"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001118" joined="2019-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy" code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Pipeline Fairness and Transparency Act

This bill addresses eminent domain, environmental review for interstate natural gas pipeline projects, and the visual impacts of natural gas pipeline projects on national scenic trails.

The bill revises the process for environmental reviews of natural gas projects. The Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)must prepare a supplement to a draft or final environmental impact statement if (1)FERC makes a substantial change in the proposed action that is relevant to environmental concerns, or (2) there are significant new circumstances relevant to environmental concerns.FERC must also hold public meetings in each county (or equivalent subdivision) in which a project is to be located.

Additionally, in an environmental impact statement, an evaluation of the visual impacts of a project on a national scenic trail must include a cumulative analysis of the visual impacts of the project and similar proposed projects.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
