<bill session="116" type="s" number="451" updated="2019-06-12T04:57:58Z">
  <state datetime="2019-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modernize the National Air Toxics Assessment, the Integrated Risk Information System, and the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expanding Transparency of Information and Safeguarding Toxics (EtO is Toxic) Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expanding Transparency of Information and Safeguarding Toxics (EtO is Toxic) Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Expanding Transparency of Information and Safeguarding Toxics (EtO is Toxic) Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000622"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2019-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1165"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-02-12T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Expanding Transparency of Information and Safeguarding Toxics (EtO is Toxic) Act of 2019

This bill updates requirements for chemicals that pose an adverse public health risk. Specifically, the bill requires the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to publish an updated National Air Toxics Assessment once every two years. The assessment uses emissions data to estimate health risks from toxic air pollutants.

The bill also requires the EPA to use data from its Integrated Risk Information System when conducting rulemaking with respect to chemicals that have been assessed in the system. For chemicals that are found to pose an adverse health risk, the EPA shall identify and do additional review on facilities that are significant sources of the chemical to determine whether the facility poses an adverse public health risk.

Under the bill, chemicals identified as carcinogenic in the system must have a toxic chemical release form completed by the owner or operator of a facility.

The bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to consult with appropriate EPA offices regarding the future schedule of assessments of chemicals to be conducted under the system, the results or existing assessments, and concerns that may merit additional review. HHS must also administer personal exposure tests for chemicals that pose a new adverse public health risk to vulnerable populations, such as children. HHS must establish a Community Outreach Division to communicate risk assessments to affected communities.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
