<bill session="116" type="h" number="1909" updated="2019-07-30T13:27:36Z">
  <state datetime="2019-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Securities and Exchange Commission to revise rules relating to general solicitation or general advertising to allow for presentations or other communication made by or on behalf of an issuer at certain events, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HALOS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HALOS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Angels Lead Our Startups Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Angels Lead Our Startups Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">HALOS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000266"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001204" joined="2019-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000600" joined="2019-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001190" joined="2019-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1063"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-03-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Helping Angels Lead Our Startups Act of 2019 or the HALOS Act

This bill directs the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to revise Regulation D, which exempts certain offerings from SEC registration requirements but prohibits general solicitation or general advertising with respect to such offerings. Specifically, this prohibition shall not apply to events with specified kinds of sponsors&#8212;including "angel investor groups" unconnected to broker-dealers or investment advisers&#8212;where presentations or communications are made by or on behalf of an issuer, if

 the advertising does not refer to any specific offering of securities by the issuer; the sponsor does not provide investment recommendation or advice to attendees, engage in investment negotiations with attendees, charge certain fees, or receive certain compensation; and no specific information regarding a securities offering is communicated beyond&#160;the type and amount of securities being offered, the amount of securities already subscribed for, and the intended use of proceeds from the offering.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
