<bill session="116" type="s" number="2170" updated="2019-10-05T16:57:33Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012 to make reforms to flood mapping programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MEMA Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MEMA Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Municipality Empowerment Mapping Achievement Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Municipality Empowerment Mapping Achievement Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">MEMA Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000437"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3872"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-07-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Municipality Empowerment Mapping Achievement Act of 2019 or the MEMA Act of 2019

This bill requires the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to publish National Flood Insurance Program (NFIP) rate maps for the entire United States (current law directs the mapping of certain risk areas). In developing these rate maps, FEMA must use the most current remote sensing technology.

In coordination with the Technical Mapping Advisory Council, FEMA must establish a digital database to display the flood hazard risks of buildings in NFIP. The database must contain specified information about each property, including a certification of the building's elevation. FEMA must provide a one-time premium credit for the purchase of an elevation certificate by a policyholder.

The bill allows reimbursement to local governments that assist FEMA in developing flood risk zone data.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
