<bill session="116" type="h" number="1098" updated="2019-09-26T18:30:24Z">
  <state datetime="2019-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To gather information about the illicit production of illicit fentanyl in foreign countries and to withhold bilateral assistance from countries that do not have emergency scheduling procedures for new illicit drugs, cannot prosecute criminals for the manufacture or distribution of controlled substance analogues, or do not require the registration of tableting machines and encapsulating machines.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Blocking Deadly Fentanyl Imports Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Blocking Deadly Fentanyl Imports Act</title>
    <title type="display">Blocking Deadly Fentanyl Imports Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2019-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2019-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2019-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000395" joined="2019-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000376" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000588" joined="2019-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001187" joined="2019-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001204" joined="2019-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000605" joined="2019-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000610" joined="2019-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001199" joined="2019-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000827" joined="2019-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="identical" number="400"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-02-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Blocking Deadly Fentanyl Imports Act

This bill expands reporting requirements related to foreign countries that produce illicit fentanyl and limits assistance to countries that fail to take various actions to combat illegal drug production and trafficking.

The President's annual report to Congress on U.S. strategy for controlling international narcotics shall include a section that identifies the countries that are the most significant sources of illicit fentanyl, fentanyl analogues, and precursor chemicals used for producing fentanyl. The report shall also describe the extent to which&#160;such a country has cooperated with U.S. efforts to prevent exports of such substances into the United States.

The United States shall withhold 50% of the foreign assistance allocated to each identified country for the fiscal year. The Department of the Treasury shall also direct U.S. Executive Directors in each multilateral development bank to vote against making loans or allocating funds to such countries. Both restrictions may be waived if the President certifies that the country has cooperated fully with U.S. anti-drug trafficking efforts or if vital U.S. national interests necessitate&#160;such a waiver.

The bill also directs the President to identify countries that (1) have not adopted various procedures for countering narcotics production and distribution, or (2)&#160;are incapable of prosecuting individuals that manufacture or distribute new types of drugs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
