<bill session="116" type="h" number="2021" updated="2019-09-27T15:56:19Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-03">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 and to establish a congressional budget for fiscal year 2020.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Investing for the People Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Investing for the People Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Investing for the People Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Investing for the People Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Investing for the People Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000480" joined="2019-04-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-04-03" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 19 - 17.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-04-05">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Budget. H. Rept. 116-35, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-05">
      <text>Committee on Rules discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-04-05" calendar="Union" number="16">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 16.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-04-09T15:03:25-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 294 passed House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3877"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="116" relation="procedurally-related" number="294"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="116" relation="unknown" number="293"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="House Committee on the Budget"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-04-05T13:33:31Z" status="Reported to House, Part I">Investing for the People Act of 2019 

This bill increases discretionary spending limits, modifies the procedures for enforcing the limits, and establishes budget enforcement procedures in the House of Representatives for FY2020.

The bill increases both the defense and nondefense discretionary spending limits for FY2020 and FY2021. It also modifies the procedures for enforcing the spending limits to

 limit adjustments for funding designated for Overseas Contingency Operations/ Global War on Terrorism, allow specified adjustments for Internal Revenue Service enforcement activities and the 2020 Census, and modify the sequestration process. The chairman of the House Budget Committee must submit for publication in the Congressional Record committee allocations, aggregate spending levels, and aggregate revenue levels that are consistent with the discretionary spending limits and requirements specified in this bill. For budget enforcement purposes, the allocations and levels shall apply in the House of Representatives as if they were included in a FY2020 budget resolution.

The chairman may adjust the allocations and levels to reflect (1) changes in the Congressional Budget Office baseline, or (2) legislation that does not increase the deficit over FY2020-FY2024 or FY2020-FY2029.

The bill prohibits advance appropriations, except for programs, activities, or accounts identified in lists submitted by the chairman of the House Budget Committee for publication in the Congressional Record. The identified accounts are subject to aggregate limits specified in the bill. (An advance appropriation is any new discretionary budget authority provided in appropriations legislation for FY2020 that first becomes available after FY2020.)</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-35</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
