<bill session="116" type="h" number="2886" updated="2019-10-31T07:13:25Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to include a single comprehensive disability examination as part of the required Department of Defense physical examination for separating members of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Affairs Transfer of Information and Sharing of Disability Examination Procedures With DOD Doctors Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Affairs Transfer of Information and Sharing of Disability Examination Procedures With DOD Doctors Act</title>
    <title type="display">Veterans Affairs Transfer of Information and Sharing of Disability Examination Procedures With DOD Doctors Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000804"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Military Personnel" code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-05-21T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans Affairs Transfer of Information and Sharing of Disability Examination Procedures With DOD Doctors Act

This bill addresses the sharing of medical information and disability examination procedures between the Departments of Defense (DOD) and Veterans Affairs (VA). It requires that if a member of the Armed Forces who is required to receive a physical examination upon separation from active duty and has or is believed to have a medical condition that may make the member eligible for veterans' disability compensation and benefits, the examination must be performed by a VA-certified health care provider.

If the condition is discovered during the physical examination and the examining health care provider is not VA-certified, the examination must be completed by a VA-certified provider.

An eligibility determination made as part of such an examination shall be binding on the VA and be used as the basis for assigning the member's disability rating.

The VA and DOD shall jointly establish a system to share data and maintain the medical and personnel records of Armed Forces members and veterans.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
