<bill session="116" type="s" number="780" updated="2019-07-24T17:45:11Z">
  <state datetime="2019-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for current year inclusion of net CFC tested income, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Tax Breaks for Outsourcing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Tax Breaks for Outsourcing Act</title>
    <title type="display">No Tax Breaks for Outsourcing Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000802"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2019-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2140"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="identical" number="1711"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-03-13T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">No Tax Breaks for Outsourcing Act 

This bill modifies the tax treatment of the foreign source income of domestic corporations. The bill includes provisions that

 eliminate an exemption for certain returns from tangible investments made overseas, eliminate deductions for a domestic corporation's foreign-derived intangible income and global intangible low-taxed income, repeal a provision that excludes foreign oil and gas extraction income from the tested income of a controlled foreign corporation, limit the tax deduction for the interest expenses of a U.S. corporation that is a member of a financial reporting group (i.e., a group that prepares consolidated financial statements according to generally accepted accounting principles or international financial reporting standards), modify the rules for the taxation of inverted corporations (U.S. corporations that acquire foreign companies to reincorporate in a foreign jurisdiction with income tax rates lower than the United States), and treat certain foreign corporations managed and controlled primarily in the United States as domestic corporations for tax purposes.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
