<bill session="116" type="h" number="1112" updated="2019-10-02T13:15:21Z">
  <state datetime="2019-02-28T12:02:30-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-02-28T12:02:30-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 44 of title 18, United States Code, to strengthen the background check procedures to be followed before a Federal firearms licensee may transfer a firearm to a person who is not such a licensee.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Enhanced Background Checks Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Enhanced Background Checks Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Enhanced Background Checks Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Enhanced Background Checks Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhanced Background Checks Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhanced Background Checks Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Enhanced Background Checks Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000537"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2019-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001122" joined="2019-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2019-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000627" joined="2019-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2019-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2019-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000592" joined="2019-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001203" joined="2019-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000172" joined="2019-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000173" joined="2019-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2019-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000616" joined="2019-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001190" joined="2019-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2019-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001201" joined="2019-02-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-02-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-02-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 21 - 14.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-02-22">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 116-12.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-02-22" calendar="Union" number="4">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 4.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-02-25T19:44:23-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 145 Reported to House. Provides for one hour of debate on each measure. Only those amendments printed in the report shall be in order and the previous question shall be considered ordered without intervening motions except one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-26T15:11:43-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 145 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-28T09:14:53-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 145.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2277-2293" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-28T09:14:58-05:00">
      <text>Provides for one hour of debate on each measure. Only those amendments printed in the report shall be in order and the previous question shall be considered ordered without intervening motions except one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-28T09:15:02-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 145 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-28T09:15:03-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Lauren Underwood to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-28T09:15:56-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1112.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-28T10:13:36-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 145, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rice (SC) amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-28T10:19:38-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 145, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Schneider amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-28T10:25:06-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Schneider amendment No. 2, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Nadler demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-28T10:26:29-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 145, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Levin (MI) amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-28T10:31:49-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 145, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Porter amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-28T10:38:16-05:00">
      <text>DEABTE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 145, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Van Drew amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-28T10:46:20-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Van Drew amendment No. 5, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Collins (GA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-28T11:28:08-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1112.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-28T11:29:34-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-28T11:31:11-05:00">
      <text>Mrs. Lesko moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2291" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-28T11:31:34-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lesko motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to insert new text on cases in which the transferee is a victim of a crime of domestic violence.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-28T11:45:18-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-28T11:53:41-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 194 - 232 (Roll no. 102).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="103" datetime="2019-02-28T12:02:30-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 228 - 198 (Roll no. 103).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2284" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-02-28T12:02:32-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-03-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="30">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 30.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="116" relation="procedurally-related" number="145"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h53"/>
    <amendment number="h52"/>
    <amendment number="h51"/>
    <amendment number="h50"/>
    <amendment number="h49"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2019-02-22T13:47:32Z" status="Reported to House">Enhanced Background Checks Act of 2019

This bill revises background check requirements applicable to proposed firearm transfers from a federal firearms licensee (e.g., a licensed gun dealer) to an unlicensed person.

Additionally, the bill modifies statutory references with respect to a particular category of prohibited persons (i.e., persons barred from receiving or possessing a firearm). Specifically, it replaces references to persons "adjudicated as a mental defective" with persons "adjudicated with mental illness, severe developmental disability, or severe emotional instability."</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-12</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
