<bill session="116" type="h" number="3368" updated="2019-09-27T07:16:53Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a tax credit for on-site apprenticeship programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Apprenticeship and Jobs Training Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Apprenticeship and Jobs Training Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Apprenticeship and Jobs Training Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001156"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2019-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2019-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects/>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-06-19T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Apprenticeship and Jobs Training Act of 2019

This bill allows employers a business-related tax credit for up to $5,000 for the training of a qualified individual in a qualified apprenticeship program or multi-employer apprenticeship program.

A "qualified individual" is an individual who (1) is an apprentice participating in a&#160;qualified apprenticeship program or multi-employer apprenticeship program, (2)&#160;has been employed in either program for a period of at least seven months that ends within the taxable year, and (3) is not a highly compensated employee or a seasonal worker.

A "qualified apprenticeship program" is a program that &#160;(1) provides qualified individuals with on-the-job training and instruction for a qualified occupation (i.e., a skilled trade occupation in a high-demand mechanical, technical, health care, or technology field); (2) is registered with the Office of Apprenticeship of the Department of Labor or a state apprenticeship agency recognized by the office; and (3) maintains records relating to the qualified individual.

A "qualified multi-employer apprenticeship program" is a program in which multiple employers are required to contribute and that is maintained pursuant to one or more collective bargaining agreements.

The bill also allows certain distributions, without penalty, from&#160;retirement and pension plans to an employee who is serving as a mentor. A "mentor" is a working individual who (1) has attained age 55; (2) works reduced hours and engages in mentoring activities for at least 20% of such hours; and (3) is responsible for the training and education of employees or students in an area of expertise for which such individual has a professional credential, certificate, or degree.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
