<amendment session="116" chamber="h" number="288" updated="2019-10-29T15:46:00Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2740" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2019-06-12T23:37:56-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000454"/>
  <offered datetime="2019-06-12"/>
  <description>Amendment increases and decreases funding by $1 for the Bureau of Labor Statistics for the purpose of instructing BLS to accept a wider and more forward-looking range of inputs into its range of projections for its workforce of the future.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 22 printed in Part B of House Report 116-109 to increase and decrease $1 from the Bureau of Labor Statistics for the purpose of instructing BLS to accept a wider and more forward-looking range of inputs into its range of projections for its workforce of the future and should conduct the Contingent Worker and Alternative Work Arrangement Supplement (CWS) to the Current Population Survey. BLS should submit to Congress an estimate of the resources it would need to make a range of forward-looking estimates, including consultation with those industries that are driving rapid technological change and those that will be affected by that change to account for the increasing rate of technological job displacement.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2019-06-12T23:37:56-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="272">
      <text>On agreeing to the Foster amendment (A022) Agreed to by recorded vote: 260 - 164 (Roll no. 272).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-06-12T19:47:37-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A022) offered by Mr. Foster.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4562, H4589" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4562" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-12"/>
    <action datetime="2019-06-12T23:37:56-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-12T23:37:56-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-12T23:37:56-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Foster amendment (A022) Agreed to by recorded vote: 260 - 164 (Roll no. 272).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-12T19:47:37-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A022) offered by Mr. Foster.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-12">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
