<bill session="116" type="h" number="2396" updated="2019-09-24T13:45:21Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the use of funds in the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund for the purposes for which the funds were collected and to ensure that funds credited to the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund are used to support navigation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Full Utilization of the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Full Utilization of the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund Act</title>
    <title type="display">Full Utilization of the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000191"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="identical" number="2440"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-04-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Full Utilization of the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund Act

This bill provides a discretionary spending limit adjustment for full utilization of the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund to ensure that funds are used to support navigation and maintain federally authorized harbors.

The bill makes certain amounts in the trust fund available, without appropriation, to pay

 100% of the eligible operations and maintenance costs of specified portions of the Saint Lawrence Seaway (a system of locks, canals, and channels in Canada and the United States that permits oceangoing vessels to travel from the Atlantic Ocean to the Great Lakes); and up to 100% of the eligible operations and maintenance costs assigned to commercial navigation of all U.S. harbors and inland harbors. The discretionary spending adjustment in a given fiscal year may not exceed the amount within the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund on the last day of the fiscal year that is two years prior to such fiscal year.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
