<bill session="116" type="s" number="1106" updated="2019-06-04T04:27:29Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow for a credit against tax for rent paid on the personal residence of the taxpayer.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rent Relief Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rent Relief Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Rent Relief Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2019-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2019-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2019-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="identical" number="2169"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-04-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Rent Relief Act of 2019

This bill allows a refundable tax credit for individuals who pay rent for a principal residence that exceeds 30% of the individual's gross income for the taxable year.

The amount of the credit ranges from 25% to 100% of the excess rent, depending on the gross income of the taxpayer. The credit is not available for taxpayers with gross income that exceeds $100,000 ($125,000 for a taxpayer whose principal residence is located in a high-cost area, as defined by the bill). Rent that exceeds 100% of the small area fair market rent (including the utility allowance) for the residence may not be taken into account for the purpose of determining the amount of the credit.

For individuals who reside in government-subsidized housing, the bill allows a credit equal to 1/12 of the rent paid by the taxpayer (and not subsidized under the program) during the year with respect to the residence.

The Department of the Treasury must establish a program for making advance payments of the credit on a monthly basis.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
