<bill session="116" type="s" number="2625" updated="2019-11-02T04:42:46Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-10-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-10-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the admission of a limited number of Kurdish Syrians and other Syrian partners as special immigrants, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Syrian Allies Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Syrian Allies Protection Act</title>
    <title type="display">Syrian Allies Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000805"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2019-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2019-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2019-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2019-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2019-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2019-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2019-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2019-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2019-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2019-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2019-10-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-10-17T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Syrian Allies Protection Act

This bill authorizes the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to provide certain Syrian nationals with special immigrant status.

To qualify, a Syrian national must (1) have worked directly with the Armed Forces in a role that was vital to the success of the U.S. military mission in Syria for at least six months during a specified time period, (2) have a favorable written recommendation from a general or flag officer in the chain of command of the unit that the alien was supporting, and (3) pass a background check. The spouse or child of a qualifying alien shall also qualify if accompanying the qualifying alien.

To receive special immigrant status, a qualified alien must apply to DHS and be otherwise eligible for an immigrant visa and admissible for permanent residence, except that an alien shall not be inadmissible on the grounds that the alien will likely become a public charge. Aliens granted special immigrant status under this bill shall qualify for benefits available to refugees for six months. Up to 250 principal aliens may receive special immigrant status each fiscal year under this bill.

For applicants whose lives are at risk while awaiting background checks, the Department of Defense shall implement a framework to temporarily resettle such applicants in a safe third country or grant them humanitarian parole.

DHS may provide lawful permanent resident status to an alien paroled or admitted as a nonimmigrant and who otherwise qualifies for special immigrant status under this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
