<bill session="116" type="s" number="647" updated="2019-10-25T04:57:20Z">
  <state datetime="2019-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to impose a tax on certain trading transactions.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wall Street Tax Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wall Street Tax Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Wall Street Tax Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2019-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="identical" number="1516"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-03-05T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Wall Street Tax Act of 2019

This bill imposes a 0.1% excise tax on certain financial transactions such as the purchase of stocks, bonds, and derivatives.

The tax applies to the purchase of a security if (1) such purchase occurs on, or is subject to the rules of, a qualified board or exchange located in the United States; or (2) the purchaser or seller is a U.S. person.

A "security" includes

 a share of stock in a corporation; a partnership or beneficial ownership interest in a partnership or trust; a note, bond, debenture, or other evidence of indebtedness; and derivatives that meet specified criteria. The tax applies to transactions with respect to a derivative if (1) the derivative is traded on, or is subject to the rules of, a qualified board or exchange located in the United States; or (2) any party with rights under the derivative is a U.S. person.

The bill exempts from such tax (1) initial issues of securities; and (2) any note, bond, debenture, or other evidence of indebtedness which is traded on or is subject to the rules of, a qualified board or exchange located in the United States, and has a fixed maturity of not more than 100 days.

The tax applies to transactions by a controlled foreign corporation and must be paid by its U.S. shareholders.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
