<bill session="116" type="h" number="267" updated="2019-07-30T13:07:03Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-10T16:16:44-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-01-10T16:16:44-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for the Department of Transportation, and Housing and Urban Development, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2019, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Department of Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Department of Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Department of Transportation Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Department of Transportation Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Department of Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Department of Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Department of Transportation Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Department of Transportation Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000523"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-08T19:39:10-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 28 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 264, H.R. 265, H.R. 266 and H.R. 267. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. The rule provides one hour of debate, orders the previous question, and allows one motion to commit on each bill. The rule waives the requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII for a two-thirds vote to consider a report from the Committee on Rules on the same day it is presented to the House with respect to any resolution reported through the legislative day of January 15, 2019, relating to a measure making or continuing appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2019.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-09T14:04:30-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 28 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-10T13:51:31-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 28.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H398-429" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-10T13:51:36-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 264, H.R. 265, H.R. 266 and H.R. 267. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. The rule provides one hour of debate, orders the previous question, and allows one motion to commit on each bill. The rule waives the requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII for a two-thirds vote to consider a report from the Committee on Rules on the same day it is presented to the House with respect to any resolution reported through the legislative day of January 15, 2019, relating to a measure making or continuing appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2019.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-10T13:52:13-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 267.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-10T14:48:09-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-10T14:48:46-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Diaz-Balart moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H438" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-10T14:49:19-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Diaz-Balart motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to increase the Public and Indian Housing Tenant-Based Rental Assistance account by $71 million and to decrease the Information Technology Fund account by a similar amount.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-10T14:54:39-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-10T14:55:09-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Diaz-Balart motion to recommit with instructions, the Chair put the question on the motion to recommit and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Diaz-Balart demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-10T15:42:30-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H437-438" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-10T16:07:13-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 193 - 228 (Roll no. 22).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="23" datetime="2019-01-10T16:16:44-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 244 - 180 (Roll no. 23).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H398-420" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-01-10T16:16:46-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hj" session="116" relation="unknown" number="31"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="116" relation="procedurally-related" number="28"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="21"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="648"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Access Board"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Maritime Commission"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing discrimination"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Interagency Council on Homelessness"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak)"/>
    <term name="National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB)"/>
    <term name="Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Saint Lawrence Seaway"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Surface Transportation Board"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-10T13:01:55Z" status="Passed House">Highlights

This bill provides FY2019 appropriations for the Department of Transportation (DOT), the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), and several related agencies.

The bill includes both discretionary and mandatory funding. The HUD budget is primarily discretionary spending, and most of the DOT budget is mandatory spending, in the form of contract authority from the Highway Trust Fund.

Full Summary

Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2019 

TITLE I--DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION

Department of Transportation Appropriations Act, 2019 

This title provides FY2019 appropriations for the Department of Transportation (DOT).

The title provides appropriations for the Office of the Secretary, including

 Salaries and Expenses; Research and Technology; National Infrastructure Investments (also known as BUILD grants); the National Surface Transportation and Innovative Finance Bureau; Financial Management Capital; Cyber Security Initiatives; the Office of Civil Rights; Transportation Planning, Research, and Development; the Working Capital Fund; the Minority Business Resource Center Program; Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization and Outreach; and Payments to Air Carriers. (Sec. 101) This section prohibits DOT from approving assessments or reimbursable agreements pertaining to funds appropriated to the modal administrations in this bill except for activities underway on the date of enactment, unless the reprogramming process has been completed.

(Sec. 102) This section requires DOT to (1) post on its website the schedule and agenda for all meetings of the Council on Credit and Finance, and (2) direct the council to record the decisions and actions of each meeting.

(Sec. 103) This section permits DOT to use the Working Capital Fund to provide payments in advance and accept subsequent reimbursements from all federal agencies for transit benefit distribution services that are necessary to carry out the federal transit pass transportation fringe benefit program.

DOT must maintain a reasonable operating reserve in the Working Capital Fund, to be expended in advance to provide uninterrupted transit benefits to government employees. The reserve may not exceed one month of benefits and may be used only for transit benefits.

The title provides appropriations to the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) for

 Operations; Facilities and Equipment; Research, Engineering, and Development; and Grants-In-Aid For Airports. Fund provided by this bill may not be used for

 new applicants for the second career training program, new unauthorized aviation user fees, or aeronautical charting and cartography activities through the Working Capital Fund. The title prohibits funds from being used to eliminate the Contract Weather Observers program at any airport.

The title permits funds received from specified public, private, and foreign sources for expenses incurred in the provision of FAA services to be credited to the FAA Operations appropriations account.

(Sec. 110) This section limits technical staff-years under the federally funded research and development center contract between the FAA and the Center for Advanced Aviation Systems Development.

(Sec. 111) This section prohibits the FAA from requiring airport sponsors to provide the FAA without cost building construction, maintenance, utilities and expenses, or space in sponsor-owned buildings for air traffic control, air navigation, or weather reporting. The prohibition does not apply to negotiations between the FAA and airport sponsors to achieve agreement on "below-market" rates for these items or to grant assurances that require airport sponsors to provide land without cost to the FAA for air traffic control facilities.

(Sec. 112) This section permits the FAA to reimburse amounts made available from certain fees to carry out the Essential Air Service program, which was established to ensure that small communities have a minimum level of air service.

(Sec. 113) This section permits amounts collected by the FAA for providing technical assistance to foreign aviation authorities to be credited to the Operations account.

(Sec. 114) This section prohibits the FAA from paying Sunday premium pay except if an individual worked on a Sunday.

(Sec. 115) This section prohibits the FAA from using funds provided by this bill to purchase a store gift card or gift certificate using a government-issued credit card.

(Sec. 116) This section prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for retention bonuses for FAA employees without prior approval of the Assistant Secretary for Administration of DOT.

(Sec. 117) This section requires the FAA, upon the request of an owner or operator, to block the display of the owner's or operator's aircraft registration number in the Aircraft Situational Display to Industry program.

(Sec. 118) This section prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to pay the salaries and expenses of more than eight political and presidential FAA appointees.

(Sec. 119) This section prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to increase fees for navigation products until the FAA provides Congress with a justification for all fees for aeronautical navigation products and explains how the fees are consistent with Executive Order 13642 (Making Open and Machine Readable the New Default for Government Information).

(Sec. 119A) This section requires the FAA to notify Congress prior to closing a regional operations center or reducing the services it provides.

(Sec. 119B) This section prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to change weight restrictions or prior permission rules at Teterboro Airport in New Jersey.

(Sec. 119C) This section prohibits the FAA from withholding consideration and approval of any new application for participation in the Contract Tower Program, including applications from cost-share program participants, if the tower meets the criteria included in the FAA report titled "Establishment and Discontinuance Criteria for Airport Traffic Control Towers."

(Sec. 119D) This section specifies restrictions and requirements for FAA actions to limit the use of an Organization Designation Authorization's (ODA's) delegated functions documented in its procedures manual on a type certification project. (Under the ODA program, the FAA may delegate to a private person a matter related to issuing certificates or the examination, testing, and inspection necessary to issue a certificate on behalf of the FAA.)

(Sec. 119E) This section requires the FAA to permit intermittent large cargo air carriers to land in remote areas using a mix of available local meteorological weather reports, in place of National Weather Service forecast reports where they do not provide weather coverage.

(Sec. 119F) This section allows the transfer of funds from the Grants-in-Aid for Airports account to reimburse certain airports and providers of general aviation ground support services impacted by temporary flight restrictions for any residence of the President that is designated or identified to be secured by the Secret Service. The funds may not be obligated or distributed until an independent audit is completed.

(Sec. 119G) This section requires the FAA to report to Congress on the implementation of NextGen at commercial service airports in the United States. (NextGen is a program to modernize and improve the efficiency of the national airspace system, primarily by migrating to satellite-based navigation and aircraft tracking.)

The title provides (1) funding from the Highway Trust Fund (HTF) to the Federal Highway Administration (FHWA) for Administrative Expenses and Federal-Aid Highways, and (2) appropriations for Highway Infrastructure Programs.

(Most of DOT's budget is mandatory budget authority rather than discretionary budget authority. The mandatory budget authority is primarily in the form of contract authority derived from the Highway Trust Fund (HTF). Contract authority is the authority to obligate funds in advance of an appropriation Act.

Spending from the HTF is determined both by authorization bill and appropriations bills. Authorization bills provide contract authority for highway programs, and appropriations bills include obligation limitations that determine how much of the contract authority may be used in a given year.)

(Sec. 120) This section specifies allocations and requirements for distributing obligation authority from the HTF among federal-aid highway programs.

(Sec. 121) This section credits funds received by the Bureau of Transportation Statistics from the sale of data products to the Federal-Aid Highways account to reimburse the bureau for expenses.

(Sec. 122) This section requires DOT to (1) provide an informal public notice and comment opportunity prior to waiving the Buy America requirement for federal-aid highway projects, and (2) report to Congress annually on waivers.

(Sec. 123) This section requires DOT to notify Congress prior to providing credit assistance under the Transportation Finance and Innovation Act (TIFIA) program, which provides credit to finance surface transportation projects of national and regional significance.

(Sec. 124) This section requires DOT to notify Congress 60 days in advance before making grants for nationally significant freight and highway projects (FASTLANE grants).

(Sec. 125) This section permits states to repurpose certain highway project funding to be used within 50 miles of its original designation.

The title provides funding from the HTF to the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) for (1) Motor Carrier Safety Operations and Programs, and (2) Motor Carrier Safety Grants.

(Sec. 130) This section directs the FMCSA to require certain Mexican motor carriers to meet specified safety requirements when applying to operate beyond U.S. municipalities and commercial zones on the U.S.-Mexico border.

(Sec. 131) This section requires the FMCSA to send notice of violations of certain safety procedures and regulations that could require expedited safety audits, compliance reviews, or corrective actions using certified mail, registered mail, or another manner of delivery that records the receipt of the notice by the persons responsible for the violation.

(Sec. 132) This section requires the FMCSA, to the maximum extent practicable, to ensure the safe and timely completion of the flexible sleeper berth pilot program The title provides appropriations to the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) for Operations and Research.

It also provides funding from the HTF to NHTSA for Operations and Research and Highway Traffic Safety Grants.

(Sec. 140) This section provides additional funding to NHTSA for travel and related expenses associated with state management reviews and core competency development training for highway safety staff.

(Sec. 141) This section exempts from the current fiscal year's obligation limitation for NHTSA programs any obligation authority that was made available in previous public laws and has not lapsed or been used.

(Sec. 142) This section provides additional appropriations for NHTSA to continue, in collaboration with the Federal Railroad Administration (FRA), a high visibility enforcement paid-media campaign regarding highway-rail grade crossing safety.

The title provides appropriations to the FRA for

 Safety and Operations, Railroad Research and Development, the Railroad Rehabilitation and Improvement Financing Program, the Federal-State Partnership for State Of Good Repair, Consolidated Rail Infrastructure and Safety Improvements, Restoration and Enhancement, Northeast Corridor Grants to the National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak), and National Network Grants to Amtrak. (Sec. 150) This section limits overtime for Amtrak employees. It also (1) permits Amtrak to waive the limit for specific employees due to safety or operational efficiency reasons, and (2) requires Amtrak to report to Congress on waivers granted and overtime payments incurred.

(Sec. 151) This section expresses the sense of Congress that long-distance passenger rail routes (1) provide much-needed transportation access and are particularly important in rural area, and (2) should be sustained to ensure connectivity throughout the National Network.

The title provides appropriations to the Federal Transit Administration (FTA) for

 Administrative Expenses, Transit Infrastructure Grants, Technical Assistance and Training, Capital Investment Grants, and Grants to the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority. The title also provides funding from the HTF to the FTA for Transit Formula Grants.

(Sec. 160) This section exempts previously made transit obligations from limitations on obligations.

(Sec. 161) This section permits funds appropriated before October 1, 2018, that remain available for expenditure to be transferred from older accounts to new accounts with similar current activities.

(Sec. 162) This section rescinds specified funds that were provided for the Transit Formula Grants account for FY2005 or prior fiscal years.

(Sec. 163) This section prohibits the FTA from using funds provided by this bill to implement or further certain new policies for the Capital Investment Grants program.

The title provides appropriations to the Saint Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation for Operations and Maintenance.

The title provides appropriations for the Maritime Administration (MARAD) for

 the Maritime Security Program, Operations and Training, State Maritime Academy Operations, Assistance to Small Shipyards, Ship Disposal, and the Maritime Guaranteed Loan (Title XI) Program Account. (Sec. 170) This section permits MARAD to furnish utilities and services and make repairs in connection with any lease, contract, or occupancy involving government property under the control of MARAD. Rental payments received pursuant to this provision must be credited to the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.

The title provides appropriations to the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration (PHMSA) for

 Operational Expenses, Hazardous Materials Safety, Pipeline Safety, and Emergency Preparedness Grants. The title provides appropriations to the Office of Inspector General.

(Sec. 180) This section permits DOT to use funds for maintenance and operation of aircraft, hire of passenger motor vehicles and aircraft, insurance for motor vehicles operating in foreign countries, and uniforms.

 DOT may use funds for the purchase, maintenance, operation, and deployment of unmanned aircraft systems that advance DOT's, or its operating administrations' missions.

Any unmanned aircraft system purchased or procured by DOT prior to the enactment of this bill is deemed to be authorized.

(Sec. 181) This section permits DOT to use funds provided by this bill for the employment of temporary or intermittent experts and consultants if the rates do not exceed the rate for an Executive Level IV.

(Sec. 182) This section prohibits recipients of funds provided by this bill from releasing certain personal information and photographs from a driver's license or motor vehicle record without the consent of the affected individual. It also prohibits DOT from withholding funds for any grantee if a state is not in compliance with this provision.

(Sec. 183) This section prohibits (1) funds provided by this bill from being used for more than 110 DOT presidential and political appointees, and (2) any of the appointees from being assigned on temporary detail outside of DOT.

(Sec. 184) This section permits funds received by the FHWA and the FRA from states or other private or public sources for training expenses to be credited to specified agency accounts, subject to an exception for state rail safety inspectors participating in certain training required under current law.

(Sec. 185) This section prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for certain loans, loan guarantees, lines of credit, or grants unless DOT notifies Congress at least three business days in advance of announcing competitively selected projects.

 DOT must provide concurrent notification to Congress regarding any ''quick release'' of funds from the FHWA's Emergency Relief Program. (The program provides funding for the repair or reconstruction of federal-aid highways and roads on federal lands which have suffered serious damage as a result of natural disasters or catastrophic failures from an external cause.)

DOT must provide a comprehensive list of all loans, loan guarantees, lines of credit, and discretionary grants that will be announced with a three-day advance notice to Congress.

(Sec. 186) This section permits rebates, refunds, incentive payments, minor fees, and other funds received by DOT from travel management centers, charge card programs, the subleasing of building space, and miscellaneous sources to be credited to DOT appropriations and allocated to elements of DOT using fair and equitable criteria.

(Sec. 187) This section permits DOT to use amounts recovered from improper payments to a third party contractor for expenses incurred in the recovery.

(Sec. 188) This section requires reprogramming action notifications to be transmitted to and approved or denied solely by the House and Senate Committees on Appropriations.

(Sec. 189) This section permits funds provided by this bill for modal administrations to be obligated to the Office of the Secretary for assessments or reimbursable agreements only if the funds provide a direct benefit to the applicable modal administration.

(Sec. 190) This section permits DOT to set uniform standards for developing and supporting agency transit passes and transit benefits.

(Sec. 191) This section prohibits the use of funds for any geographic, economic, or other hiring preference not otherwise authorized by law, unless certain requirements are met related to availability of local labor, displacement of existing employees, and delays in transportation plans.

(Sec. 192) This section requires DOT to report to Congress on efforts to engage with local communities, metropolitan planning organizations, and regional transportation commissions on advancing data and intelligent transportation systems technologies and other smart cities solutions.

(Sec. 193) This section requires DOT to consult with the Army Corps of Engineers to identify any existing authorities and any additional authorities that may be needed to leverage funds from DOT programs for purposes of inland waterway project costs.

(Sec. 194) This section prohibits DOT from using funds to enforce or require the enforcement of certain vehicle weight limitations if specified segments of the William H. Natcher Parkway and the Julian M. Carroll (Purchase) Parkway in Kentucky are designated as routes of the Interstate System.

(Sec. 195) This section prohibits DOT from using funds to enforce certain requirements for the use of electronic logging devices with respect to operators of commercial motor vehicles transporting livestock or insects.

(Sec. 196) This section prohibits the FTA from using funds to procure rolling stock for use in public transportation if the manufacturer of the rolling stock is incorporated in or has manufacturing facilities in the United States and receives support from the government of a country that

 is identified as a nonmarket economy country, was identified by the United States Trade Representative (USTR) as a priority foreign country, and is subject to monitoring by the USTR under the Trade Act of 1974. TITLE II--DEPARTMENT OF HOUSING AND URBAN DEVELOPMENT

Department of Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2019 

This title provides FY2019 appropriations for the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD).

The title provides appropriations for Management and Administration, including for Executive Offices and Administrative Support Offices.

The title provides appropriations for Program Office Salaries and Expenses, including

 Public and Indian Housing, Community Planning and Development, Housing, Policy Development and Research, Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity, and the Office of Lead Hazard Control and Healthy Homes. HUD may transfer specified funds provided by this title for salaries and expenses to the Working Capital Fund to fund centralized activities.

The title provides appropriations for Public and Indian Housing, including

 Tenant-Based Rental Assistance, the Housing Certificate Fund, the Public Housing Capital Fund, the Public Housing Operating Fund, the Choice Neighborhoods Initiative, the Family Self-Sufficiency Program, Native American Housing Block Grants, the Indian Housing Loan Guarantee Fund Program Account, and the Native Hawaiian Housing Block Grant. The title provides appropriations for Community Planning and Development, including

 Housing Opportunities for Persons with AIDS, the Community Development Fund, the Community Development Loan Guarantees Program Account, the Home Investment Partnerships Program, the Self-Help and Assisted Home Ownership Opportunity Program, and Homeless Assistance Grants. The title provides appropriations for Housing Programs, including

 Project-Based Rental Assistance, Housing for the Elderly, Housing for Persons with Disabilities, Housing Counseling Assistance, Rental Housing Assistance, and Payment to the Manufactured Housing Fees Trust Fund. The title provides appropriations and establishes limits on loan commitments for the Federal Housing Administration (FHA), which includes (1) the Mutual Mortgage Insurance Program Account, and (2) the General and Special Risk Program Account.

The title provides appropriations and establishes limits on loan commitments for the Government National Mortgage Association (Ginnie Mae).

The title provides appropriations to HUD for

 Policy Development and Research, Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity, the Office of Lead Hazard Control and Healthy Homes, the Information Technology Fund, and the Office of Inspector General. (Sec. 201) This section requires 50% of the funds that are recaptured from the refinancing of state or locally financed projects under the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Amendments Act of 1988 to be rescinded or, in the case of cash, remitted to the Treasury.

Funds that are not rescinded or returned to the Treasury must be used by state housing finance agencies or local governments for certain projects approved by HUD.

HUD may award up to 15% of the funds that are recaptured and not rescinded or remitted to the Treasury to provide project owners with incentives to refinance projects at lower interest rates.

(Sec. 202) This section prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to investigate or prosecute under the Fair Housing Act any otherwise lawful activities, including the filing or maintaining of a nonfrivolous legal action to achieve or prevent action by a government entity or a court.

(Sec. 203) This section requires any grant, cooperative agreement, or other assistance made pursuant to this title to be made on a competitive basis and in accordance with provisions of the Department of Housing and Urban Development Reform Act of 1989 regarding HUD accountability.

(Sec. 204) This section permits specified funds to be used, without regard to limitations on administrative expenses, for (1) legal services; and (2) payment for services and facilities of the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae), Ginnie Mae, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac), the Federal Financing Bank, Federal Reserve banks, Federal Home Loan banks, and any bank insured under the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Act.

(Sec. 205) This section prohibits HUD appropriations from being used for any program, project, or activity in excess of amounts included in the budget estimates submitted to Congress, unless otherwise provided by this bill or through reprogramming.

(Sec. 206) This section permits HUD corporations and agencies subject to the Government Corporation Control Act to utilize funds and make contracts and commitments, without regard to fiscal year limitations and subject to specified restrictions, to implement the FY2019 budget.

(Sec. 207) This section requires HUD to provide quarterly reports to Congress regarding uncommitted, unobligated, recaptured, and excess funds for each program and activity.

(Sec. 208) This section requires the President's budget request and HUD's congressional budget justifications to use the same account and sub-account structure included in this bill.

(Sec. 209) This section exempts Ginnie Mae from certain requirements of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990.

(Sec. 210) This section permits HUD to authorize the transfer of project-based assistance, debt, and low-income and very low-income use restrictions associated with a multifamily housing project from obsolete or economically nonviable housing to a viable project if no additional costs are incurred and other specified conditions are met.

(Sec. 211) This section sets forth eligibility requirements for section 8 housing assistance vouchers.

(Sec. 212) This section requires Native American Housing Block Grant funds to be distributed to the same Native Alaskans that received funds in FY2005.

(Sec. 213) This section sets forth requirements for HUD regarding the managing and disposing of any multifamily housing property that is held or owned by HUD. The section also specifies requirements for maintaining any rental assistance payments under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 and other programs that are attached to any dwelling units in the property.

(Sec. 214) This section permits Community Development Loan Guarantee funds to be used to guarantee notes or other obligations issued by any state on behalf of its non-entitlement communities.

(Sec. 215) This section permits certain public housing agencies (PHAs) that own and operate 400 or fewer public housing units to elect to be exempt from asset management requirements imposed by HUD in connection with the operating fund rule.

(Sec. 216) This section prohibits HUD from using public housing funds to impose any requirement or guideline relating to asset management that restricts or limits the use of capital funds for central office costs, up to the limits established in the Quality Housing and Work Responsibility Act of 1998.

(Sec. 217) This section prohibits the designation of a HUD official or employee as an allotment holder unless the Chief Financial Officer has determined that the employee has (1) implemented an adequate system of funds control, and (2) received training in funds control procedures and directives.

The Chief Financial Officer must ensure that there is a trained allotment holder for each HUD appropriations under specified accounts.

(Sec. 218) This section requires HUD to publish on the Internet all competitively awarded Notices of Funding Availability for FY2019.

(Sec. 219) This section sets forth limitations and reporting requirements for the payment of attorney fees in program-related litigation.

(Sec. 220) This section sets forth requirements for transferring and reprogramming funds within specified HUD Administrative Support Office and Program Office Salaries and Expenses accounts.

(Sec. 221) This section requires HUD to take specified actions against owners who are receiving rental subsidies and do not maintain safe properties.

(Sec. 222) This section limits compensation for PHA officials and employees.

(Sec. 223) This section requires HUD to notify Congress at least three business days before announcing the recipients of grant awards.

(Sec. 224) This section prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to require or enforce the Physical Needs Assessment (PNA).

(Sec. 225) This section prohibits the FHA, Ginnie Mae, or HUD from using funds provided by this bill to finance mortgages for properties that have been subject to eminent domain condemnation or seizure by a state, municipality, or other political subdivision of a state.

(Sec. 226) This section prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to terminate the status of a unit of general local government as a metropolitan city with respect to community development grants under the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974.

(Sec. 227) This section permits funds that are provided to the HUD Office of Policy Development and Research for research, evaluation, and statistical purposes and that are unexpended at the completion of a contract, grant or cooperative agreement to be used for additional research, subject to reprogramming requirements.

(Sec. 228) This section prohibits funds from being used for awards, including performance, special act, or spot, for HUD employees who have been subject to administrative discipline in FY2018 or FY2019, including suspension from work.

(Sec. 229) This section permits HUD to use funds provided for Homeless Assistance Grants to participate in the multiagency Performance Partnerships Pilots program on a limited basis.

(Sec. 230) This section permits costs paid by the program income of grant recipients to count toward the recipient's matching requirements for 2015, 2016, 2017, 2018, and 2019 Continuum of Care funds. (The program awards project sponsors or unified funding agencies competitive grants focused on addressing the long-term housing and services needs of homeless individuals and families.)

(Sec. 231) This section permits HUD to use funds provided by this bill for Homeless Assistance Grants to award one-year grants to transition from one Continuum of Care program component to another. (The program awards project sponsors or unified funding agencies competitive grants focused on addressing the long-term housing and services needs of homeless individuals and families.)

No more than 50% of each transition grant may be used for the costs of eligible activities of the program component originally funded.

(Sec. 232) This section prohibits HUD from using funds provided by this bill to direct a grantee to undertake specific changes to existing zoning laws as part of carrying out the final rule titled "Affirmatively Furthering Fair Housing" or the notice entitled "Affirmatively Furthering Fair Housing Assessment Tool."

(Sec. 233) This section prohibits provisions of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act regarding the expiration of the right to draw funds from applying to the right of a jurisdiction to draw funds from its HOME Investment Trust Fund that otherwise expired or would expire in 2016, 2017, 2018, 2019, 2020, or 2021 under current law.

(Sec. 234) This section maintains existing Promise Zone designations and agreements.

(Sec. 235) This section requires HUD to review public housing and tenant-based rental assistance regulations, related notices, and other guidance documents to identify opportunities to streamline the administration of the programs while also ensuring compliance with financial and internal control requirements.

It also requires HUD to establish a regulatory advisory committee to advise HUD on specific policy proposals to reduce the administrative burden.

(Sec. 236) This section prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to establish and apply a ranking factor in the selection and award of any funds made available and requiring competitive selection under this bill, including preference, bonus points, or other incentives for participation in or coordination with EnVision Centers.

(Sec. 237) This section requires HUD to continue to engage in, and report to Congress on, efforts authorized by the Violence Against Women Reauthorization Act of 2013 to ensure that survivors of domestic violence and sexual assault are not unlawfully evicted or denied housing by certain landlords based on their experience as survivors.

(Sec. 238) This section prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to provide housing assistance benefits to any individual who is convicted of

 aggravated sexual abuse, murder, or any other federal or state offense involving child pornography or severe forms of trafficking in persons or sex trafficking. TITLE III--RELATED AGENCIES

This title provides FY2019 appropriations to

 the Access Board, the Federal Maritime Commission, the Amtrak Office of Inspector General, the National Transportation Safety Board, the Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation, the Surface Transportation Board, and the U.S. Interagency Council on Homelessness. TITLE IV--GENERAL PROVISIONS--THIS ACT

(Sec. 401) This section prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to compensate or pay the expenses of non-federal parties intervening in regulatory or adjudicatory proceedings funded in this bill.

(Sec. 402) This section prohibits transfers of funds to other appropriations or obligations beyond the current fiscal year, unless expressly permitted in this bill.

(Sec. 403) This section limits expenditures for consulting services to contracts where the expenditures are a matter of public record and available for public inspection, unless otherwise provided by law or an executive order.

(Sec. 404) This section prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill for employee training not specifically related to the performance of official duties.

(Sec. 405) This section specifies procedures, restrictions, and reporting requirements for the reprogramming of funds provided by this bill.

(Sec. 406) This section permits up to 50% of unobligated balances remaining at the end of FY2019 from appropriations for salaries and expenses to remain available through FY2020, subject to congressional approval and reprogramming guidelines.

(Sec. 407) This section prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for any project that seeks to use eminent domain unless eminent domain is employed only for a public use.

(Sec. 408) This section prohibits the transfer of funds provided by this bill to a department, agency, or instrumentality of the U.S. government unless the transfer is pursuant to an appropriations Act.

(Sec. 409) This section prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to permanently replace an employee intent on returning to his or her previous occupation after completing military service.

(Sec. 410) This section requires expenditures of funds provided by this bill to comply with the Buy American Act.

(Sec. 411) This section prohibits funds provided by this bill from being made available to any person or entity that has been convicted of violating the Buy American Act.

(Sec. 412) This section prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to purchase first class or premium airline travel in violation of specified federal travel regulations.

(Sec. 413) This section prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to approve a new foreign air carrier permit or exemption application if the approval would contravene U.S. law or specified provisions of the U.S.-E.U.-Iceland-Norway Air Transport Agreement.

(Sec. 414) This section restricts the number of employees that agencies funded in this bill may send to international conferences.

(Sec. 415) This section limits Surface Transportation Board fees for the filing of rate or practice complaints.

(Sec. 416) This section prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to purchase new light-duty vehicles, except in accordance with Presidential Memorandum- Federal Fleet Performance, which establishes requirements for purchasing alternative fueled vehicles.

(Sec. 417) This section prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for a computer network unless pornography is blocked, with an exception for law enforcement, prosecution, or adjudication activities.

(Sec. 418) This section prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to deny an Inspector General (IG) timely access to any records, documents, or other materials available to the department or agency over which that IG has responsibilities, or to prevent or impede that IG's access. Each IG must comply with (1) specified statutory limitations on disclosure of the information provided, and (2) reporting requirements regarding violations of this section.

(Sec. 419) This section prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to pay award or incentive fees for contractors whose performance is below satisfactory, behind schedule, over budget, or has failed to meet the basic requirements of a contract unless specified requirements are met.

(Sec. 420) This section prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to acquire telecommunications equipment produced by Huawei Technologies Company, ZTE Corporation or a high-impact or moderate-impact information system unless the agency acquiring the system meets certain requirements for reviews, assessments, reports, and mitigation strategies for risks.

(Sec. 421) This section specifies that the explanatory statement printed in the Congressional Record regarding division D (Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2019) of H.R. 21 (Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2019) has the same effect, with respect to this bill, as if it were a joint explanatory statement of a conference committee.

(Sec. 422) This section compensates federal employees furloughed as a result of a lapse in appropriations that began on or about December 22, 2018, and ended upon the enactment of this bill. It also ratifies and approves certain obligations incurred in anticipation of the appropriations made and the authority granted by this bill.

(Sec. 423) This section reimburses or compensates certain states, federal grantees, and furloughed state employees for any period in FY2019 in which a lapse in appropriations occurs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
