<bill session="116" type="s" number="1309" updated="2019-11-01T04:59:26Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combating Global Corruption Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combating Global Corruption Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Combating Global Corruption Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to identify and combat corruption in countries, to establish a tiered system of countries with respect to levels of corruption by their governments and their efforts to combat such corruption, and to assess United States assistance to designated countries in order to advance anti-corruption efforts in those countries and better serve United States taxpayers.</title>
    <title type="display">Combating Global Corruption Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2019-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2019-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2019-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2019-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2019-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2019-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2019-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2019-05-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-06-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Risch with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-07-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="144">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 144.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-05-02T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Combating Global Corruption Act of 2019

This bill requires the Department of State to develop a program to combat corruption in foreign countries, in particular in countries that receive U.S. aid.

The State Department shall publish annually a tiered list of all countries. The first tier shall contain countries that meet the bill's prescribed minimum standards for combatting corruption, while the second tier shall contain countries that do not comply but are making efforts to do so. Third-tier countries do not meet the minimum anti-corruption standards and are making little to no effort to comply.

For a third-tier country that receives U.S. foreign aid, the State Department shall conduct corruption risk assessments for all U.S. aid programs in that country. It shall also implement various anti-corruption mechanisms in such programs, such as by requiring the disclosure of the beneficial ownership of contractors and partners involved in an aid program and requiring claw-back provisions to recover funds&#160;that are misappropriated by corrupt partners. For future aid programs to such countries, the State Department shall conduct its risk assessment and implement the required anti-corruption mechanisms before agreeing to provide assistance.

The State Department shall report to Congress annually about its anti-corruption efforts and integrate anti-corruption material into its existing training courses.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
