<bill session="116" type="h" number="2362" updated="2019-10-15T14:38:23Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prioritize the purchase of agricultural commodities from domestically owned enterprises, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Agriculture First Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Agriculture First Act</title>
    <title type="display">American Agriculture First Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001187"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Biotechnology, Horticulture, and Research.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Biotechnology, Horticulture, and Research" code="HSAG14" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-04-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">American Agriculture First Act 

This bill requires the Agricultural Marketing Service (AMS) to purchase at least 75% of the agricultural commodities of the Food Purchase and Distribution Program from domestically owned enterprises if it is necessary to respond to trade damage from retaliation by foreign nations with respect to agricultural commodities.

The requirement does not apply if the Department of Agriculture reports to Congress that meeting the requirement

 is not possible because the agricultural commodities available from domestically owned enterprises cannot meet the supply needs of the AMS; or would result in a greater than 150% increase between (1) the amount necessary to purchase the agricultural commodities, and (2) the average cost of the agricultural commodities purchased by the AMS in the prior 3 years. The authority provided by this bill expires on September 30, 2023.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
