<bill session="116" type="hr" number="6" updated="2019-10-27T07:56:27Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-09T16:51:30-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-01-09T16:51:30-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Adopting the Rules of the House of Representatives for the One Hundred Sixteenth Congress, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Adopting the Rules of the House of Representatives for the One Hundred Sixteenth Congress, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000874"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03T18:11:11-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 5.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H17-32" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03T18:11:57-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 5, the House proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on Title I of H.Res. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03T18:42:57-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on Title I pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03T19:14:18-05:00">
      <text>On agreeing to Title I of the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 234 - 197 (Roll no. 7).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03T19:14:33-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03T19:14:48-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - Pursuant to section 3 of H.Res. 5, the Chair announced that further proceedings on H.Res. 6 would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-04T09:11:56-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H220-224" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-04T09:12:14-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 5, the House proceeded with one hour of debate on Title II of H. Res. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-04T09:43:31-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on Title II pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-04T09:44:36-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on Title II of H. Res. 6, the Chair put the question on agreeing to Title II of the resolution and by voice vote announced that ayes had prevailed. Mr. Cole demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further consideration on the question until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-04T10:16:53-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H224-225" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-04T10:43:54-05:00">
      <text>On agreeing to Title II of the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 418 - 12 (Roll no. 12).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-04T10:43:55-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-04T10:44:08-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - Pursuant to section 3 of H. Res. 5, the Chair announced that further proceedings on H. Res. 6 would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-09T15:20:19-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H338-346" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-09T15:20:52-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 5, the House proceeded with one hour of debate on Title III of H. Res. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-09T16:25:48-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion On agreeing to Title III of the resolution was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-09T16:51:28-05:00">
      <text>On agreeing to Title III of the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 235 - 192 (Roll no. 19).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="without objection" type="vote" datetime="2019-01-09T16:51:30-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-01-09T16:51:40-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="116" relation="unknown" number="5"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="116" relation="unknown" number="14"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional leadership"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    <term name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/>
    <term name="House Committee on Ethics"/>
    <term name="House Committee on Financial Services"/>
    <term name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <term name="House Committee on Rules"/>
    <term name="House Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation facilities"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-09T16:42:43Z" status="Passed House">This resolution adopts the Rules of the House of Representatives for the 116th Congress. The resolution adopts the rules of the 115th Congress with amendments that include

 allowing Delegates and the Resident Commissioner to vote in the Committee of the Whole; revising annual ethics training requirements; providing mandatory anti-harassment and anti-discrimination policies for House offices; prohibiting Members, officers, and employees of the House from serving as an officer or director of a public company; requiring Members to pay for any discrimination settlements against them; requiring indicted Members to step down from any committee and leadership positions until disposition of the criminal case; reinstating certain provisions of Pay-As-You-Go rules; providing for automatic suspension of the debt limit if the House adopts a budget resolution (Gephardt rule); requiring committee hearings and markups on bills and joint resolutions before floor consideration; revising the rule prohibiting a floor vote on a measure before the third day text is available to require text to be available for 72 hours before a floor vote; excluding measures addressing the War Powers Resolution from "motions to table"; renaming, establishing, or reauthorizing specified congressional committees, commissions, and offices; creating a Consensus Calendar, which provides an alternative path to a floor vote for measures with 290 or more cosponsors; permitting religious headwear in the Hall of the House; authorizing the Speaker to intervene in litigation involving the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act; directing the Office of General Counsel to explore legal options for responding to certain rulemaking by the Department of Agriculture regarding Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program requirements for able-bodied adults without dependents; prohibiting nondisclosure agreements from requiring notice or approval for employees to communicate with certain offices or entities, including the Committee on Ethics and the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights; and requiring each House office to prominently display a statement of the rights and protections provided to House employees. The resolution also bans (1) discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation or gender identity, and (2) sexual relationships between Members and committee staff.

For more detailed information, see Congressional Research Service Report R45787, House Rules Changes Affecting Floor Proceedings in the 116th Congress (2019-2020), Congressional Research Service Report R45731, House Rules Changes Affecting Committee Procedure in the 116th Congress (2019-2020), and Congressional Research Service Report R45552, Changes to House Rules Affecting the Congressional Budget Process Included in H.Res. 6 (116th Congress).</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
