<bill session="116" type="s" number="1780" updated="2019-06-29T03:32:15Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to provide for studies and reports relating to the impact of legislation on spending on children, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Focus on Children Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Focus on Children Act</title>
    <title type="display">Focus on Children Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2019-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2019-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-06-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Focus on Children Act 

This bill requires the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) to produce studies and reports regarding federal spending on children.

The CBO must provide

 studies of legislation containing changes in spending on children, upon the request of a congressional committee; an annual report regarding spending on children; and an annual report on the President's budget request for spending on children. The CBO may provide a warning report to Congress regarding a fiscal year in which outlays for interest on the public debt will exceed spending on children.

The CBO must also develop and maintain a public website that includes

 the reports and studies required by this bill, a dashboard containing key indicators and visualization tools to assist the public in understanding trends in spending on children, and an open data portal that contains quantitative data on federal spending on children.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
