<bill session="116" type="s" number="1513" updated="2019-10-24T04:16:13Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve oversight of privatized military housing provided by the Department of Defense to members of the Armed Forces and their families, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Better Military Housing Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Better Military Housing Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Better Military Housing Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001113"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="identical" number="2811"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-05-16T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Better Military Housing Act of 2019

 This bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to develop and implement a plan to address health, safety, and quality issues at privatized military housing.

DOD shall provide a tenant entering into a tenancy agreement for such a housing unit information on

 tenant rights; expectations regarding reporting by tenants and landlords of maintenance, health, or safety issues relating to the unit; a comprehensive accounting of the rights and responsibilities relating to maintenance; and a comprehensive maintenance, repair, and remediation history of the unit. At least annually, the DOD Inspector General shall inspect the oversight of privatized military housing at no fewer than 15 randomly selected installations. Additionally, DOD shall study ways to improve privatized military housing and the oversight and execution of contracts in order to improve housing conditions for Armed Forces members and their families.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
