<bill session="116" type="s" number="2263" updated="2019-10-24T19:00:36Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to enhance the requirements for secure geological storage of carbon oxide for purposes of the carbon oxide sequestration credit, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CO2 Regulatory Certainty Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CO2 Regulatory Certainty Act</title>
    <title type="display">CO2 Regulatory Certainty Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2019-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2019-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2019-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2019-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-07-25T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">CO2 Regulatory Certainty Act

This bill&#160;amends the Internal Revenue Code to revise requirements for the secure geological storage of carbon oxide.

The bill requires the Internal Revenue Service (IRS), in consultation with other federal agencies, including the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), to proscribe regulations for determining adequate security measures for the geological storage of&#160; carbon oxide so that it does not escape into the atmosphere.

The IRS regulations must consider the carbon oxide to be disposed of in secure geological storage if it is stored in compliance with specified rules promulgated by the EPA under the Clean Air Act and the Safe Drinking Water Act for the geologic sequestration of carbon oxide.

The bill also revises the definition of "qualified enhanced oil or natural gas recovery project" to exclude a requirement for the first injection of liquids, gases, or other matter to commence after December 31, 1990.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
