<bill session="116" type="h" number="3351" updated="2019-09-21T07:16:24Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-26T15:06:17-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-06-26T15:06:17-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for financial services and general government for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2020, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Department of the Treasury Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Department of the Treasury Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Executive Office of the President Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Executive Office of the President Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Judiciary Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Judiciary Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Department of the Treasury Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Department of the Treasury Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Executive Office of the President Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Executive Office of the President Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Judiciary Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Judiciary Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Department of the Treasury Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Executive Office of the President Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Judiciary Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="display">Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Q000023"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 116-122, by Mr. Quigley.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-06-19" state="REPORTED" calendar="Union" number="90">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 90.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-06-24T23:51:01-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 460 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2722 and H.R. 3351. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 2722 under a closed rule with one hour of general debate. Also, the resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 3351 under a structured rule with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T14:08:41-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 460 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T14:50:45-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 460.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5104-5108" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T14:50:50-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2722 and H.R. 3351. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 2722 under a closed rule with one hour of general debate. Also, the resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 3351 under a structured rule with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T14:51:06-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 460 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T14:51:07-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable William R. Keating to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T14:52:12-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 3351.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T15:24:43-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Quigley moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T15:24:59-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T15:25:53-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 3351 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T15:27:22-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5108-5138" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T15:27:35-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T15:27:39-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with further debate on H.R. 3351.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T15:47:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 460, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pocan amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T15:54:33-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 460, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the King (IA) amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T16:01:17-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the King (IA) amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. King (IA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T16:02:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 460, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norton amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T16:11:21-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Norton amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Graves (GA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T16:12:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 460, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Huizenga amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T16:20:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 460, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Vel&#225;zquez amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T16:24:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 460, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hill (AR) amendment No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T16:29:07-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 460, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lee (CA) amendment No. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T16:34:32-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 460, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Courtney amendment No. 9.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T16:37:36-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 460, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pascrell amendment No. 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T16:43:22-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Quigley moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T16:43:42-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T16:44:06-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 3351 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T20:50:13-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5159-5161" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T20:50:59-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T21:24:27-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Kaptur moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T21:24:40-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25T21:24:48-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 3351 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T12:23:21-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5177-5197" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T12:23:51-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T12:25:54-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 460, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Quigley amendment en bloc No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T12:36:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 460, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grothman amendment No. 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T12:41:07-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Grothman amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Grothman demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T12:42:51-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 460, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Quigley amendment en bloc No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T12:47:37-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Quigley amendment en bloc No. 2, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Graves (GA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T12:49:08-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 460, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Connolly amendment No. 18</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T13:01:19-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 460, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Banks amendment No. 19.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T13:07:15-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Banks amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Quigley demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T13:08:21-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 460, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Suozzi amendment No. 26.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T13:10:39-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Suozzi amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Suozzi demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T13:11:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 460, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lee (NV) amendment No. 27.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T13:13:49-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Lee (NV) amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Quigley demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T13:16:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 460, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Dean amendment No. 32.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T13:20:18-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Dean amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Dean demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T13:20:33-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 460, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kim amendment No. 35.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T13:23:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Kim amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Kim demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T13:24:02-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 460, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Malinowski amendment No. 40.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T13:26:38-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Malinowski amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Malinowski demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T14:34:30-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 3351.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T14:34:31-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T14:35:25-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T14:36:40-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Graves (GA) moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5194" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T14:37:15-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Graves (GA) motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to increase funding for the Office of Terrorism and Financial Intelligence account by $10 million and decrease funding for the General Services Administration account by a similar amount.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T14:46:24-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T14:58:39-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Agreed to by recorded vote: 226 - 195 (Roll no. 423).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="424" datetime="2019-06-26T15:06:17-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 224 - 196 (Roll no. 424).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 6/25/2019 H5110-5130" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26T15:06:19-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-27">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2524"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="116" relation="procedurally-related" number="460"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h503"/>
    <amendment number="h502"/>
    <amendment number="h501"/>
    <amendment number="h500"/>
    <amendment number="h499"/>
    <amendment number="h498"/>
    <amendment number="h497"/>
    <amendment number="h496"/>
    <amendment number="h495"/>
    <amendment number="h494"/>
    <amendment number="h493"/>
    <amendment number="h491"/>
    <amendment number="h490"/>
    <amendment number="h489"/>
    <amendment number="h488"/>
    <amendment number="h487"/>
    <amendment number="h486"/>
    <amendment number="h485"/>
    <amendment number="h484"/>
    <amendment number="h483"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2019-06-26T14:00:00Z" status="Passed House">Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act, 2020

This bill provides FY2020 appropriations for several federal departments and agencies, including

 the Department of the Treasury, the Executive Office of the President, the judiciary, the District of Columbia, and several independent agencies. The independent agencies funded in the bill include

 the Administrative Conference of the United States, the Consumer Product Safety Commission, the Election Assistance Commission, the Federal Communications Commission, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Federal Election Commission, the Federal Labor Relations Authority, the Federal Trade Commission, the General Services Administration, the Harry S. Truman Scholarship Foundation, the Merit Systems Protection Board, the Morris K. Udall and Stewart L. Udall Foundation, the National Archives and Records Administration, the National Credit Union Administration, the Office of Government Ethics, the Office Personnel Management, the Office of Special Counsel, the Postal Regulatory Commission, the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board, the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Selective Service System, the Small Business Administration, the U.S. Postal Service, and the U.S. Tax Court. The bill also sets forth requirements and restrictions for using funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-122</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
