<bill session="116" type="s" number="2584" updated="2019-10-03T04:42:34Z">
  <state datetime="2019-09-26">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill making appropriations for the Departments of Commerce and Justice, Science, and Related Agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2020, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate" partial="1">Department of Commerce Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate" partial="1">Department of Commerce Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate" partial="1">Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate" partial="1">Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate" partial="1">Science Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate" partial="1">Science Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Department of Commerce Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Science Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="display">Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000934"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-09-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-26">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Moran. With written report No. 116-127.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-09-26" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="231">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 231.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3055"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-09-26T15:22:33Z" status="Reported to Senate">Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020

This bill provides FY2020 appropriations to the Department of Commerce; the Department of Justice (DOJ); science agencies, including the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) and the National Science Foundation (NSF); and several related agencies.

The bill provides appropriations to the Department of Commerce for

 the International Trade Administration, the Bureau of Industry and Security, the Economic Development Administration, the Minority Business Development Agency, Economic and Statistical Analysis, the Bureau of the Census, the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and Departmental Management. The bill provides appropriations to DOJ for

 General Administration; the Executive Office for Immigration Review; the Office of Inspector General; the U.S. Parole Commission; Legal Activities; the U.S. Marshals Service; the National Security Division; Interagency Law Enforcement; the Federal Bureau of Investigation; the Drug Enforcement Administration; the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives; and the Federal Prison System. The bill also provides appropriations to DOJ for State and State and Local Law Enforcement Activities, including

 the Office on Violence Against Women, the Office of Justice Programs, and Community Oriented Policing Services (COPS). The bill provides appropriations for science agencies, including

 the Office of Science and Technology Policy, the National Space Council, NASA, and the NSF. The bill provides appropriations to related agencies, including

 the Commission on Civil Rights, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the U.S. International Trade Commission, the Legal Services Corporation, the Marine Mammal Commission, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative, and the State Justice Institute. The bill also sets forth requirements and restrictions for using funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 116-127</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
