<bill session="116" type="h" number="1033" updated="2019-09-26T16:15:22Z">
  <state datetime="2019-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Arms Export Control Act to modify certification and report requirements relating to sales of major defense equipment with respect to which nonrecurring costs of research, development, and production are waived or reduced under the Arms Export Control Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REPAY Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REPAY Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Return Expenses Paid And Yielded Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Return Expenses Paid And Yielded Act</title>
    <title type="display">REPAY Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001175"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2019-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2019-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2019-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001187" joined="2019-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2019-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2019-02-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1790"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2500"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-02-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Return Expenses Paid and Yielded Act or REPAY Act

This bill modifies certification and reporting requirements related to certain defense equipment sales to foreign countries or international organizations, and limits the President's authority&#160;to waive various research, development, and production costs charged to the buyer in such sales.

The President shall, in the certification submitted to Congress for a sale of major defense equipment of $14 million or more, provide information about any waived or reduced charges for the proportionate amount of nonrecurring research, development,&#160;and production costs in the sale. The certification shall include additional information such as the type of waiver provided to the buyer, the justification for the waiver, and in certain instances the manner in which the sale would help standardization between the buyer's forces and&#160;the U.S. Armed Forces.

The President may not waive such nonrecurring charges if the buyer has received (1) $16 million worth of such waivers in the past two years, (2) 15 waivers in the past five years, or (3) $425 million worth of waivers in the past five years.

The bill also allows Armed Forces salaries and civilian benefits costs to be included as chargeable administrative expenses related to such defense equipment sales.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
