<bill session="116" type="s" number="1018" updated="2019-04-26T04:42:11Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Refund to Rainy Day Savings Program.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Refund to Rainy Day Savings Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Refund to Rainy Day Savings Act</title>
    <title type="display">Refund to Rainy Day Savings Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2019-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000300" joined="2019-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2019-04-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="identical" number="2112"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-04-03T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Refund to Rainy Day Savings Act 

This bill requires the Department of the Treasury to establish and implement a Refund to Rainy Day Savings Program to permit a taxpayer to defer payment on 20% of a tax refund to be deposited into a Treasury account, accumulate interest, and disbursed to the taxpayer in six months.

The bill also reauthorizes the Assets for Independence (AFI) federal matched savings program through FY2024 and requires appropriations for the program to be reserved for

 general research and evaluation, grants for AFI innovation projects to expand the availability of matched savings accounts to low-income individuals, and a three-year matched savings account pilot program established by the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to encourage savings by low-income taxpayers. Under the pilot program, HHS may provide grants to qualified entities to match funds saved by low-income taxpayers under the Refund to Rainy Day Savings Program.

Qualified entities for the pilot program include

 nonprofit organizations, state or local government agencies or tribal governments applying with a nonprofit organization, sites that offer free tax assistance under certain Internal Revenue Service programs, and certain low-income credit unions and community development financial institutions. HHS must (1) contract with an independent research organization to evaluate the pilot program, and (2) report annually to Congress on the progress and outcomes of the pilot program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
