<bill session="116" type="h" number="1926" updated="2019-10-24T19:00:30Z">
  <state datetime="2019-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide temporary protected status for certain nationals of Liberia, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Our Liberian Community Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Our Liberian Community Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Protect Our Liberian Community Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000616"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2019-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Immigration and Citizenship" code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Liberia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-03-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Protect Our Liberian Community Act of 2019

This bill establishes that a national of Liberia shall be deemed to have registered for temporary protected status as of April 1, 2019, for three years, if the national registered for such status at any time and was present in the United States on March 30, 2019, under deferred enforced departure.

Temporary protected status is available to nationals of certain designated countries, and such aliens shall have work authorization not be removed from the United States while the status is in effect. Liberia's designation was terminated as of May 21, 2017. The President has granted deferred enforced departure status to Liberian nationals, which prevents their removal from the country and provides work authorization, until March 30, 2020.

Individuals with temporary protected status under this bill shall have employment authorization for the three-year period, and any lapse of authorization between April 1, 2019, and the enactment date of this bill shall not affect the validity of such an individual's employment authorization document.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
