<bill session="116" type="h" number="1825" updated="2019-07-30T13:26:42Z">
  <state datetime="2019-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modernize the Office of the National Taxpayer Advocate.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Assistance for Taxpayers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Assistance for Taxpayers Act</title>
    <title type="display">Improving Assistance for Taxpayers Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000585"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001201" joined="2019-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3151"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="928"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1957"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-03-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Improving Assistance for Taxpayers Act 

This bill requires the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to respond to Taxpayer Advocate Directives within specified time frames.

In the case of a Taxpayer Advocate Directive issued by the National Taxpayer Advocate (NTA) pursuant to a delegation of authority from the IRS, the IRS Commissioner or a Deputy Commissioner must modify, rescind, or ensure compliance with the directive within 90 days.

If a directive is modified or rescinded by a Deputy Commissioner, the NTA may appeal to the Commissioner. Within 90 days of the appeal, the Commissioner must either ensure compliance with the directive or provide a description of the reasons for any modification or rescission made or upheld pursuant to the appeal.

The bill also requires the NTA annual report to identify any directive that was not honored by the IRS in a timely manner, as required by this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
