<bill session="116" type="h" number="2133" updated="2019-09-25T16:00:19Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for interim appropriations for the District of Columbia courts and related agencies with respect to any fiscal year for which appropriations are not otherwise provided for such courts and agencies.</title>
    <title type="display">To provide for interim appropriations for the District of Columbia courts and related agencies with respect to any fiscal year for which appropriations are not otherwise provided for such courts and agencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E423"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="State and local courts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-04-08T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill provides continuing appropriations to the District of Columbia courts and related agencies during any fiscal year in which appropriations have not otherwise been provided. (The continuing appropriations would exempt the courts and agencies from a government shutdown due to a lapse in appropriations for the federal government.)

The bill provides continuing appropriations for federal payments to

 the District of Columbia Courts, defender services in District of Columbia courts, the Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency for the District of Columbia, the District of Columbia Public Defender Service, the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council, the District of Columbia Commission on Judicial Disabilities and Tenure, and the District of Columbia Judicial Nomination Commission.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
