<bill session="116" type="h" number="3613" updated="2019-08-16T10:41:41Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to establish a methodology for determining State allotments for Medicaid disproportionate share hospital payments that is based on State poverty levels, to require States to prioritize disproportionate share hospital payments on the basis of Medicaid inpatient utilization and low-income utilization rates, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE Hospitals Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE Hospitals Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State Accountability, Flexibility, and Equity for Hospitals Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State Accountability, Flexibility, and Equity for Hospitals Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">State Accountability, Flexibility, and Equity for Hospitals Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001257"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="identical" number="18"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-07-02T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">State Accountability, Flexibility, and Equity for Hospitals Act of 2019 or the SAFE Hospitals Act of 2019

This bill alters Medicaid requirements relating to payment for inpatient hospital services that are provided by disproportionate share hospitals (DSHs). (DSHs are hospitals that receive additional payment under Medicaid for treating a large share of low-income patients.)

Among other changes, the bill requires state Medicaid programs to adopt a payment methodology that meets certain criteria, including by prioritizing payments based on the DSH tier for which the hospital qualifies; tiers are determined based on factors such as the hospital's Medicaid inpatient utilization rate.

The bill also incorporates state poverty ratios (i.e., the number of qualifying low-income individuals in a state compared to all states) into the formula for determining state DSH allotments under Medicaid. The bill phases in application of the revised formula over the course of 10 to 15 years.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
