<bill session="116" type="h" number="1500" updated="2019-10-24T02:25:29Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-22T17:25:38-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-05-22T17:25:38-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau to meet its statutory purpose, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Consumers First Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Consumers First Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Consumers First Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Consumers First Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consumers First Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consumers First Act</title>
    <title type="display">Consumers First Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000187"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000370" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000378" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001281" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001049" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000631" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000454" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000571" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000586" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000587" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000581" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000553" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001064" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001047" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000586" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000562" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001137" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000172" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000593" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000618" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000617" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001204" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001157" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000130" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000081" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000825" joined="2019-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-03-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 34 - 26.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-05-10">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 116-57, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-10">
      <text>Committee on Education and Labor discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-05-10" calendar="Union" number="35">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 35.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-05-20T20:05:47-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 389 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1500 and H.R. 1994. The resolution provides for one hour of debate on H.R. 1500, under a structured rule, and provides for one hour of debate on H.R. 1994, under a closed rule. The resolution provides for proceedings during the period from May 24, 2019, through May 31, 2019, and provides for motions to suspend the rules on the legislative day of May 23, 2019.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T12:15:53-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 389.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4075-4110" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T12:15:58-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1500 and H.R. 1994. The resolution provides for one hour of debate on H.R. 1500, under a structured rule, and provides for one hour of debate on H.R. 1994, under a closed rule. The resolution provides for proceedings during the period from May 24, 2019, through May 31, 2019, and provides for motions to suspend the rules on the legislative day of May 23, 2019.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T12:17:16-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 389 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T12:17:23-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Ami Bera to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T12:17:35-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1500.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T13:22:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 389, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Velazquez amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T13:30:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 389, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Steil amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T13:40:45-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Steil amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Steil demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T13:41:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 389, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Adams amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T13:52:34-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 389, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lawson (FL) amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T13:59:56-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 389, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pressley amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T14:11:01-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 389, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Burgess amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T14:18:21-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Burgess amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Waters demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T14:19:07-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 389, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Burgess amendment No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T14:26:44-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Burgess amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Burgess demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T14:28:39-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 389, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cohen amendment No. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T14:39:24-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 389, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bonamici amendment No. 9.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T14:47:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 389, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Case amendment No. 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T14:55:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 389, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Golden amendment No. 11.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T15:03:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 389, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Escobar amendment No. 12.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T15:08:16-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 389, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Neguse amendment No. 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T15:12:55-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 389, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Stevens amendment No. 14.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T15:18:52-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Stevens amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Stevens demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T15:20:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 389, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the DeSaulnier amendment No. 15.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T15:28:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 389, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tlaib amendment No. 16.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T15:38:43-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 389, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Green (TX) amendment No. 17.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T15:48:08-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Green (TX) amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McHenry demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T15:49:26-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on adoption of amendments, which had been debated earlier an on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T16:56:20-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1500.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T16:57:05-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T16:58:18-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Steil moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Financial Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4108" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T16:58:35-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Steil motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to prohibit the use of funds from the Civil Penalty Fund to be used for any purpose other than compensating actual victims of activities for which civil penalties have been imposed under Federal consumer financial laws.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T17:05:34-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T17:13:41-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 191 - 231 (Roll no. 227).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="228" datetime="2019-05-22T17:25:38-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 231 - 191 (Roll no. 228).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T17:25:40-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-23">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="4664"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="331"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="963"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="116" relation="procedurally-related" number="389"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Financial literacy"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h263"/>
    <amendment number="h262"/>
    <amendment number="h261"/>
    <amendment number="h260"/>
    <amendment number="h259"/>
    <amendment number="h258"/>
    <amendment number="h257"/>
    <amendment number="h256"/>
    <amendment number="h255"/>
    <amendment number="h254"/>
    <amendment number="h253"/>
    <amendment number="h252"/>
    <amendment number="h251"/>
    <amendment number="h250"/>
    <amendment number="h249"/>
    <amendment number="h248"/>
    <amendment number="h247"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2019-05-10T15:05:38Z" status="Reported to House, Part I">Consumers First Act 

This bill revises provisions related to the administration of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB), including establishing requirements for staffing levels, political appointees, and the publication of consumer complaints regarding consumer financial products or services.

The bill specifically states the duties of the Office of Fair Lending and Equal Opportunity (under current law, these are delegated by the CFPB Director). It also adds the duty to implement enforcement and supervisory authority regarding the fair lending laws.

Specified units, offices, and boards of the CFPB must perform their assigned duties and may not be renamed or reorganized.

The bill amends all statutory references to the "Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection" to refer instead to the "Consumer Financial Protection Bureau."

Membership and meeting requirements for the Consumer Advisory Board are also revised.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-57</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
