<bill session="116" type="h" number="3607" updated="2019-10-24T19:00:32Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to direct Federal research in fossil energy and to promote the development and demonstration of environmentally responsible coal and natural gas technologies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fossil Energy Research and Development Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fossil Energy Research and Development Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Fossil Energy Research and Development Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000131"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2019-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000468" joined="2019-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000126" joined="2019-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000588" joined="2019-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001180" joined="2019-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001183" joined="2019-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000484" joined="2019-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 7 - 5 .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-07-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 22 - 13.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy" code="HSSY20" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-07-02T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Fossil Energy Research and Development Act of 2019

This bill expands Department of Energy (DOE) research, development, and demonstration programs for fossil energy. Specifically, the bill authorizes DOE programs regarding

 carbon capture technologies for power plants, including technologies for coal and natural gas; carbon storage, including to develop and maintain mapping tools and resources that assess the capacity of geologic storage formations in the United States; carbon utilization, including to assess and monitor potential changes in life cycle carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gas emissions; advanced energy systems to reduce emissions from and improve the efficiency of fossil fuel power generation; developing and assessing methods to separate and recover rare earth elements from coal and byproduct streams; identifying the environmental, health, and safety impacts of methane hydrate development; carbon dioxide removal from the atmosphere; methane leak detection and mitigation; and identifying and evaluating novel uses for light hydrocarbons produced during oil and shale gas production.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
