<bill session="116" type="h" number="2007" updated="2019-07-30T13:28:20Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to establish a program for the automated disclosure of taxpayer information for third-party income verification, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to establish a program for the automated disclosure of taxpayer information for third-party income verification, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000574"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001156" joined="2019-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="3151"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="identical" number="1100"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="928"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1957"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-04-01T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill requires the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to implement a program to ensure that certain disclosures of tax returns or return information for third-party income verification are (1) fully automated and accomplished through the Internet, and (2) accomplished in as close to real-time as is practicable.

The requirement applies to IRS disclosures of returns or return information to a person verifying the income or creditworthiness of a taxpayer who is a borrower in the process of a loan application.

In implementing the program, the IRS must (1) ensure that the program complies with applicable security standards and guidelines; and (2) assess and collect a fee for the disclosures at rates that are sufficient to cover the costs related to implementing the program, including the costs of necessary infrastructure or technology.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
