<bill session="116" type="s" number="2335" updated="2019-10-30T04:28:24Z">
  <state datetime="2019-09-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to accelerate smart building development, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Smart Building Acceleration Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Smart Building Acceleration Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Smart Building Acceleration Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Smart Building Acceleration Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Smart Building Acceleration Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2019-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-09-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-10-24">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski without amendment. With written report No. 116-151.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-10-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="272">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 272.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2741"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2044"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-07-30T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Smart Building Acceleration Act of 2019

This bill assists the building sector in adopting smart building technology that increases energy efficiency. Smart buildings are buildings with energy systems that (1) are flexible and automated; (2) have extensive operational monitoring and communication connectivity, allowing remote monitoring and analysis of building functions; (3) take a systems-based approach in integrating the overall building operations for control of energy generation, consumption, and storage; (4) communicate with utilities and other third-party commercial entities, if appropriate; (5) protect the health and safety of occupants and workers; and (6) are cybersecure.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of Energy (DOE) to establish a Federal Smart Building Program. Under the program, DOE must implement smart building technology in certain federal buildings and demonstrate the costs and benefits of smart buildings.

DOE may expand awards made under the Federal Energy Management Program and the Better Building Challenge to recognize specific federal agency achievements in accelerating the adoption of smart building technologies.

In addition, DOE must conduct (1) a survey of privately owned smart buildings throughout the United States and evaluate their costs and benefits, and (2) research and development on barriers to the integration of advanced building technologies. As part of the Better Building Challenge, DOE must demonstrate policies and approaches that accelerate the transition to smart buildings.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 116-151</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
