<bill session="116" type="h" number="170" updated="2019-07-30T13:06:09Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Black Lung Benefits Act to provide equity for certain eligible survivors, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Black Lung Benefits Act to provide equity for certain eligible survivors, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000568"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill amends the Black Lung Benefits Act to preserve specified amendments made by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) in the event those amendments are repealed. The amendments expanded the application of certain eligibility requirements for black lung benefits to claims that were pending on or after the enactment of PPACA. Those requirements (1) established a rebuttable presumption for claims filed by a miner who worked at least 15 years in an underground coal mine that a disabling lung or respiratory condition was due to black lung disease; and (2) entitled the survivors of a miner who, before death, was determined to be eligible for benefits to those benefits without the survivors being required to revalidate the miner's claim. (Previously, survivors were required to prove that the miner's death was caused by black lung disease.)</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
