<bill session="116" type="h" number="2513" updated="2019-10-31T09:52:13Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-22T18:52:48-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-10-22T18:52:48-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that persons who form corporations or limited liability companies in the United States disclose the beneficial owners of those corporations or limited liability companies, in order to prevent wrongdoers from exploiting United States corporations and limited liability companies for criminal gain, to assist law enforcement in detecting, preventing, and punishing terrorism, money laundering, and other misconduct involving United States corporations and limited liability companies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Coordinating Oversight, Upgrading and Innovating Technology, and Examiner Reform Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Corporate Transparency Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Corporate Transparency Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Coordinating Oversight, Upgrading and Innovating Technology, and Examiner Reform Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">COUNTER Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Corporate Transparency Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Corporate Transparency Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Corporate Transparency Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Corporate Transparency Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Corporate Transparency Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001292" joined="2019-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2019-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2019-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000754" joined="2019-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2019-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2019-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2019-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001203" joined="2019-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001137" joined="2019-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2019-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-06-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 43 - 16.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-10-08">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 116-227.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-10-08" calendar="Union" number="180">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 180.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-10-21T18:40:33-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 646 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2513 with 1 hour of general debate. Motion to recommit with or without instructions allowed. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T13:52:29-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 646 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T13:54:44-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 646.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8316-8339" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T13:54:49-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2513 with 1 hour of general debate. Motion to recommit with or without instructions allowed. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T13:55:30-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 646 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T13:55:31-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Lauren Underwood to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T13:56:13-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2513.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T15:05:21-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 646, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Burgess amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T15:08:23-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Burgess amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Waters demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T15:09:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 646, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hill (AR) amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T15:17:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 646, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brown (MD) amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T15:23:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 646, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Carolyn B. Maloney (NY) amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T15:29:50-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Carolyn B. Maloney (NY) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McHenry demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T15:31:07-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 646, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Davidson (OH) amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T15:39:47-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Davidson (OH) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Waters demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T15:40:16-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Waters moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T15:40:25-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T15:40:32-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2513 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T17:43:08-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8365-8370" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T17:43:23-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T18:27:19-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2513.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T18:27:42-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T18:29:10-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Davidson (OH) moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Financial Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8368" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T18:29:23-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes on the Davidson (OH) motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to require a court-issued subpoena for specified requests in the underlying bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T18:38:43-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T18:46:12-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 197 - 224 (Roll no. 576).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="577" datetime="2019-10-22T18:52:48-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 249 - 173 (Roll no. 577).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22T18:52:49-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-23">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2613"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2514"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1039"/>
    <bill type="hr" session="116" relation="procedurally-related" number="646"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1978"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets and economic espionage"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h637"/>
    <amendment number="h636"/>
    <amendment number="h635"/>
    <amendment number="h634"/>
    <amendment number="h633"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2019-05-03T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Corporate Transparency Act of 2019 This bill requires certain new and existing small corporations and limited liability companies to disclose information about their beneficial owners. A beneficial owner is an individual who (1) exercises substantial control over a corporation or limited liability company, (2) owns 25% or more of the interest in a corporation or limited liability company, or (3) receives substantial economic benefits from the assets of a corporation or limited liability company. Specifically, if certain entities apply to form a corporation or limited liability company, they must file beneficial ownership information with the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network (FinCEN). Furthermore, certain existing corporations and limited liability companies must file this information with FinCEN two years after the implementation of final regulations required under this bill. The bill imposes a civil penalty and authorizes criminal penalties&#8212;a fine, a prison term for up to three years, or both&#8212;for providing false or fraudulent beneficial ownership information or for willfully failing to provide complete or updated beneficial ownership information. The Government Accountability Office must study and report on (1) the availability of beneficial ownership information for other legal entities (e.g., partnerships), and (2) the effectiveness of incorporation practices implemented under this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-227</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
