<bill session="116" type="h" number="322" updated="2019-07-30T13:08:02Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide the work opportunity tax credit with respect to the hiring of veterans in the field of renewable energy.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Incentives for our Nation's Veterans in Energy Sustainability Technologies</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Incentives for our Nation&#8217;s Veterans in Energy Sustainability Technologies</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">INVEST Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">INVEST Act</title>
    <title type="display">INVEST Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000551"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2019-01-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Incentives for our Nation's Veterans in Energy Sustainability Technologies or the INVEST Act

This bill allows the work opportunity tax credit to be used for the hiring of a specified veteran who works in a field of renewable energy. A "specified veteran" means any veteran who is certified as (1) having received a credential or certification from the Department of Defense of a military occupational specialty or skill in a field of renewable energy or with respect to advanced manufacturing, machinist or welding, or engineering; (2) having completed a vocational degree in a field of renewable energy; or (3) having completed a LEED (Leadership in Energy &amp; Environmental Design) certification with the United States Green Building Council.

The Department of the Treasury shall pay (1) each U.S. possession (i.e., American Samoa, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and the U.S. Virgin Islands) with a mirror code tax system amounts equal to the loss to such possession due to this bill; and (2) each U.S. possession without such a tax system an amount estimated to equal the loss to such possession that would have occurred due to this bill if such a tax system had been in effect.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
