<bill session="116" type="s" number="255" updated="2019-09-03T15:00:13Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to include individuals receiving Social Security Disability Insurance benefits under the work opportunity credit, increase the work opportunity credit for vocational rehabilitation referrals, qualified SSI recipients, and qualified SSDI recipients, expand the disabled access credit, and enhance the deduction for expenditures to remove architectural and transportation barriers in the handicapped and elderly.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disability Employment Incentive Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disability Employment Incentive Act</title>
    <title type="display">Disability Employment Incentive Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2019-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2019-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2019-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2019-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2019-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2019-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2019-01-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="identical" number="3992"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Migrant, seasonal, agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-29T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Disability Employment Incentive Act 

This bill expands tax credits and deductions that are available for employers who hire and retain employees with disabilities.

The bill expands the work opportunity tax credit to include the hiring of employees who receive Social Security Disability Insurance (SSDI) benefits. For employers who hire vocational rehabilitation referrals, Supplemental Security Income recipients, or SSDI recipients, the bill also (1) increases the amount of wages that may be taken into account for the credit, and (2) allows an additional credit for second-year wages.

With respect to the tax credit for expenditures by eligible small businesses to provide access to disabled individuals, the bill increases the limits that apply to (1) the amount of expenditures that are eligible for the credit, and (2) the gross receipts and full-time employees of eligible small businesses.

The bill also expands the tax deduction for expenditures to remove architectural and transportation barriers to the handicapped and elderly. The bill modifies the deduction to (1) increase limitation on the amount of the deduction, and (2) allow the deduction to be used for certain improvements in the accessibility of Internet or telecommunications services to handicapped and elderly individuals.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
