<bill session="116" type="s" number="676" updated="2019-09-03T14:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2019-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to exclude certain post-graduation scholarship grants from gross income in the same manner as qualified scholarships to promote economic growth.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Workforce Development Through Post-Graduation Scholarships Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Workforce Development Through Post-Graduation Scholarships Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Workforce Development Through Post-Graduation Scholarships Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2019-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="4038"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-03-06T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Workforce Development Through Post-Graduation Scholarships Act of 2019

This bill modifies the requirements for calculating taxable income to exclude post-graduation scholarship grants from gross income in the same manner as scholarships are currently excluded.

A "post-graduation scholarship grant" is a grant provided by a program that

 is established by certain tax-exempt organizations; requires the grantee to live and work in an applicable community that meets certain requirements regarding income, out-migration, and bachelor's degree attainment rates; and under which, in accordance with the conditions of a grant, the organization repays any portion of an education loan incurred by an individual to pay higher education expenses. In implementing this bill, the Department of the Treasury must prescribe specified regulations and meet reporting requirements. The Government Accountability Office must report on the post-graduation scholarship grants covered by this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
