<amendment session="116" chamber="h" number="123" updated="2019-07-10T07:16:09Z">
  <amends type="h" number="1585" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2019-04-03T17:36:53-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000187"/>
  <offered datetime="2019-04-03"/>
  <description>Amendment would create a new purpose area for section 303 grants, which allows funding to be used by higher education institutions to train employees on how to conduct victim-centered, trauma-informed interviews with the students who report being a victim of sexual assault, domestic violence, stalking, or harassment. The employee would be trained to communicate in a manner which does not blame or judge the survivor for the crimes he or she reports.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 7 printed in Part B of House Report 116-32 to create a new purpose area to the grants to combat violent crimes on campuses, which allows grant funds to be used for the training of campus personnel in how to use victim-centered, trauma-informed interview techniques, informed by evidence based research on the neurobiology of trauma, when asking questions of a student or employee who reports to be a victim of sexual harassment, sexual assault, domestic violence, dating violence or stalking.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2019-04-03T17:36:53-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="149">
      <text>On agreeing to the Waters amendment (A007) Agreed to by recorded vote: 258 - 173 (Roll no. 149).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-04-03T15:52:44-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A007) offered by Ms. Waters.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3033-3034, H3044-3045" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3033" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-03"/>
    <action datetime="2019-04-03T17:36:53-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-03T17:36:53-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-03T17:36:53-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Waters amendment (A007) Agreed to by recorded vote: 258 - 173 (Roll no. 149).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-03T15:52:44-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A007) offered by Ms. Waters.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-03">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
