<bill session="116" type="h" number="1582" updated="2019-07-30T13:23:38Z">
  <state datetime="2019-03-12T13:26:32-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-03-12T13:26:32-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 44, United States Code, to require preservation of certain electronic records by Federal agencies, to require a certification and reports relating to Presidential records, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Electronic Message Preservation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Electronic Message Preservation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Electronic Message Preservation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Electronic Message Preservation Act</title>
    <title type="display">Electronic Message Preservation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000984"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000479" joined="2019-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-12T13:18:31-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Norton moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-12T13:18:42-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2665-2667" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-12T13:18:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1582.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2019-03-12T13:26:32-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2666" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-03-12T13:26:33-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="National Archives and Records Administration"/>
    <term name="Presidential administrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-03-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Electronic Message Preservation Act

This bill requires the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) to regulate federal agency preservation of electronic messages that are federal records.

NARA's regulations must (1) require the electronic capture, management, and preservation of such records in accordance with the Federal Records Act; (2) require such records to be retrievable through electronic searches; (3) include timelines for federal agency implementation of the regulations that ensure compliance as expeditiously as practicable; (4) establish functional requirements for electronic records management systems and a process to ensure that such systems meet the functional requirements; and (5) include requirements for the capture, management, and preservation of other electronic records.

Agencies must publicly report on their compliance with the regulations.

NARA must (1) establish standards for the management of electronic presidential records during a President's term of office, (2) certify annually whether a President's electronic records management controls meet the requirements of the Presidential Records Act, and (3) report after the conclusion of a President's term of office regarding electronic records deposited into the presidential archival depository and whether electronic records management controls met specified requirements.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
