<bill session="116" type="s" number="2304" updated="2019-09-07T04:28:58Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to enhance efforts to address antibiotic resistance, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STAAR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STAAR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strategies To Address Antibiotic Resistance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strategies To Address Antibiotic Resistance Act</title>
    <title type="display">Strategies To Address Antibiotic Resistance Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-07-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Strategies To Address Antibiotic Resistance Act or the STAAR ActThis bill expands various initiatives to address antibiotic resistance.

The bill&#160;reestablishes the interagency Antimicrobial Resistance Task Force to coordinate and develop efforts addressing antibiotic resistance.

The Department of Health and Human Services must&#160;encourage health care facilities to implement antimicrobial stewardship programs to evaluate and improve the use of antimicrobial drugs.

The bill also requires the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to use the National Healthcare Safety Network to collect and report data about the usage of antibiotic drugs, changes in resistance to such drugs, and other trends impacting patient outcomes.

Additionally, the bill increases nationwide efforts to monitor, research, and prevent the spread of infection from resistant organisms by

 establishing the Antibiotic Resistance Surveillance and Laboratory Network in at least seven geographic regions, establishing the Clinical Trials Network on Antibacterial Resistance to conduct clinical research, and requiring the CDC to collaborate with state and local agencies to support health care facilities that focus on preventing the spread of antibiotic-resistant bacteria.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
