<bill session="116" type="h" number="556" updated="2019-09-23T14:15:21Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Social Security Act to establish a new employment, training, and supportive services program for the long-term unemployed and individuals with barriers to employment, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Economic Ladders to End Volatility and Advance Training and Employment Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Economic Ladders to End Volatility and Advance Training and Employment Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ELEVATE Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ELEVATE Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">ELEVATE Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000096"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2019-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001296" joined="2019-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2019-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001185" joined="2019-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001201" joined="2019-01-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="identical" number="136"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Social Security Administration"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-15T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Economic Ladders to End Volatility and Advance Training and Employment Act of 2019 or the ELEVATE Act of 2019

This bill establishes a federal program to help fund (1) state- and tribe-run job-assistance programs, and (2) assistance for self-employed individuals and workers who relocate for employment opportunities.

The Department of Health and Human Services shall provide funds for programs that assist eligible individuals, such as those who face barriers to employment. Such programs shall provide employment services, training, and related services.

The bill also establishes criteria for using such funds for various purposes, including subsidized jobs. The bill also establishes various reporting and application requirements for&#160;states seeking funds for such programs.

The bill establishes an assistance program for self-employed individuals who meet various requirements and whose most recent contracts ended through no fault of their&#160;own. Such&#160;individuals shall be entitled to a weekly benefit equal to half of the average weekly earnings from their&#160;last employment, not to exceed the maximum available for unemployment benefits. An individual may not concurrently receive unemployment compensation and self-employment assistance.

Dislocated workers and long-term unemployed individuals shall be entitled to assistance for moving to a new area to earn family-sustaining employment. Such assistance may cover up to 90% of reasonable expenses, subject to a cap of $2,000 for an individual.

The bill establishes the Office of Reemployment Assistance in the Social Security Administration to administer the self-employment and relocation assistance programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
