<bill session="116" type="h" number="1215" updated="2019-07-30T13:19:37Z">
  <state datetime="2019-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend titles II and XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish a Social Security Surplus Protection Account in the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund to hold the Social Security surplus and a Medicare Surplus Protection Account in the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund to hold the Medicare surplus, to provide for suspension of investment of amounts held in such Accounts until enactment of legislation providing for investment of the Trust Funds in investment vehicles other than obligations of the United States, and to establish a Social Security and Medicare Part A Investment Commission to make recommendations for alternative forms of investment of the Social Security and Medicare surpluses.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security and Medicare Lock-Box Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security and Medicare Lock-Box Act</title>
    <title type="display">Social Security and Medicare Lock-Box Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000798"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Social Security" code="HSWM01" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-02-13T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Social Security and Medicare Lock-Box Act

This bill establishes (1)&#160;in the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund, a Social Security Surplus Protection Account; and (2) in the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund, a Medicare Surplus Protection Account.

The Managing Trustee of&#160;each trust fund (in both cases, the Secretary of the Treasury) (1) must transfer the annual surplus of&#160;the trust fund to its respective&#160;account; and (2) may not invest the balance in the account until a law takes effect that authorizes, for amounts in the trust fund, an investment vehicle other than U.S. obligations.

The bill establishes in the executive branch a commission to study the most effective vehicles for investment of the trust funds, other than investments in the form of U.S. obligations.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
