<bill session="116" type="s" number="1079" updated="2019-11-01T19:30:28Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the withdrawal and protection of certain Federal land in the State of New Mexico.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Chaco Cultural Heritage Area Protection Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Chaco Cultural Heritage Area Protection Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Chaco Cultural Heritage Area Protection Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2019-04-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-14">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="identical" number="2181"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-04-09T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Chaco Cultural Heritage Area Protection Act of 2019

This bill withdraws any federal lands and interests that are within the boundaries of the Chaco Cultural Heritage Withdrawal Area and any land or interest located in such area which is acquired by the United States after enactment of this bill from

 entry, appropriation, and disposal under the public land laws; location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws. The Department of the Interior may convey the federal lands to, or exchange such lands with, an Indian tribe in accordance with an approved resource management plan.

Certain oil and gas leases for federal lands on which drilling options have not started before the end of the primary term of the applicable lease and that are not producing oil or gas in paying quantities

 must terminate by operation of law pursuant to the Mineral Leasing Act and federal regulations, and may not be extended by Interior. Any portion of federal land subject to such a lease that has been terminated, relinquished, or acquired by the United States shall also be withdrawn as described above.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
