<bill session="116" type="h" number="593" updated="2019-10-17T07:16:12Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to simplify income tax compliance for small businesses, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Owners' Tax Simplification Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Owners&#8217; Tax Simplification Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Small Business Owners' Tax Simplification Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000266"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2019-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000623" joined="2019-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000586" joined="2019-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2019-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001188" joined="2019-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2019-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000600" joined="2019-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000081" joined="2019-01-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-16T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Small Business Owners' Tax Simplification Act of 2019

 This bill modifies several tax-related requirements that affect small businesses and self-employed individuals.

The bill includes provisions that

 align the deadlines for quarterly estimated tax payments with the calendar year quarters; modify the dollar thresholds for various information reporting requirements; allow certain self-employed individuals to participate in cafeteria benefit plans; exclude from self-employment income net earnings that are less than the amount required under the Social Security Act for a quarter of coverage for the calendar year in which the tax year began; allow certain health insurance costs of self-employed individuals to be deducted for self-employment tax purposes; and specify that voluntary tax withholding agreements, training, or group discount programs have no effect on whether an individual is classified as an employee or an employer. The Department of the Treasury must (1) establish uniform standards and procedures for the acceptance of digital or electronic signatures, and (2) use prenotification testing to verify recipient information before transferring a tax refund or credit through an electronic funds transfer.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
