<bill session="116" type="hr" number="660" updated="2019-11-02T09:40:06Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-31T11:29:21-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-10-31T11:29:21-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-10-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Directing certain committees to continue their ongoing investigations as part of the existing House of Representatives inquiry into whether sufficient grounds exist for the House of Representatives to exercise its Constitutional power to impeach Donald John Trump, President of the United States of America, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Directing certain committees to continue their ongoing investigations as part of the existing House of Representatives inquiry into whether sufficient grounds exist for the House of Representatives to exercise its Constitutional power to impeach Donald John Trump, President of the United States of America, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000312"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000623" joined="2019-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2019-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001206" joined="2019-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000593" joined="2019-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2019-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001205" joined="2019-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001206" joined="2019-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000474" joined="2019-10-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-10-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-30">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Rules. H. Rept. 116-266.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-10-30" state="REPORTED" calendar="House" number="52">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 52.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-10-31T09:16:16-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8683-8698" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-31T09:24:05-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 660.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-31T11:21:20-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 231 - 196 (Roll no. 603).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8697" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="604" datetime="2019-10-31T11:29:21-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 232 - 196 (Roll no. 604).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8683" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-10-31T11:29:23-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-31T12:22:33-04:00">
      <text>UNANIMOUS CONSENT REQUEST - Ms. Scanlon asked unanimous consent that Mr. Cole of Oklahoma be permitted to insert the text of the amendment he would have offered had the House rejected the previous question on H. Res. 660, along with extraneous material, into the Record immediately prior to the vote on ordering the previous question on H. Res. 660. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Reporting, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-10-29T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This resolution directs the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence and the Committees on Financial Services, Foreign Affairs, the Judiciary, Oversight and Reform, and Ways and Means to continue their ongoing investigations as part of the existing House of Representatives inquiry into whether sufficient grounds exist for the House to impeach President Trump.

The resolution authorizes the (1) Permanent Select Committee to conduct investigative proceedings, and (2) chair of any committee having custody of materials relating to the inquiry to transfer the materials to the Committee on the Judiciary.

The House authorizes the Committee on the Judiciary to conduct proceedings relating to the impeachment inquiry. The committee shall report to the House such resolutions, articles of impeachment, or other recommendations as it deems proper.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-266</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
