<bill session="116" type="h" number="3931" updated="2019-09-30T14:30:27Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2020, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="display">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000486"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-24">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 116-180, by Ms. Roybal-Allard.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-07-24" state="REPORTED" calendar="Union" number="139">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 139.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2582"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-07-24T13:22:58Z" status="Reported to House">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2020

This bill provides FY2020 appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security.

The bill provides appropriations for Departmental Management, Operations, Intelligence, and Oversight, including

 the Office of the Secretary and Executive Management; the Management Directorate; Intelligence, Analysis, and Operations Coordination; and the Office of Inspector General. The bill provides appropriations for Security, Enforcement, and Investigations, including

 U.S. Customs and Border Protection, U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, the Transportation Security Administration, the U.S. Coast Guard, and the U.S. Secret Service. The bill provides appropriations for Protection, Preparedness, Response, and Recovery, including

 the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, and the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA). The bill provides appropriations for Research, Development, Training, and Services, including

 U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services, the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers, the Science and Technology Directorate, and the Countering Weapons of Mass Destruction Office. The bill also sets forth requirements and restrictions for using funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-180</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
