<bill session="116" type="h" number="3832" updated="2019-08-16T10:41:42Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to expand tax-free distributions from individual retirement accounts to include rollovers for charitable life-income plans for charitable purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Legacy IRA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Legacy IRA Act</title>
    <title type="display">Legacy IRA Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001292"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000376" joined="2019-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001185" joined="2019-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="identical" number="1257"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-07-18T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Legacy IRA Act 

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to expand the tax exclusion for distributions from individual retirement accounts (IRAs) for charitable purposes.

The bill increases from $100,000 to $400,000 the annual limit on the aggregate amount of distributions for charitable purposes that may be excluded from the gross income of a taxpayer.

The bill permits tax-free distributions from IRAs to a split-interest entity for four years after the enactment of this bill. A split-interest entity is exclusively funded by charitable distributions and includes: a charitable remainder annuity trust, a charitable remainder unitrust, or a charitable gift annuity. A charitable gift annuity must commence fixed payments of at least 5% no later than one year from the date of funding.

A distribution to a split-interest entity may only be treated as a qualified charitable distribution if: (1) no person holds an income interest in the entity other than the individual for whose benefit the account is maintained, the spouse of such individual, or both; and (2) the income interest in the entity is nonassignable.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
