<bill session="116" type="s" number="535" updated="2019-10-30T07:56:26Z">
  <state datetime="2019-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enable Federal employees and contractors to correct their credit reports to remove adverse items of information reported as a result of a shutdown, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Federal Workers' Credit Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Federal Workers' Credit Act</title>
    <title type="display">Protect Federal Workers' Credit Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000393" joined="2019-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2019-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-02-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-02-14T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protect Federal Workers' Credit Act 

This bill generally restricts the inclusion of certain negative credit information on credit reports upon notification that an individual was affected by a federal government shutdown. Specifically, the bill prohibits (1) an individual from reporting such negative credit information to a consumer reporting agency and (2) the inclusion of such negative credit information on a credit report. The Consumer Financial Protection Bureau must maintain a database of affected federal employees and contractors and make the database accessible to consumer reporting agencies. Subsequently, consumer reporting agencies must delete all negative credit information from the relevant time period regarding affected federal employees and contractors. Consumer reporting agencies must also make additional free credit reports available to an affected individual upon request.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
