<bill session="116" type="h" number="1815" updated="2019-10-25T04:42:53Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-17T15:05:48-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-10-17T15:05:48-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Securities and Exchange Commission, when developing rules and regulations about disclosures to retail investors, to conduct investor testing, including a survey and interviews of retail investors, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">SEC Disclosure Effectiveness Testing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">SEC Disclosure Effectiveness Testing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">SEC Disclosure Effectiveness Testing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">SEC Disclosure Effectiveness Testing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SEC Disclosure Effectiveness Testing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SEC Disclosure Effectiveness Testing Act</title>
    <title type="display">SEC Disclosure Effectiveness Testing Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001117"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-03-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 33 - 26.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 116-123.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-06-20" calendar="Union" number="91">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 91.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-10-15T18:42:26-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 629 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1815 and H.R. 3624 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17T12:17:50-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 629.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8209-8224" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8215-8216" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17T12:17:55-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1815 and H.R. 3624 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17T12:23:35-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 629 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17T12:23:35-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable James R. Langevin to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17T12:23:42-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1815.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17T13:06:19-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 629, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Huizenga amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17T13:17:10-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Huizenga amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Huizenga demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17T13:18:19-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 629, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gottheimer amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17T13:28:04-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gottheimer amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Gottheimer demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17T13:29:12-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 629, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Wagner amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17T13:40:36-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Wagner amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mrs. Wagner demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17T13:42:30-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 629, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Casten (IL) amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17T14:29:58-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1815.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17T14:30:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17T14:30:55-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="564" datetime="2019-10-17T15:05:48-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 229 - 186 (Roll no. 564).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17T15:05:50-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17T15:05:51-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 1815.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-21">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hr" session="116" relation="procedurally-related" number="629"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h630"/>
    <amendment number="h629"/>
    <amendment number="h628"/>
    <amendment number="h627"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2019-10-17T12:34:03Z" status="Passed House">SEC Disclosure Effectiveness Testing Act 

This bill requires the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to assess the usefulness of certain disclosure rules to&#160;retail investors. Specifically, the SEC must make these assessments&#160;regarding both current and new securities rules and regulations that require the disclosure of documents or information to retail investors.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-123</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
