<bill session="116" type="s" number="248" updated="2019-06-06T04:59:00Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that the Secretary of the Interior collaborates fully with State and local authorities and certain nonprofit entities in managing the Corolla Wild Horse population on Federal land.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to ensure that the Secretary of the Interior collaborates fully with State and local authorities and certain nonprofit entities in managing the Corolla Wild Horse population on Federal land.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000476"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2019-02-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Seashores and lakeshores"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-28T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill instructs the Department of the Interior to allow for the introduction of a small number of free-roaming wild horses from the Cape Lookout National Seashore in North Carolina as necessary to ensure the genetic diversity of the wild horse population in and around Currituck National Wildlife Refuge, consistent with&#160;the December 2014 Wild Horse Management Agreement.

Interior may enter into an agreement with the Corolla Wild Horse Fund to provide for the cost-effective management of the horses in and around the refuge while ensuring that its natural resources are not adversely impacted. Such agreement shall require the fund to pay the costs associated with:

 conducting a periodic census of, and inspecting the health of, the horses; maintaining records of the horses living in the wild and those living in confinement; conducting the removal and placement of horses and monitoring horses removed from the Currituck County Outer Banks; and administering a viable population-control plan for the horses.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
