<amendment session="116" chamber="h" number="617" updated="2019-10-03T07:16:20Z">
  <amends type="h" number="1146" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2019-09-12T11:21:21-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <offered datetime="2019-09-12"/>
  <description>On page 1, line 6, strike "Section" and insert the following:    (a) Section    On page 1, after line 7, insert the following:    (b) TRIBAL CONSULTATION REQUIREMENT.- The repeal made by subsection (a) shall not take effect until-    (1) the Secretary of the Interior completes a thorough consultation with the Inupiat people regarding the effect of this Act on the quality of life, human rights, and future of the Inupiat people; and    (2) by formal action Kaktovic Village approves of such repeal.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in Part D of House Report 116-200 to prohibit the repeal of the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge oil and gas program until the Alaska Natives who live and work closest to the proposed oil and gas development in the Coastal Plain of ANWR are thoroughly consulted regarding the effect of the bill on their quality of life and future.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2019-09-12T11:21:21-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="526">
      <text>On agreeing to the Young amendment (A001) Failed by recorded vote: 193 - 230 (Roll no. 526).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-09-12T10:26:30-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Young.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7681-7682, H7685-7686" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7681" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-12"/>
    <action datetime="2019-09-12T10:26:30-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Young.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-12T11:21:21-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Young amendment (A001) Failed by recorded vote: 193 - 230 (Roll no. 526).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-12T11:21:21-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-12T11:21:21-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-12">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
