<bill session="116" type="s" number="745" updated="2019-11-01T04:59:23Z">
  <state datetime="2019-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the position of Climate Security Envoy within the Department of State, who shall develop policies to address security concerns with climate change and serve as a liaison with other Federal agencies and international partners on climate security issues, to express concern with, and improved preparedness for, growing security issues in the Arctic, to establish the position of Special Representative for the Arctic, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Climate Security Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Climate Security Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Climate Security Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2019-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-03-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Climate Security Act of 2019

This bill establishes various positions and duties related to climate change in the foreign policy context.

The President shall appoint a Climate Security Envoy within the Department of State. The envoy shall develop, implement, and encourage other countries to support a climate security policy to (1) enhance resilience to the effects of climate change to reduce the risk of conflict and instability, (2) evaluate the risks to regions and countries that are vulnerable to climate change and are strategically significant to the United States, and (3) coordinate the integration of climate risk assessments into foreign-assistance decisions.

The President shall periodically evaluate global climate disruptions, including&#160;by analyzing&#160;(1) the intensity and frequency of natural disasters, (2) the scarcity of resources including fresh water, (3) food and energy insecurities, and (4) how such conditions contribute to conflict and instability.

The State Department shall designate a Special Representative for the Arctic, whose duties shall include (1) formulating U.S. policy related to resolving international disputes in the Arctic, and (2) acting as the U.S. representative in discussions with other countries on Arctic-related issues.

The bill establishes that whistleblower protections shall apply to individuals reporting on what they reasonably believe to be a deliberate manipulation, removal, or misjudgment of information critical to national security assessment and planning.

The President shall ensure that drafts and final reports related to federal climate security research are publicly available.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
