<bill session="116" type="s" number="51" updated="2019-07-01T15:58:50Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-01-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend the Federal recognition to the Little Shell Tribe of Chippewa Indians of Montana, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Little Shell Tribe of Chippewa Indians Restoration Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Little Shell Tribe of Chippewa Indians Restoration Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Little Shell Tribe of Chippewa Indians Restoration Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2019-01-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-01-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1790"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="297"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Little Shell Tribe of Chippewa Indians Restoration Act of 2019

 This bill extends federal recognition to the Little Shell Tribe of Chippewa Indians of Montana.

The bill makes the tribe and its members eligible for services and benefits provided to federally recognized tribes and their members, without regard to the existence of a reservation or the location of the residence of any member. The service area of the tribe is considered to be the area comprised of Blaine, Cascade, Glacier, and Hill Counties, Montana.

 The tribe must submit a membership roll to the Department of the Interior as a condition of receiving recognition, services, and benefits. The tribe must maintain the membership roll.

Interior must take into trust for the benefit of the tribe 200 acres of land within the tribe's service area to be used for a tribal land base.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
