<bill session="116" type="h" number="332" updated="2019-07-31T07:32:53Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To modify the expedited procedures in the House of Representatives under section 36 of the Arms Export Control Act with respect to consideration of joint resolutions prohibiting proposed sales of defense articles or services, prohibiting proposed licenses for exports of defense articles or services, and prohibiting approval of United States commercial technical assistance or manufacturing licensing agreements.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Arms Sale Oversight Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Arms Sale Oversight Act</title>
    <title type="display">Arms Sale Oversight Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000582"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2019-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2019-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000173" joined="2019-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Arms Sale Oversight Act

This bill revises House of Representatives procedures for considering joint resolutions related to weapons and defense services sales to foreign countries, export licenses for such weapons and services, and technical assistance or manufacturing agreements with foreign countries.

Currently, the President must provide certification supporting such an action, which can go forward unless Congress enacts a joint resolution opposing it. The bill provides for rules such as who may make a motion to discharge the resolution from committee and time limits on debate.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
