<bill session="116" type="h" number="1349" updated="2019-10-30T07:15:59Z">
  <state datetime="2019-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to simplify reporting requirements, promote tax compliance, and reduce tip reporting compliance burdens in the beauty service industry.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Tax Fairness and Compliance Simplification Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Tax Fairness and Compliance Simplification Act</title>
    <title type="display">Small Business Tax Fairness and Compliance Simplification Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000585"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001306" joined="2019-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001051" joined="2019-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2019-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2019-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2019-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000385" joined="2019-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2019-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2019-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000616" joined="2019-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-02-25T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Small Business Tax Fairness and Compliance Simplification Act 

This bill expands the tax credit for a portion of the employer-paid Social Security taxes for employee cash tips to include beauty service establishments. (Under current law, the credit is limited to tips received for providing, serving, or delivering food or beverages.)

The credit applies to tips received in connection with providing beauty services to a customer or client if tipping employees who provide the service is customary. "Beauty services" include barbering and hair care, nail care, esthetics, and body and spa treatments.

The bill also (1) establishes an employer tip reporting safe harbor for beauty service establishments, and (2) specifies reporting requirements for income received from renting space to individuals who provide beauty services.

The employer tip reporting safe harbor for beauty service establishments provides an exemption from certain Internal Revenue Service tip examinations for employers who meet certain requirements for educational programs, reporting procedures, compliance with tax law, and recordkeeping.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
