<bill session="116" type="hr" number="66" updated="2019-07-30T12:58:54Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the obligation of the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Education and the Civil Rights Division of the Department of Justice to enforce title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 and its implementing regulations, and expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the obligation of the Department of Housing and Urban Development to "build inclusive and sustainable communities free from discrimination", and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the obligation of the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Education and the Civil Rights Division of the Department of Justice to enforce title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 and its implementing regulations, and expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the obligation of the Department of Housing and Urban Development to "build inclusive and sustainable communities free from discrimination", and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000185"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2019-01-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties" code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing discrimination"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-22T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This resolution reaffirms the following on behalf of the House of Representatives:

 the original intent of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to broadly prohibit all forms of discrimination by providing public and private rights of action against disparate treatment and disparate impact; the commitment to ensuring that all educational systems of the United States prepare all students for successful careers, regardless of race, color, or national origin; and the commitment to ensuring all communities are inclusive, sustainable, and free from discrimination. This resolution also recognizes that the Department of Education, the Department of Justice, and other federal agencies have an obligation to enforce title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 and its implementing regulations, and expects the agencies to do so. It resolves that oversight hearings will be held to ensure the agencies are enforcing title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 and its implementing regulations, including enforcement with respect to unintentional discrimination.

Finally, the resolution states that the House will consider legislation that reaffirms the original intent of the Civil Rights Act of 1964.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
