<bill session="116" type="hr" number="389" updated="2019-10-08T16:15:23Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-21T15:15:25-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-05-21T15:15:25-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1500) to require the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau to meet its statutory purpose, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1994) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to encourage retirement savings, and for other purposes; providing for proceedings during the period from May 24, 2019, through May 31, 2019; and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1500) to require the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau to meet its statutory purpose, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1994) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to encourage retirement savings, and for other purposes; providing for proceedings during the period from May 24, 2019, through May 31, 2019; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000593"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-20">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 116-79, by Mr. Perlmutter.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-20T20:05:47-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for one hour of debate on H.R. 1500, under a structured rule, and provides for one hour of debate on H.R. 1994, under a closed rule. The resolution provides for proceedings during the period from May 24, 2019, through May 31, 2019, and provides for motions to suspend the rules on the legislative day of May 23, 2019.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-05-20" state="REPORTED" calendar="House" number="24">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 24.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-05-21T12:39:14-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4024-4030" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-21T12:44:58-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 389.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-21T13:31:48-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 389, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question, and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Woodall demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of ordering the previous question until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-21T14:28:52-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4030-4031" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-21T15:00:38-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 227 - 191 (Roll no. 220).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4030" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="221" datetime="2019-05-21T15:15:25-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 230 - 190 (Roll no. 221).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4024-4025" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-05-21T15:15:27-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="procedurally-related" number="1500"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="procedurally-related" number="1994"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-05-21T20:57:10Z" status="Passed House">This resolution sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 1500 ( Consumers First Act) and H.R. 1994 (Setting Every Community Up for Retirement Enhancement Act of 2019).

Certain proceedings may take place on any legislative day from May 24, 2019, through May 31, 2019.

It shall be in order at any time on the legislative day of May 23, 2019, for the Speaker of the House to suspend the rules, relating to a measure making supplemental appropriations for FY2019.

The resolution waives a specified requirement of Rule XIII (Calendar and Committee Reports) to allow consideration of any resolution reported from the Committee on Rules through such legislative day, on the same day it is presented to the House, relating to such measure.

The House Committee on Appropriations may, at any time before 5:00 p.m. on Sunday, June 2, 2019, file privileged reports to accompany measures making appropriations for FY2020.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-79</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
