<bill session="116" type="h" number="3725" updated="2019-09-18T07:19:14Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To designate the Civil War Defenses of Washington National Historical Park comprised of certain National Park System lands, and by affiliation and cooperative agreements other historically significant resources, located in the District of Columbia, Virginia, and Maryland, that were part of the Civil War defenses of Washington and related to the Shenandoah Valley Campaign of 1864, to study ways in which the Civil War history of both the North and South can be assembled, arrayed, and conveyed for the benefit of the public, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Civil War Defenses of Washington National Historical Park Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Civil War Defenses of Washington National Historical Park Act</title>
    <title type="display">Civil War Defenses of Washington National Historical Park Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000147"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2019-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E899-900"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-07-11T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Civil War Defenses of Washington National Historical Park Act

 This bill designates as the Civil War Defenses of Washington National Historical Park the defenses constructed at the beginning of the Civil War in 1861 as a ring of fortifications in the District of Columbia, Maryland, and northern Virginia to protect the nation's capital.

 The park shall include all areas associated with the Civil War defenses of Washington currently owned by the federal government and under the administration of the National Park Service, including Battleground National Cemetery.

 Certain eligible sites and certain additional sites associated with the Civil War defenses of Washington may become affiliated with the park pursuant to a cooperative agreement under this bill.

 The Department of the Interior shall study and consider creative and cost-effective ways to facilitate how the storied history of the Civil War for both the North and the South, including the history of the defenses of Washington and the Shenandoah Valley Campaign of 1864, can be assembled, arrayed, and conveyed for the benefit of the public.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
