<bill session="116" type="s" number="493" updated="2019-09-25T04:27:47Z">
  <state datetime="2019-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require Federal agencies not performing security functions to relocate throughout the United States by the beginning of fiscal year 2030.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Decentralize Regulatory Agencies, Include the Nation Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Decentralize Regulatory Agencies, Include the Nation Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DRAIN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DRAIN Act</title>
    <title type="display">DRAIN Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000064"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-02-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-02-14T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Decentralize Regulatory Agencies, Include the Nation Act of 2019 or the DRAIN Act

This bill requires the Office of Management and Budget and the General Services Administration to jointly develop and implement a plan for relocating nonsecurity agencies outside the National Capital region by the later of October 1, 2029, or the expiration date of the lease for the building in which the nonsecurity agency's headquarters is located.

The bill exempts security agencies and nonsecurity agencies specifically exempted by the President from the relocation requirement. A security agency is an agency that receives the majority of its funding from appropriations provided for the Department of Defense, the Department of Homeland Security, or for the Department of State, foreign operations, and related programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
