<bill session="116" type="h" number="315" updated="2019-07-30T13:07:58Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-01">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to authorize partnerships between States and nongovernmental entities for the purpose of reclaiming and restoring land and water resources adversely affected by coal mining activities before August 3, 1977, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Reclamation Partnerships Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Reclamation Partnerships Act</title>
    <title type="display">Community Reclamation Partnerships Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000585"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-28">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-01">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-01">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-05-01" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Community Reclamation Partnerships Act

This bill revises the Abandoned Mine Land Reclamation Program which restores land and water adversely impacted by surface coal mines that were abandoned before August 3, 1977.

A state with an approved reclamation program may enter into a memorandum of understanding with relevant federal or state agencies for remediating mine drainage on abandoned mine land and water impacted by abandoned mines.

In addition, the bill authorizes a partnership between a state and a community reclaimer for remediating abandoned mine land if

 the partnership's proposed project is consistent with an approved state memorandum of understanding and conducted on certain prioritized sites; the state assumes all responsibly on behalf of the community reclaimer and the owner of the proposed project site for costs or damages resulting from actions or inactions of the community reclaimer in carrying out the project, except for gross negligence or intentional misconduct by the community reclaimer; and the state has necessary legal authority to conduct the project and has financial resources to ensure the project's completion. A community reclaimer is a person who (1) voluntarily assists a state in a reclamation project, (2) did not participate in the creation of site conditions at the proposed site or activities that caused any land or waters to become eligible for reclamation or drainage abatement expenditures, (3) is not a past or current owner or operator of any site with ongoing reclamation obligations, and (4) is not subject to outstanding violations of surface coal mining permits.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
