<bill session="116" type="h" number="3630" updated="2019-09-13T07:16:19Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act to protect health care consumers from surprise billing practices, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Surprises Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Surprises Act</title>
    <title type="display">No Surprises Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2019-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000812" joined="2019-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000791" joined="2019-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-12">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Health Prior to Introduction and Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral, Hearings"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-07-09T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">No Surprises ActThis bill expands restrictions on charging health care plan holders out-of-network rates for certain services. First, the bill requires insurers offering plans that cover emergency services to bill plan holders no more than the median in-network rate for a particular emergency service, even if the service provider is out of network. The bill further prohibits insurers from billing plan holders more than the median in-network rate for nonemergency services provided by out-of-network providers at in-network facilities.Out-of-network providers may not bill plan holders for the difference between the in-network and out-of-network rates for emergency services. The bill further prohibits out-of-network providers from billing plan holders for the difference in rates for nonemergency services provided at an in-network facility unless the provider complies with specified notice and consent requirements. Even when complying with these requirements, an out-of-network provider may not charge plan holders for the difference in rates for such nonemergency services if the provider is based at the in-network facility and&#160;is the only provider available to deliver&#160;the particular treatment or service at the facility.The Department of Health and Human Services must provide grants to states to&#160;establish or maintain All Payer Claims Databases, which publish claims and payment information from insurers.The bill also requires insurers to publish provider directories and requires the Government Accountability Office and the Department of Labor&#160;to report on certain issues related to&#160;the commercial health care market.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
