<bill session="116" type="s" number="845" updated="2019-11-01T04:59:23Z">
  <state datetime="2019-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish as United States policy that, pending confirmation of the Russian Federation's continued compliance with the New START Treaty, the United States should extend the Treaty through 2026.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">New START Policy Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">New START Policy Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">New START Policy Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2019-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2019-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2394"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="2529"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-03-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">New START Policy Act of 2019

This bill requires reports related to Russia's nuclear arsenal and the effect that&#160;the Measures for the Further Reduction and Limitation of Strategic Offensive Arms (New START treaty) has had on that arsenal. (The treaty is set to expire in February 2021 but may be extended to February 2026.)

The Office of the Director of National Intelligence shall report to Congress on (1) Russia's current nuclear forces and predicted force levels in 2026, (2) the impact the New START treaty has had on Russia's nuclear forces and strategic delivery systems, (3) how the expiration of the treaty would affect strategic stability and security for the United States and its allies, and (4) how the expiration of the treaty would affect the ability of the U.S. intelligence community&#160;to accurately assess Russia's nuclear arsenal.

The Department of Defense (DOD) shall report to Congress on (1) the impact the expiration of the treaty will have on the U.S. nuclear arsenal and posture, (2) the options available to respond to changes to Russia's nuclear posture if the treaty's limitations are removed, (3) the changes to DOD's budget that will be necessary if the treaty is not extended, and (4) how the expiration of the treaty would affect strategic stability.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
