<bill session="116" type="h" number="2304" updated="2019-07-30T13:31:09Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish a program to populate downloadable tax forms with taxpayer return information.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Autofill Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Autofill Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Autofill Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000454"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-04-12T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Autofill Act of 2019

This bill requires the Department of the Treasury to establish a program to allow taxpayers to download income tax forms that are populated with tax return information (e.g., wages, withholding, and self-employment income) previously reported to Treasury for the taxable year.

By October 31, 2019, Treasury must: (1) establish standards for data download to tax preparation software, and (2) provide a demonstration server for downloading the partially populated printable document file.

By February 15, 2020, and annually thereafter, Treasury must a provide a secure function on its website that allows a taxpayer to download, as both a printable document file and in a form suitable for input to automatic tax preparation software, the 1040, 1040A, and 1040EZ forms that are populated with tax return information previously reported to Treasury.

The bill also establishes deadlines for reporting tax return information to Treasury and for making such information available for populating tax returns.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
