<bill session="116" type="h" number="1143" updated="2019-07-31T07:33:18Z">
  <state datetime="2019-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act to require a health insurance issuer offering short-term limited duration insurance to include a standardized disclosure and certain information with respect to coverage exclusions and premium variations in marketing, application, and enrollment materials distributed in connection with such insurance and prohibiting the sale of such insurance during certain periods.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Educating Consumers on the Risks of Short-Term Plans Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Educating Consumers on the Risks of Short-Term Plans Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Educating Consumers on the Risks of Short-Term Plans Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000215"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Health" code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-02-11T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Educating Consumers on the Risks of Short-Term Plans Act of 2019This bill requires health insurers offering short-term, limited-duration insurance coverage to prominently disclose all medical conditions for which an individual may be denied coverage, limited in coverage, or subject to a premium increase. (Short-term, limited-duration insurance coverage is designed to fill a temporary gap in insurance coverage.)Insurers must further disclose that this type of coverage is temporary, provides limited benefits, and is subject to termination. Insurers may not enroll an individual in a short-term, limited-duration insurance plan during any time in which that individual is eligible for open enrollment in coverage through the health insurance exchange.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
