<bill session="116" type="h" number="104" updated="2019-07-30T13:05:31Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To repeal certain amendments to the Clean Air Act relating to the expansion of the renewable fuel program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Leave Ethanol Volumes at Existing Levels Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Leave Ethanol Volumes at Existing Levels Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LEVEL Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LEVEL Act</title>
    <title type="display">LEVEL Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001248"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Climate Change.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Environment and Climate Change" code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Leave Ethanol Volumes at Existing Levels Act or the LEVEL Act 

This bill revises the renewable fuel program, including the renewable fuel standard (RFS). Under current law, the RFS specifies the minimum volume of renewable fuel, such as ethanol, that must be contained in gasoline sold in the United States, except in noncontiguous states or territories. The RFS annually increases until 2022 when a minimum of 36 billion gallons of renewable fuel must be blended into gasoline. This bill decreases the volume of renewable fuel that must be contained in gasoline to 7.5 billion gallons each year. The bill also revises the RFS to eliminate separate volume requirements for the following renewable fuel categories: advanced biofuels, cellulosic biofuel, and biomass-based diesel.

Petitions for waivers from requirements under the renewable fuel program may not be brought by a person who is subject to the requirements of the program, nor by the EPA on its own motion.

The EPA may not authorize the sale of gasoline that contains greater than 10% ethanol, unless the gasoline was registered under the program and lawfully sold in the United States before this bill's enactment.

The EPA must study the effects of gasoline that contains greater than 10% ethanol, including the effects on consumer products, such as nonroad vehicles.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
