<bill session="116" type="h" number="2202" updated="2019-10-30T17:30:30Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a coordinated Federal initiative to accelerate artificial intelligence research and development for the economic and national security of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GrAITR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GrAITR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Growing Artificial Intelligence Through Research Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Growing Artificial Intelligence Through Research Act</title>
    <title type="display">GrAITR Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2019-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000585" joined="2019-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2019-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1558"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-04-10T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Growing Artificial Intelligence Through Research Act or the GrAITR Act

This bill requires certain federal activities related to artificial intelligence, including implementation by the President of a National Artificial Intelligence Initiative.

The initiative must invest in artificial intelligence research and support the development of an artificial intelligence science and technology workforce pipeline, among other activities.

The Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP) shall establish or designate

 a National Artificial Intelligence Advisory Committee to advise the OSTP on matters related to the initiative; a National Artificial Intelligence Coordination Office to provide technical and administrative support to the advisory committee and serve as the point of contact on federal artificial intelligence activities; and an Interagency Committee on Artificial Intelligence to coordinate the artificial intelligence and technology research and education activities and programs of the federal agencies, among other activities. The National Institute of Standards and Technology shall, among other things

 carry out initiative activities, including by awarding contracts as necessary; support the development of measurements and standards necessary to advance commercial development of artificial intelligence applications; and establish collaborative ventures or consortia. The National Science Foundation shall

 implement a research and education program on artificial intelligence and engineering, and award grants to establish up to five Multidisciplinary Centers for Artificial Intelligence Research and Education to conduct activities in support of the initiative. The Department of Energy shall carry out an artificial intelligence research program.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
