<bill session="116" type="s" number="378" updated="2019-06-25T18:57:21Z">
  <state datetime="2019-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish an excise tax on certain prescription drugs which have been subject to a price spike, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Price Gouging Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Price Gouging Act</title>
    <title type="display">Stop Price Gouging Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2019-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2019-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2019-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2019-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2019-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1801"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="identical" number="1093"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-02-07T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop Price Gouging Act 

This bill imposes an excise tax on pharmaceutical companies that sell prescription drugs that are subject to price spikes that exceed the annual percentage increase in the Chained Consumer Price Index.

For each taxable prescription drug, the excise tax ranges from 50% to 100% of price spike revenue received by the company, depending on the size of the price spike and including an adjustment for revenue that is due solely to an increase in the cost of the inputs necessary to manufacture the drug.

Pharmaceutical companies must submit specified data regarding drug prices and revenue to the Inspector General (IG) of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), and the IG must submit an assessment of the data to the Internal Revenue Service.

HHS, upon the recommendation of the IG, may exempt certain drugs from the excise tax if (1) a for-cause price increase exemption should apply; or (2) the drug has an average manufacturer price of not greater than $10 for a 30-day supply and is marketed by at least 3 other holders of applications approved under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act.

The Government Accountability Office must examine (1) how drug manufacturers and health plans establish initial launch prices for newly approved drugs, and (2) alternative methods that have been proposed for setting the price of new drugs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
