<amendment session="116" chamber="s" number="65" updated="2019-09-04T15:24:37Z">
  <amends type="s" number="1" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2019-02-04">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000355"/>
  <offered datetime="2019-01-29"/>
  <description>To express the sense of the Senate that the United States faces continuing threats from terrorist groups operating in Syria and Afghanistan and that the precipitous withdrawal of United States forces from either country could put at risk hard-won gains and United States national security.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2019-02-04" how="roll" result="pass" roll="14">
      <text>Amendment SA 65, as amended, agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 70 - 26. Record Vote Number: 14.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-02-04">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S820-829" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-31">
      <text>Cloture on amendment SA 65 invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 68 - 23. Record Vote Number: 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-31">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S776" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-30">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S756" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-29">
      <text>Cloture motion on amendment SA 65 presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S736"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-29">
      <text>Amendment SA 65 proposed by Senator McConnell. (consideration: CR S732-733; text: CR S732-733) To express the sense of the Senate that the United States faces continuing threats from terrorist groups operating in Syria and Afghanistan and that the precipitous withdrawal of United States forces from either country could put at risk hard-won gains and United States national security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-29"/>
    <action datetime="2019-02-04">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 65, as amended, agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 70 - 26. Record Vote Number: 14.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-04">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 65, as amended, agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 70 - 26. Record Vote Number: 14.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-31">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Cloture on amendment SA 65 invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 68 - 23. Record Vote Number: 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-29">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 65 proposed by Senator McConnell.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-29">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
