<bill session="116" type="s" number="99" updated="2019-07-31T07:34:24Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for the negotiation of lower covered part D drug prices on behalf of Medicare beneficiaries and the establishment and application of a formulary by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under Medicare part D, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Drug Price Negotiation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Drug Price Negotiation Act</title>
    <title type="display">Medicare Drug Price Negotiation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2019-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2019-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2019-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001075" joined="2019-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2019-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2019-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2019-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2019-01-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="identical" number="448"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Medicare Drug Price Negotiation Act

This bill makes a series of changes relating to the prices of prescription drugs under the Medicare prescription drug benefit and Medicare Advantage (MA) prescription drug plans (PDPs).

Under current law, the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) may neither negotiate the prices of covered drugs nor establish a formulary. The bill repeals these restrictions and instead specifically requires the CMS to (1) negotiate the prices of covered drugs; and (2) either establish a formulary for covered drugs, or require changes to PDP formularies that take into account CMS negotiations.

 If the CMS is unable to negotiate an appropriate price for a drug in accordance with certain criteria, the price must be the lowest of three specified options (e.g., the average price in other countries). The CMS must identify drugs that are subject to negotiation, with priority given to certain categories of drugs based on usage and cost.

Additionally, drug manufacturers must issue rebates to the CMS for drugs dispensed to eligible low-income individuals. Subject to civil monetary penalties, a Medicare or MA PDP sponsor must report, both to drug manufacturers and to the CMS, specified information related to the determination and payment of such rebates.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
