<bill session="116" type="h" number="1470" updated="2019-10-15T14:38:23Z">
  <state datetime="2019-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to provide greater access to the supplemental nutrition assistance program by reducing duplicative and burdensome administrative requirements, authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to award grants to certain community-based nonprofit feeding and anti-hunger groups for the purpose of establishing and implementing a Beyond the Soup Kitchen Pilot Program for certain socially and economically disadvantaged populations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Anti-Hunger Empowerment Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Anti-Hunger Empowerment Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Beyond the Soup Kitchen Grants Program Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Beyond the Soup Kitchen Grants Program Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Anti-Hunger Empowerment Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000248"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2019-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000297" joined="2019-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2019-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2019-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2019-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2019-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000173" joined="2019-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2019-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2019-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000081" joined="2019-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2019-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-02-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition, Oversight, and Department Operations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Nutrition, Oversight, and Department Operations" code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Indiana"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Iowa"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-02-28T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Anti-hunger Empowerment Act of 2019

This bill reduces administrative requirements for the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP, formerly known as the food stamp program), authorizes funding to increase access to SNAP offices, and authorizes grants for community-based nonprofits to expand anti-hunger activities.

The bill repeals existing provisions regarding administrative costs and authorizes the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to pay 75% of the administrative costs for state agencies to carry out new activities to increase the operating hours of SNAP offices, reduce wait times, accept online applications, upgrade technology, and provide a checklist of required documents.

If a state agency believes that information provided by a SNAP applicant is incorrect or incomplete, the agency must notify the applicant in writing and include instructions for providing the required information. A state may not require an appplicant to appear in person unless the information is not provided in response to the request or cannot be verified. State agencies may not require fingerprints for any member of a household to participate in SNAP or receive benefits.

USDA must report annually to Congress on the comparative progress of states in improving access to SNAP.



The bill also establishes a Beyond the Soup Kitchen Pilot Program to provide grants to community-based nonprofit feeding and anti-hunger groups for programs and technical assistance to reduce hunger, increase the use of nutrition assistance and anti-poverty programs, bolster food security, assist individuals and families to develop assets, promote economic independence, improve nutrition, and reduce obesity.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
