<bill session="116" type="s" number="2010" updated="2019-10-09T21:26:18Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase research, education, and treatment for cerebral cavernous malformations.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CCM-CARE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CCM&#8211;CARE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cerebral Cavernous Malformations Clinical Awareness, Research, and Education Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cerebral Cavernous Malformations Clinical Awareness, Research, and Education Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">CCM-CARE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2019-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="identical" number="3573"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-06-27T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Cerebral Cavernous Malformations Clinical Awareness, Research, and Education Act of 2019 or the CCM-CARE ActThis bill requires the National Institutes of Health (NIH) and other agencies to expand and coordinate their efforts to research cerebral cavernous malformation. (Cerebral cavernous malformation is a condition in which blood vessels in the brain and spinal cord become enlarged, which can lead to seizures, paralysis, hearing or vision loss, and bleeding in the brain.)The NIH must (1) award grants for medical, clinical, and pharmacological research; (2) award grants to support a network of clinical research centers intended to develop a cure for the condition; and (3) convene a Cerebral Cavernous Malformations Research Consortium to develop programs for clinicians, scientists, and patients.The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention must award grants to research entities for collecting and reporting data about cerebral cavernous malformation.The Food and Drug Administration must accelerate the clinical trial process for cerebral cavernous malformation by supporting (1) appropriate laboratory indicators of the condition, (2) the qualification of clinical outcome measures related to quality of life, (3) investigational drug applications, and (4) expedited peer-review pathways.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
