<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <version>1.0.0</version>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <title>To provide for the rescheduling of marijuana into schedule III of the Controlled Substances Act.</title>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <title>Marijuana 1-to-3 Act of 2019</title>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <title>Marijuana 1-to-3 Act of 2019</title>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <title>Marijuana 1–to–3 Act of 2019</title>
        <titleType>(Extracted from GPO) Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <chamberName />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <recordedVotes />
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <laws />
    <createDate>2019-09-13T07:12:17Z</createDate>
    <notes />
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 165, Number 146 (Thursday, September 12, 2019)][House][Pages H7706-H7707]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href="http://www.gpo.gov">www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. STEUBE:H.R. 4323.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article 1, Section 8[[Page H7707]]The Congress shall have Power To lay and collect Taxes,Duties, Imposts and Excises, to pay the Debts and provide forthe common Defence and general Welfare of the United States;but all Duties, Imposts and Excises shall be uniformthroughout the United States;To borrow money on the credit of the United States;To regulate Commerce with foreign Nations, and among theseveral States, and with the Indian Tribes;To establish an uniform Rule of Naturalization, and uniformLaws on the subject of Bankruptcies throughout the UnitedStates;To coin Money, regulate the Value thereof, and of foreignCoin, and fix the Standard of Weights and Measures;To provide for the Punishment of counterfeiting theSecurities and current Coin of the United States;To establish Post Offices and Post Roads;To promote the Progress of Science and useful Arts, bysecuring for limited Times to Authors and Inventors theexclusive Right to their respective Writings and Discoveries;To constitute Tribunals inferior to the supreme Court;and Offenses against the Law of Nations;To declare War, grant Letters of Marque and Reprisal, andmake Rules concerning Captures on Land and Water;To raise and support Armies, but no Appropriation of Moneyto that Use shall be for a longer Term than two Years;To provide and maintain a Navy;To make Rules for the Government and Regulation of the landand naval Forces;To provide for calling forth the Militia to execute theLaws of the Union, suppress Insurrections and repelInvasions;To provide for organizing, arming, and disciplining, theMilitia, and for governing such Part of them as may beemployed in the Service of the United States, reserving tothe States respectively, the Appointment of the Officers, andthe Authority of training the Militia according to thediscipline prescribed by Congress;To exercise exclusive Legislation in all Cases whatsoever,over such District (not exceeding ten Miles square) as may,by Cession of particular States, and the acceptance ofCongress, become the Seat of the Government of the UnitedStates, and to exercise like Authority over all Placespurchased by the Consent of the Legislature of the State inwhich the Same shall be, for the Erection of Forts,Magazines, Arsenals, dock-Yards, and other needful Buildings;AndTo make all Laws which shall be necessary and proper forcarrying into Execution the foregoing Powers, and all otherPowers vested by this Constitution in the Government of theUnited States, or in any Department or Officer thereof.</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
    </policyArea>
    <updateDate>2019-10-30T16:41:34Z</updateDate>
    <committeeReports />
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2019-09-12T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-116hr4323ih/xml/BILLS-116hr4323ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <party>R</party>
        <bioguideId>S001214</bioguideId>
        <middleName>Gregory</middleName>
        <firstName>W.</firstName>
        <fullName>Rep. Steube, W. Gregory [R-FL-17]</fullName>
        <state>FL</state>
        <byRequestType />
        <district>17</district>
        <lastName>Steube</lastName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId />
          <bioguideId>S001214</bioguideId>
          <lisID>2389</lisID>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <firstName>Matt</firstName>
        <middleName />
        <lastName>Gaetz</lastName>
        <state>FL</state>
        <fullName>Rep. Gaetz, Matt [R-FL-1]</fullName>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <identifiers>
          <lisID>2314</lisID>
          <bioguideId>G000578</bioguideId>
          <gpoId />
        </identifiers>
        <district>1</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2019-09-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <bioguideId>G000578</bioguideId>
        <party>R</party>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <congress>116</congress>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of Justice</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Drug trafficking and controlled substances</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <latestAction>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <links />
      <actionDate>2019-10-02</actionDate>
    </latestAction>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <billNumber>4323</billNumber>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <relatedBills />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2019-09-12T04:02:40Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                  <date>2019-10-02T19:38:35Z</date>
                </item>
              </activities>
              <systemCode>hsju08</systemCode>
              <name>Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security Subcommittee</name>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
          <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
          <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2019-09-12T04:02:35Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <subcommittees />
          <systemCode>hsif00</systemCode>
          <name>Energy and Commerce Committee</name>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2019-09-23T13:59:06Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Marijuana 1-to-3 Act of 2019</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Drug Enforcement Administration to transfer marijuana from schedule I to schedule III of the Controlled Substances Act. (A schedule I controlled substance is a drug, substance, or chemical that has a high potential for abuse; that has no currently accepted medical use; and that is subject to regulatory controls and administrative, civil, and criminal penalties under the Controlled Substances Act. A schedule III controlled substance is a drug, substance, or chemical that has less potential for abuse than a schedule I or II substance; that has a currently accepted medical use; and that has low or moderate risk of dependence if abused.)</p>]]></text>
          <updateDate>2019-09-12T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <actionDate>2019-09-12</actionDate>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <placeholderTextForH>1</placeholderTextForH>
        <billReferrals>2</billReferrals>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>5</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2019-10-02</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <name>Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security Subcommittee</name>
          <systemCode>hsju08</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
          <code>1</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        <links />
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <committee>
          <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <actionDate>2019-09-12</actionDate>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
          <code>2</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        <links />
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <committee>
          <name>Energy and Commerce Committee</name>
          <systemCode>hsif00</systemCode>
        </committee>
        <actionDate>2019-09-12</actionDate>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <links />
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2019-09-12</actionDate>
      </item>
      <item>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
          <code>9</code>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <links />
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <committee />
        <actionDate>2019-09-12</actionDate>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <title>Marijuana 1-to-3 Act of 2019</title>
    <introducedDate>2019-09-12</introducedDate>
    <amendments />
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

