<bill session="116" type="h" number="3946" updated="2019-10-29T15:00:29Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide further means of accountability with respect to the United States debt and promote fiscal responsibility.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Debt Solution and Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Debt Solution and Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="display">Debt Solution and Accountability Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001158"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000375" joined="2019-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001183" joined="2019-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-07-24T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Debt Solution and Accountability Act

 This bill requires the Department of the Treasury to submit to Congress a debt report and a statement of intent within 60 days of an increase in the public debt limit.

The debt report must include

 the historic, current, and projected levels of debt; the drivers and composition of future debt; and how the United States will meet debt obligations. The statement of intent must include a detailed explanation of

 proposals of the President to reduce the debt; the impact the increased debt limit will have on future government spending, debt service, and the position of the U.S. dollar as the international reserve currency; and projections of the fiscal health and sustainability of major entitlement programs (including Social Security, Medicare, and Medicaid). Treasury must make the information required by this bill available to the public on its website.

Upon request, Treasury must submit to Congress specified financial and economic data relevant to determining the amount of the public debt.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
