<bill session="116" type="h" number="2718" updated="2019-07-30T13:35:08Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to include green infrastructure bonds in the definition of qualified private activity bonds.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">P3 Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">P3 Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Pollution through Partnerships Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Pollution through Partnerships Act</title>
    <title type="display">P3 Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000381"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001064" joined="2019-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-05-14T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Preventing Pollution through Partnerships Act or the P3 Act 

This bill allows state and local governments to issue green infrastructure bonds as tax-exempt private activity bonds. The bonds are not subject to the state volume caps that apply to certain tax-exempt private activity bonds.

A green infrastructure bond must be issued as part of an issuance that requires 95% or more of the net proceeds to be used to develop, carry out, or certify approved green infrastructure projects. The approved projects are to construct, rehabilitate, maintain, or repair green infrastructure that has been certified by the state in which the project is located as effectively addressing nonpoint source pollution.

 "Green infrastructure" is infrastructure that preserves, enhances, or mimics natural infiltration, evapotranspiration, or capture of storm water.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
