<bill session="116" type="hj" number="1" updated="2019-09-10T09:25:46Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-03T21:35:56-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-01-03T21:35:56-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making further continuing appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security for fiscal year 2019, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Making further continuing appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security for fiscal year 2019, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000480"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03T20:23:18-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 5.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H190-196" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03T20:24:48-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with thirty minutes of debate on H.J. Res. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03T20:53:11-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03T20:54:06-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Granger moved to recommit to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03T20:54:17-05:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Granger motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03T20:55:40-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03T21:26:11-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 197 - 233 (Roll No. 8).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="9" datetime="2019-01-03T21:35:56-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 239 - 192 (Roll no. 9).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H190" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03T21:35:58-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-01-08" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="6">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 6.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-02-11">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1152"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-11">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed to the consideration of measure presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1155"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-11">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure withdrawn in Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="hj" session="116" relation="unknown" number="31"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-03T19:19:09Z" status="Passed House">This joint resolution provides continuing FY2019 appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) through the earlier of February 8, 2019, or the enactment of the applicable appropriations legislation.

It is known as a continuing resolution (CR) and ends the partial DHS shutdown that began on December 22, 2018, because the existing CR expired and the FY2019 DHS appropriations bill has not been enacted.

The CR also

 compensates DHS employees furloughed as a result of any lapse in appropriations that began on or about December 22, 2018, and ended upon the enactment of this joint resolution; reimburses or compensates certain states, federal grantees, and furloughed state employees for the lapse in DHS appropriations; and ratifies and approves certain obligations incurred in anticipation of the appropriations made and the authority granted by this joint resolution. Additionally, the CR has the effect of extending through February 8, 2019, several immigration programs and authorities that were extended in prior CRs and expired on December 21, 2018.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
