<amendment session="116" chamber="h" number="248" updated="2019-05-29T07:16:08Z">
  <amends type="h" number="1500" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2019-05-22T16:21:29-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001213"/>
  <offered datetime="2019-05-22"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to strike the findings in the bill and insert language requiring the Comptroller General to conduct a study of the effectiveness and efficiency of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) in meeting its statutorily mandated obligations, the prevalence of discriminatory practices in lending, and the workplace rights of CFPB staff.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 2 printed in Part A of House Report 116-79 to strike the findings in the bill and insert language requiring the Comptroller General to conduct a study of the effectiveness and efficiency of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) in meeting its statutorily mandated obligations, the prevalence of discriminatory practices in lending, and the workplace rights of CFPB staff.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2019-05-22T16:21:29-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="222">
      <text>On agreeing to the Steil amendment (A002) Failed by recorded vote: 190 - 234 (Roll no. 222).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T13:29:27-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Steil.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4087-4088" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4087" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22"/>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T16:21:29-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T13:29:27-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Steil.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T16:21:29-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22T16:21:29-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Steil amendment (A002) Failed by recorded vote: 190 - 234 (Roll no. 222).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
