<bill session="116" type="h" number="86" updated="2019-07-30T13:05:22Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that the salaries of Members of a House of Congress will be held in escrow if that House has not agreed to a concurrent resolution on the budget for fiscal year 2020 by April 15, 2019, and to withhold the salary of the Director of OMB upon failure to submit the President's budget to Congress as required by section 1105 of title 31, United States Code.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Budget Process Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Budget Process Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="display">Budget Process Accountability Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001302"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on the Budget, and Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on the Budget, and Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on the Budget, and Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Budget Process Accountability Act

This bill withholds the salaries of Members of Congress and cancels the salaries of certain employees of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) when budget process requirements are not met.

The bill withholds the salaries of Members of a chamber of Congress that has not agreed to a budget resolution for FY2020 by April 15, 2019, the deadline for passage of the resolution under the Congressional Budget Act of 1974. Withheld salaries are paid when the chamber of Congress agrees to a budget resolution or on the last day of the 116th Congress, whichever is earlier.

The Inspector General of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM), by three days after the President's budget is due, shall (1) make an annual determination of whether the OMB and the President are in compliance with statutory requirements for the President's annual budget submission to Congress, and (2) provide a written notification of such determination to specified congressional committees. The Director, Deputy Director, and Deputy Director for Management of the OMB may not receive pay for any period of noncompliance.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
