<bill session="116" type="h" number="39" updated="2019-07-30T13:04:56Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the periodic review of the efficiency and public need for Federal agencies, to establish a commission for the purpose of reviewing the efficiency and public need of such agencies, and to provide for the abolishment of agencies for which a public need does not exist.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Sunset Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Sunset Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Sunset Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001067"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Reform" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Sunset Act of 2019

This bill abolishes a federal agency one year after it is reviewed by the Federal Agency Sunset Commission, established by the bill, unless the agency is reauthorized by Congress. Each agency, including each advisory committee, must be reviewed by the commission at least once every 12 years.

The commission must (1) review and evaluate the efficiency and public need for each agency using specified criteria, (2) recommend whether each agency should be abolished or reorganized, and (3) report to Congress on introduced legislation that would establish a new agency or a new program. The commission shall terminate at the end of 2037.

The Government Accountability Office and the Congressional Budget Office, in cooperation with the Congressional Research Service, shall prepare an inventory of federal programs to assist Congress and the commission in carrying out this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
