<bill session="116" type="h" number="3862" updated="2019-10-07T14:30:26Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to prohibit the use of consumer credit checks against prospective and current employees for the purposes of making adverse employment decisions.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Equal Employment for All Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Equal Employment for All Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Equal Employment for All Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2019-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2019-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2019-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2019-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2019-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2019-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-07-19T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Equal Employment for All Act of 2019

This bill prohibits a consumer reporting agency from furnishing an employer with a consumer credit report containing information on the consumer's creditworthiness, credit standing, or credit capacity if the employer intends to use that information for any decision made for employment purposes.

An employer may use such a report in either an employment decision or before taking an adverse employment action with the consumer's authorization under certain circumstances. Specifically, a report may be used if the consumer applies for or holds employment that requires eligibility for access to classified information or such use is otherwise required by law.

An employer who has sought such a report may neither deny employment to nor make any other employment decision about a consumer because the consumer has not authorized the employer's procurement of the report.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
