<bill session="116" type="h" number="282" updated="2019-07-30T13:07:37Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve public safety through sensible reforms to firearms regulations.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safer America for Everyone Right Now Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safer America for Everyone Right Now Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFER Now Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFER Now Act</title>
    <title type="display">SAFER Now Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001281"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2019-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2019-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2019-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2019-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2019-01-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1186"/>
    <bill type="s" session="116" relation="unknown" number="447"/>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="820"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-08T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Safer America for Everyone Right Now Act or the SAFER Now Act

This bill establishes new restrictions and requirements regarding the sale, transfer, and possession of firearms. Specifically, it does the following:

 prohibits a licensed gun dealer from transferring a firearm to an unlicensed person prior to the completion of a background check; generally prohibits the import, sale, manufacture, transfer, or possession of a semiautomatic assault weapon (SAW) or large capacity ammunition feeding device (LCAFD); requires a gun dealer to conduct a background check prior to the sale or transfer of a grandfathered SAW between private parties; requires law enforcement agencies to be notified when a prohibited person attempts to purchase a grandfathered SAW; allows Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program funds to be used to compensate individuals who surrender a SAW or LCAFD under a buy-back program; requires a person who operates a gun show to meet certain requirements (e.g., minimum age and registration); makes trafficking in firearms a stand-alone criminal offense; prohibits firearm sale or disposition to or receipt or possession by a person who has been convicted of a misdemeanor crime of stalking; and prohibits the import, sale, manufacture, transfer, or possession of a trigger crank, a bump-fire device, or any part, combination of parts, component, device, attachment, or accessory that is designed or functions to accelerate the rate of fire of a semiautomatic rifle but not convert the semiautomatic rifle into a machine gun.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
