<bill session="116" type="s" number="3" updated="2019-07-31T07:34:22Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to bring stability to the individual insurance market, make insurance coverage more affordable, lower prescription drug prices, and improve Medicaid.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keeping Health Insurance Affordable Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keeping Health Insurance Affordable Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Keeping Health Insurance Affordable Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="unknown" number="1419"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Keeping Health Insurance Affordable Act of 2019

This bill alters and establishes several programs relating to health insurance and prescription drugs.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a public health insurance option through health insurance exchanges. The bill sets forth corresponding implementing provisions, including criteria for payment rates and provider participation. (For example, initial payment rates for providers and services must be set at the same rates as under Medicare; HHS may subsequently alter payment rates in accordance with a specified administrative process.)

The bill also expands eligibility for (1) the health insurance premium tax credit, and (2) repayment limitations for excess advance payments of the premium tax credit.

Additionally, the bill requires drug manufacturers, as a condition of participation in the Medicare prescription drug benefit, to issue rebates to the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) for drugs dispensed to certain low-income enrollees.

The bill also requires the CMS to (1) negotiate with pharmaceutical companies regarding prices for drugs covered under the Medicare prescription drug benefit, and (2) serve as a prescription drug plan sponsor for a nationwide prescription drug plan under Medicare.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
