<bill session="116" type="s" number="108" updated="2019-02-02T05:35:19Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide deferred action for certain individuals brought to the United States and to establish a border security trust fund, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to provide deferred action for certain individuals brought to the United States and to establish a border security trust fund, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2019-01-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-01-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish a program for certain individuals without lawful immigration status to apply for deferred action status, and also appropriates $25 billion for border security.

Deferred action status refers to an unlawful alien whose deportation may be delayed because DHS, exercising its discretion, considers the case a low priority. Under the bill, an individual must meet certain criteria for eligibility, such as having been previously granted the status before this bill was enacted. The individual must also have been less than 31 years old on June 15, 2012, entered the United States before the age of 16, and not been convicted of a felony or significant misdemeanor, among other requirements.

The bill also establishes the Border Security Trust Fund with the appropriated $25 billion. The fund shall be available for the construction of not fewer than 700 miles of reinforced fencing, additional physical barriers, access and patrol roads, and other equipment and technology related to border security. DHS shall report to Congress annually on the status of the construction and the estimated number of unlawful border crossings.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
