<bill session="116" type="h" number="3158" updated="2019-07-30T13:38:25Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a pilot program to execute lease agreements using alternative procedures, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To establish a pilot program to execute lease agreements using alternative procedures, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001187"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000615" joined="2019-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-06-06T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill modifies requirements regarding leases for federal buildings. It directs the General Services Administration (GSA) to establish, and operate through 2024, a pilot program to execute lease agreements using alternative procedures to (1) reduce the costs to the government of leased space, including by improving office space utilization rates of federal tenants; and (2) significantly reduce or eliminate the backlog of expiring leases over the next five years.

The GSA shall furnish simplified procedures for the leasing of real property at rates that do not exceed $500,000.

The bill provides for (1) waiver of space-planning and housing-cost requirements concerning building projects subject to congressional approval, and (2) consolidation of projects into a single prospectus to achieve efficiencies and improve utilization rates.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
