<bill session="116" type="s" number="1995" updated="2019-11-01T16:45:30Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Food Safety Administration to protect the public health by preventing foodborne illness, ensuring the safety of food, improving research on contaminants leading to foodborne illness and the chronic health outcomes associated with foodborne illnesses, improving the surveillance of foodborne pathogens (including foodborne pathogens identified as antibiotic resistant), and improving security of food from intentional contamination, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Food Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Food Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">Safe Food Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2019-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2019-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2019-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4570-4579" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="identical" number="4755"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine and animal diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-06-26T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Safe Food Act of 2019

This bill establishes the Food Safety Administration (FSA) as an independent agency to administer and enforce food safety laws.

The functions of specified federal agencies that relate to the administration or enforcement of food safety laws are transferred to the FSA.

The FSA is directed to

 promulgate regulations to protect the food supply from contamination; implement federal food safety inspection, labeling, enforcement, and research efforts to protect the public health; develop consistent and science-based standards for safe food; prioritize federal food safety efforts and deployment of resources to achieve the greatest benefit in reducing foodborne illness; administer a national food safety program based on an analysis of the hazards associated with different foods and the processing of different foods; require that all food and feed facilities register before operation or importation of food, feed, or ingredients; establish an accreditation system for foreign governments seeking to certify food for importation to the United States; establish requirements for tracing food and animals from point of origin to retail sale; establish and administer a food safety technology program to foster innovations with the potential to improve food safety; maintain or access an active surveillance system of food and epidemiological evidence; establish a sampling system to monitor contaminants in food; rank categories of food based on their health hazard; establish a national public education campaign on food safety; and conduct research relating to food safety. This bill includes provisions regarding prohibited acts, recall authority, penalties for violations of food safety laws, whistle-blower protection, and civil actions.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
