<bill session="116" type="s" number="2195" updated="2019-09-20T04:31:00Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the National Fab Lab Network, a Federally chartered organization consisting of a national network of local digital fabrication facilities providing universal access to advanced manufacturing tools for workforce development, STEM education, developing inventions, creating businesses, producing personalized products, mitigating risks, and other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Fab Lab Network Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Fab Lab Network Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="display">National Fab Lab Network Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000128"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2019-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill type="h" session="116" relation="identical" number="3837"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Federally chartered organizations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-07-22T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Fab Lab Network Act of 2019

This bill establishes the National Fab Lab Network as a federally chartered corporation.

A fab lab is a digital fabrication facility with the capabilities necessary to create form and function from digital designs. The bill requires the National Fab Lab Network to (1) endeavor to establish at least one fab lab in each congressional district and additional labs according to local demand, (2) link fab labs into a national network and promote their further expansion across the country, (3) serve as a training and operating resource for fab labs and their leaders and mentors, (4) maintain a national registry of fab labs, and (5) provide standards and protocols for connecting fab labs.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
