<amendment session="116" chamber="h" number="278" updated="2019-11-01T04:57:47Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2740" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2019-06-12T19:00:03-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000185"/>
  <offered datetime="2019-06-12"/>
  <description>At the end of division A (before the short title), insert the following:    SEC. __. None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to finalize or implement the proposed rule entitled "Occupational Exposure to Beryllium and Beryllium Compounds in Construction and Shipyard Sectors" published by the Department of Labor in the Federal Register on June 27, 2017 (82 Fed Reg. 29182 et seq.).</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 12 printed in Part B of House Report 116-109 to prohibit the Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) from using funds appropriated in this Act to finalize or implement a proposed rule to weaken health protections in OSHA's existing beryllium standards that cover construction and maritime workers.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2019-06-12T19:00:03-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="258">
      <text>On agreeing to the Scott (VA) amendment (A012) Agreed to by recorded vote: 241 - 181 (Roll no. 258).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-06-12T17:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A012) offered by Mr. Scott (VA).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4540-4541, H4554-4555" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4540" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-12"/>
    <action datetime="2019-06-12T19:00:03-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-12T19:00:03-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-12T19:00:03-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Scott (VA) amendment (A012) Agreed to by recorded vote: 241 - 181 (Roll no. 258).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-12T17:02:00-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A012) offered by Mr. Scott (VA).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-12">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
