<bill session="116" type="s" number="1038" updated="2019-10-24T19:00:35Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen highway funding in the near term, to offer States additional financing tools, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Build USA Infrastructure Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Build USA Infrastructure Act</title>
    <title type="display">Build USA Infrastructure Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000463"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2019-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee subcommittee="" code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-04-04T04:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Build USA Infrastructure Act

This bill addresses highway infrastructure funding.

The bill requires, for the five-year period beginning on October 1, 2020, the deposit of the first $21.4 billion of revenues collected by the U.S. Customs and Border Protection into the Highway Trust Fund.

A state may enter into an agreement with the Federal Highway Administration (FHWA), for a period of three years or longer, under which it agrees to

 opt out of receiving at least 60% of funds out of the Highway Trust Fund that the state may receive during each year of the agreement for federal-aid highway activities under the national highway performance program and the surface transportation block grant program; accept from the FHWA funds equal to 90% of the amount the state opted out of; and use those funds to carry out core infrastructure projects in accordance with provisions that authorize the state to determine whether it is in compliance with certain federal project requirements, including the use of steel, iron, and manufactured products produced in the United States. The amount of the opt out does not include amounts required to be set aside, penalties, or amounts required to be suballocated to areas based on population.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
